[
	{
		"content": "Sent for information Priority to Athens, Bonn, Copenhagen, The Hague, Lisbon, London, Luxembourg, Oslo, Ottawa, Paris, Reykjavik, Rome, USNATO, Nicosia, and USUN.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				33,
				39,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1977-80v21d160"
	},
	{
		"content": "Sent for information Priority to Athens, Bonn, Copenhagen, The Hague, Lisbon, London, Luxembourg, Oslo, Ottawa, Paris, Reykjavik, Rome, USNATO, Nicosia, and USUN.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				130,
				134,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1977-80v21d160"
	},
	{
		"content": "It is unclear what is holding up this necessary evaluation, although bureaucratic confusion and the fact that President Yahya has been in Dacca may be part of the problem.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President Yahya",
				110,
				125,
				"PERSON"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q333981",
		"id": "frus1969-76ve07d98"
	},
	{
		"content": "<hr><ol class=\"footnote\"> <li id=\"frus1951v04p1d429u_n1\" value=\"1\">611.41/3-1451: Telegram </li> <li id=\"frus1951v04p1d429u_n2\" value=\"2\">Repeated to Paris, Frankfurt, Brussels, Rome, and The Hague.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				178,
				182,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1951v04p1d429"
	},
	{
		"content": "The only constructive thought in respect of the Argentine problem which I have recently encountered came from President Lleras<a href=\"#frus1946v11d167u_n2\"><sup>2</sup></a> (vide my telegram No. 84, of January 24, 1946, 2 pm<a href=\"#frus1946v11d167u_n3\"><sup>3</sup></a>) in which he expressed the hope that if it was true that the United States possessed documentary evidence establishing Argentine guilt in respect of the Axis, \"we can then do something\".",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President Lleras",
				110,
				126,
				"PERSON"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q540230",
		"id": "frus1946v11d167"
	},
	{
		"content": "p>Respectfully yours,</p> <p>John C. Wiley</p> <hr><ol class=\"footnote\"> <li id=\"frus1946v11d167u_n1\" value=\"1\">835.00/2-846 </li> <li id=\"frus1946v11d167u_n2\" value=\"2\">Alberto Lleras Camargo.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Lleras Camargo",
				178,
				192,
				"PERSON"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q12002",
		"id": "frus1946v11d167"
	},
	{
		"content": "He is in touch today with the five recently promoted sergeants opposed to a continuance of Grau San Martin, four of them in command of the key barracks in Habana and the fifth in command of the troops in Santiago.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				204,
				212,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q117040",
		"id": "frus1933v05d468"
	},
	{
		"content": "We replied that while possible reorientation general policy toward Yugoslavia under study, we do not yet feel Yugoslavia should be treated differently aviationwise from other satellites.</li> <li value=\"5.\"> Zehnder asked implementation should not be discussed on working level (i.e. with Federal air officers) until he had chance discuss matter with Federal Council and prepare ground which he expects will take about eight days.</li> </ol> <p>On whole, Zehnders reaction was sympathetic; our impression is we can expect his advocacy of effective Swiss cooperation on an informal basis and discreet form.</p> <p>Sent Department 200, repeated London 9, Paris 15, pouched Rome, Cairo, Moscow.</p> <p> Vincent </p>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				671,
				675,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1949v05d106"
	},
	{
		"content": "<hr><ol class=\"footnote\"> <li id=\"frus1949v05d106u_n1\" value=\"1\">711.4027/2-4249: Telegram </li> <li id=\"frus1949v05d106u_n2\" value=\"2\">Francis Deak, Economic Officer and Attache (for civil aviation affairs) at the Legation in Switzerland; also assigned to Athens, Belgrade, Bucharest, Helsinki, London, Paris, Praha, Rome, Sofia, Vienna, and Warsaw.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				257,
				263,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1949v05d106"
	},
	{
		"content": "<hr><ol class=\"footnote\"> <li id=\"frus1949v05d106u_n1\" value=\"1\">711.4027/2-4249: Telegram </li> <li id=\"frus1949v05d106u_n2\" value=\"2\">Francis Deak, Economic Officer and Attache (for civil aviation affairs) at the Legation in Switzerland; also assigned to Athens, Belgrade, Bucharest, Helsinki, London, Paris, Praha, Rome, Sofia, Vienna, and Warsaw.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				318,
				322,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1949v05d106"
	},
	{
		"content": "\"> Country of India's size and potential political and economic structure should be represented on at least one of main UN bodies.</li> <li value=\"3.\"> India has shown tendency this session GA to follow fairly independent and moderate course.</li> <li value=\"4.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				190,
				192,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1947v01d102"
	},
	{
		"content": "The most recent manifestation of this attitude occurred when an Embassy officer attempted on October 22 to discuss the Department's suggestions for GA tactics (reftel)<a href=\"#frus1964-68v29p1d95u_n3\"><sup>3</sup></a> with the Ministry of Foreign Affairs International Relations Bureau Director Pak Kun.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				148,
				150,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1964-68v29p1d95"
	},
	{
		"content": "Havana has been circumspect about trying to use Chile as a base for promoting revolutionary movements elsewhere in Latin America, partly so as not to add to Allende's problems and partly so as not to jeopardize the advantages offered by the Cuban presence in Santiago.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				259,
				267,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1969-76ve16d116"
	},
	{
		"content": "By \"R\" day an Allied Liquidating headquarters on similar lines to Liquidating Agency for SHAEF (CALA) will be established in Rome.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				125,
				129,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1947v03d557"
	},
	{
		"content": "li id=\"frus1947v03d557u_n5\" value=\"5\">In telegram FX 74612 (Naf 1272), January 28, from Caserta, not printed, General Morgan reported to the CCS that he was ordering the abolition of the Allied Commission, effective midnight, January 31; cf.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"CCS",
				141,
				144,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1113673",
		"id": "frus1947v03d557"
	},
	{
		"content": "You may pass following views Department regarding Albania to Foreign Office: (1) United States has no immediate \"plans\" for Albania beyond present policy (attitude non-recognition, condemning conduct regime, participating concerted measures against Albania such as GA arms embargo, and obtaining maximum intelligence).",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				265,
				267,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1950v04d180"
	},
	{
		"content": "/li> <li id=\"frus1950v04d180u_n2\" value=\"2\">Copies of this airgram were sent for information only to Belgrade, London, Paris, and Rome.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				130,
				134,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1950v04d180"
	},
	{
		"content": "/li> <li id=\"frus1961-63v03d15u_n3\" value=\"3\">Harriman reported these assurances in telegram 882 from Rome, September 13, 1961.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				102,
				106,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1961-63v03d15"
	},
	{
		"content": "Deptel 137 January 25 to Rome.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				25,
				29,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1945v04d1146"
	},
	{
		"content": "(Reference Mat 353 from SACMED to CCAC, Deptel 396, November 17 to Rome<a href=\"#frus1945v04d1146u_n3\"><sup>3</sup></a> and Rome 759 November 19 to Department.<a href=\"#frus1945v04d1146u_n4\"><sup>4</sup></a>)</li> <li value=\"3.\">",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				67,
				71,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1945v04d1146"
	},
	{
		"content": "In the meantime, the British have asked that we not give the Quintieri-Mattioli mission the statement referred to in Department's 66 to Rome January 13 in view of the fact that the financial question is under discussion on a combined basis.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				136,
				140,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1945v04d1146"
	},
	{
		"content": "A meeting of the Cabinet has been called for this afternoon to consider what effect the notification of the denunciation of the Locarno Treaty might bring about.</p> <p>When Marriner left Massigli was about to go into consultation with one of the high officers of the General Staff, perhaps on the basis of an unconfirmed press report now circulating that a small detachment of the German army has just entered Cologne.</p> <p>Ciphers to London, Rome, Berlin, Geneva.</p> <p> Straus </p>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				446,
				450,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1936v01d177"
	},
	{
		"content": "value=\"2\">For this report, see GA (II) vol.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				31,
				33,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1947v01d136"
	},
	{
		"content": "/li> <li id=\"frus1947v01d136u_n4\" value=\"4\">On November 13, after having debated through one meeting and part of a second (GA (II), Plenary, vol.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				123,
				125,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1947v01d136"
	},
	{
		"content": "For text of the resolution, Resolution 111(II), see United Nations, Official Records of the General Assembly, Second Session, Resolutions, pp. 15 and 16 (hereafter cited as GA (II), Resolutions).",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				173,
				175,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1947v01d136"
	},
	{
		"content": "/li> <li id=\"frus1952-54v09p2d1310u_n2\" value=\"2\">Repeated to London as telegram 396, to Amman as telegram 77, to Baghdad as telegram 51, to Beirut as telegram 88, to Damascus as telegram 41, to Jidda as telegram 33, and unnumbered to Paris, Bonn, Rome, and Valletta.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				248,
				252,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1952-54v09p2d1310"
	},
	{
		"content": "Following completion of the December draft, Ambassador Korry returned to Santiago, but he and Ambassador Troxel returned to Washington in mid-January and, following a meeting with Rogers, continued drafting their report under Nathaniel Samuels' direction.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				73,
				81,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1969-76v04d123"
	},
	{
		"content": "(Telegram 885 from Santiago; National Archives, RG 59, Central Files 1970-73, AID (US) 1)</p> </div>']",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				19,
				27,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1969-76v04d123"
	},
	{
		"content": "Repeated to Paris, London, Athens, and Ankara.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				27,
				33,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1955-57v26d247"
	},
	{
		"content": "They understood from Norwegian UN delegation that proposal now was for delegations of 6 powers jointly to address letter to Assembly President tomorrow December 4 requesting item be placed on GA agenda as urgent priority matter.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				192,
				194,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1950v07d956"
	},
	{
		"content": "Once this process were set in motion by putting the question on the GA agenda, the other steps would inexorably follow without possibility of stopping them.</p> <p>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				68,
				70,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1950v07d956"
	},
	{
		"content": "Thirdly Norwegian Government would hope that Attlee and President Truman would weigh consequences of proposed GA procedure during interval.</p> <p>Lange said he believed we would find other western European countries thinking along these same lines.</p> <p>Issue being placed before full cabinet tomorrow morning and then before Storting Foreign Affairs Committee composed all parties.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				110,
				112,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1950v07d956"
	},
	{
		"content": "Instructions to Norwegian UN delegation are to set forth above position and if other 5 delegations should insist on getting item on GA agenda without further delay, delegation is to seek further instructions.</p> <p>Please instruct niact if Department wishes I press US view.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				132,
				134,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1950v07d956"
	},
	{
		"content": "Norwegian view that once matter gets on GA agenda it will head straight toward declared war or equivalent in short time seems to afford room for argument.<a href=\"#frus1950v07d956u_n2\"><sup>2</sup></a> </p> <p> Snow </p>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				40,
				42,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1950v07d956"
	},
	{
		"content": "Subj: President Yahya on U.S.-China Relations.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President Yahya",
				6,
				21,
				"PERSON"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q333981",
		"id": "frus1969-76v17d98"
	},
	{
		"content": "During a wide-ranging conversation with President Yahya on December 12, he made the following observations with reference to his recent trip to Peking:<a href=\"#frus1969-76v17d98u_n3\"><sup>3</sup></a> </p>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President Yahya",
				40,
				55,
				"PERSON"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q333981",
		"id": "frus1969-76v17d98"
	},
	{
		"content": "He said that Chou En-lai listened with unusual attention and interest and upon conclusion of this conversation observed that the comments made by President Yahya were extremely interesting and deserved full consideration.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President Yahya",
				146,
				161,
				"PERSON"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q333981",
		"id": "frus1969-76v17d98"
	},
	{
		"content": "<p>Sent Department Depto 39; repeated info Paris 194 pass OSR, The Hague 35, Brussels 35, Copenhagen 27, Oslo 21, Ottawa 12, Lisbon 17, Rome 49, Frankfort unnumbered, pass Heidelberg 11 for Handy.</p> <p>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				136,
				140,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1950v03d121"
	},
	{
		"content": "<p>\"Having decided on 15 July, 1948 that subject to further decision by the SC or the GA, the truce in Palestine shall remain in force in accordance with the resolution of that date and with that of 29 May, 1948, until a peaceful adjustment of the future situation of Palestine is reached;</p>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				86,
				88,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1948v05p2d738"
	},
	{
		"content": "The Ambassador assured Lavrishchev that he would, in conformity with the latter's request, inform the Foreign Office of the name of the liaison officer.</p> <p>To Department as 1459; repeated to Athens as 19; repeated to Sofia as 33.</p> <p> Kennan </p>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				195,
				201,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1945v04d189"
	},
	{
		"content": "A copy was sent to Meyer, Feldman, Winder (E/IFD/ODF), Hunt (OPIC), Van Batenburg (Treasury), and Santiago.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				98,
				106,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1969-76ve16d119"
	},
	{
		"content": "I will send over in a day or two so that you will get it in plenty of time before going to Rome.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				91,
				95,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1933v01d176"
	},
	{
		"content": "He continued that, if the U.S. had been presented with a choice on March 25, it would certainly have urged President Yahya not to take a military course of action.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President Yahya",
				107,
				122,
				"PERSON"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q333981",
		"id": "frus1969-76v11d24"
	},
	{
		"content": "But he recalled that everyone had been taken by surprise when the negotiations broke down and Yahya turned to military action.</p> <p>Mr. Sisco noted that the U.S. and President Yahya both have a large stake in the preservation of moderate leadership in East Pakistan.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President Yahya",
				168,
				183,
				"PERSON"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q333981",
		"id": "frus1969-76v11d24"
	},
	{
		"content": "In response to a question from Dr. Kissinger, Mr. Sisco felt that CIA much earlier than State had indicated the likelihood of President Yahya's taking recourse to military action.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President Yahya",
				126,
				141,
				"PERSON"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q333981",
		"id": "frus1969-76v11d24"
	},
	{
		"content": "He concluded by noting that President Yahya is trying to crank up a \"quizzling leadership,\" and Mr. Sisco described Ambassador Hilaly's present line about how Yahya is planning to concede the \"six points\" to East Pakistani leadership.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President Yahya",
				28,
				43,
				"PERSON"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q333981",
		"id": "frus1969-76v11d24"
	},
	{
		"content": "After further discussion we agreed that in these circumstances the best thing to do would be to have no resolution, announce that we had agreed to resume negotiations by the end of July and meanwhile would have some bilateral talks in June and July on disarmament, including the composition of the forum, and recommend that all pending resolutions be deferred until the next GA.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				375,
				377,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1961-63v07d10"
	},
	{
		"content": "Following is rationale underlying our essentially negative response Madame Pandit's request for resumed GA session, for use with delegations and foreign offices.</p> <ol> <li value=\"1.\">",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				104,
				106,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1952-54v15p2d856"
	},
	{
		"content": "We see no point in resumed GA at present because we believe it will not serve useful purpose in connection Korean problem.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				27,
				29,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1952-54v15p2d856"
	},
	{
		"content": "If Indians had complied with armistice agreement and had released POWs to civilian status January 23 as required therein it might have been desirable for GA subsequently express moral approval of Indian course and we would have viewed sympathetically Indian request for such action.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				154,
				156,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1952-54v15p2d856"
	},
	{
		"content": "GA consideration of POW problem could only result in presentation three conflicting points of view,--i.e., Communist, Indian and UNC views re what would have been proper disposition POWs--with fruitless recriminations and controversial resolution of dubious practical utility.</li> <li value=\"3.\"> GOI also seeks have GA deal with question of Korean political conference or other steps looking toward settlement Korean question.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				0,
				2,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1952-54v15p2d856"
	},
	{
		"content": "GA consideration of POW problem could only result in presentation three conflicting points of view,--i.e., Communist, Indian and UNC views re what would have been proper disposition POWs--with fruitless recriminations and controversial resolution of dubious practical utility.</li> <li value=\"3.\"> GOI also seeks have GA deal with question of Korean political conference or other steps looking toward settlement Korean question.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				318,
				320,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1952-54v15p2d856"
	},
	{
		"content": "Again, we fail see utility GA action.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				27,
				29,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1952-54v15p2d856"
	},
	{
		"content": "By resolution August 28, 1953<a href=\"#frus1952-54v15p2d856u_n3\"><sup>3</sup></a> GA has already set forth its views on organization of political conference.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				82,
				84,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1952-54v15p2d856"
	},
	{
		"content": "We believe we can do this more effectively than GA, unless or until some radically new basis of procedure becomes desirable.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				48,
				50,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1952-54v15p2d856"
	},
	{
		"content": "Meanwhile, if Communists should come to believe a resumed GA session is imminent, they will obviously refrain from any serious negotition.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				58,
				60,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1952-54v15p2d856"
	},
	{
		"content": "GA consideration this question could also revive in very difficult form demands for GA hearings for Chinese Communists and North Koreans.</li> <li value=\"4.\">",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				0,
				2,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1952-54v15p2d856"
	},
	{
		"content": "GA consideration this question could also revive in very difficult form demands for GA hearings for Chinese Communists and North Koreans.</li> <li value=\"4.\">",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				84,
				86,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1952-54v15p2d856"
	},
	{
		"content": "Therefore, since on our analysis GA to consider POW issue and Korean political conference would at present produce no useful result but would actually increase tension and difficulties of negotiation, we are not now prepared to agree that session should be resumed or to set date for resumption.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				33,
				35,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1952-54v15p2d856"
	},
	{
		"content": "We believe we should all keep open mind on this question and avoid commitment until clear prospect of concrete improvement in Korean situation through GA action seems likely.</li> </ol> <p>USUN should make our position clear to other delegations and New Delhi should make foregoing points at high level, reporting responses.<a href=\"#frus1952-54v15p2d856u_n4\"><sup>4</sup></a> London should similarly approach FonOff if in its view UK position at variance with above.</p> <p",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				151,
				153,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1952-54v15p2d856"
	},
	{
		"content": "GA has no legal authority in this matter and we fail to see how GA action could be as effective as action prescribed in armistice agreement.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				64,
				66,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1952-54v15p2d856"
	},
	{
		"content": "Indian sources are also reported as implying GA might have to take action if Communists refuse to take back POWs desiring to go to Communist China and North Korea.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				45,
				47,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1952-54v15p2d856"
	},
	{
		"content": "Here again, GA has no legal authority deal with situation and we fail see how GA action at this time could be as useful as diplomatic methods to determine fate these prisoners if indeed Communists should refuse accept them.</p> <p>Dulles</p> <hr><ol class=\"footnote\"> <li id=\"frus1952-54v15p2d856u_n1\" value=\"1\">320/1-2054: Telegram <",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				12,
				14,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1952-54v15p2d856"
	},
	{
		"content": "Here again, GA has no legal authority deal with situation and we fail see how GA action at this time could be as useful as diplomatic methods to determine fate these prisoners if indeed Communists should refuse accept them.</p> <p>Dulles</p> <hr><ol class=\"footnote\"> <li id=\"frus1952-54v15p2d856u_n1\" value=\"1\">320/1-2054: Telegram <",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				78,
				80,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1952-54v15p2d856"
	},
	{
		"content": "<li id=\"frus1950v03d388u_n2\" value=\"2\">Sent to London, Frankfort, The Hague, Rome, Oslo, Copenhagen, Paris, Brussels, Luxembourg, Bern, Stockholm, and Moscow.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				77,
				81,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1950v03d388"
	},
	{
		"content": "Repeated to Caracas.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Caracas",
				12,
				19,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1533",
		"id": "frus1969-76v05d57"
	},
	{
		"content": "/li> <li id=\"frus1969-76v05d57u_n2\" value=\"2\">In telegram 720, February 12, the Embassy in Caracas reported that the Venezuelan Government sought U.S. support for Nava Carillo's candidacy for chairman of the Committee.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Caracas",
				91,
				98,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1533",
		"id": "frus1969-76v05d57"
	},
	{
		"content": "The suspicions, particularly in Ankara, that Greeks will in the last analysis get together against Turks, whatever the temporary realism and reasonableness in Athens, is omnipresent.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				159,
				165,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1969-76v29d390"
	},
	{
		"content": "Repeated priority to Athens, Ankara, London, Prague, USUN, USNATO, USDOCOSOUTH, and EUCOM.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				21,
				27,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1969-76v29d390"
	},
	{
		"content": "Secretary McNamara in Athens<a href=\"#frus1961-63v13d394u_n4\"><sup>4</sup></a> made clear our view that relatively weak nuclear forces with enemy cities as targets are not likely to be adequate to perform the function of deterrence.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				22,
				28,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1961-63v13d394"
	},
	{
		"content": "In short, then, weak nuclear capabilities, operating independently, are expensive, prone to obsolescence, and lacking in credibility as a deterrent.\"</p> <p>These remarks, which were generally interpreted at Athens as applying to the French, apply with equal force to the British.</p> <p",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				208,
				214,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1961-63v13d394"
	},
	{
		"content": "li id=\"frus1961-63v13d394u_n4\" value=\"4\">Reference is to the Athens meeting of the North Atlantic Council, May 4-6, 1962; see Documents 136 and 137.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				61,
				67,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1961-63v13d394"
	},
	{
		"content": "value=\"2\">The first two paragraphs of this memorandum relate to the 25th Meeting of the First Committee, November 21; for the record of that meeting, see GA (I/2), First Committee, pp.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				154,
				156,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1946v01d532"
	},
	{
		"content": "/li> <li id=\"frus1945v02d479u_n2\" value=\"2\">Repeated to Brussels, Helsinki, The Hague, Paris, Rome, Athens, Belgrade, Vienna, Budapest, Bucharest, Praha, Warsaw, and Berlin.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				94,
				98,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1945v02d479"
	},
	{
		"content": "/li> <li id=\"frus1945v02d479u_n2\" value=\"2\">Repeated to Brussels, Helsinki, The Hague, Paris, Rome, Athens, Belgrade, Vienna, Budapest, Bucharest, Praha, Warsaw, and Berlin.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				100,
				106,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1945v02d479"
	},
	{
		"content": "Delbos said that 5 days ago Ciano<a href=\"#frus1937v01d44u_n5\"><sup>5</sup></a> had sent for the French Charge d'Affaires at Rome and had denied to him the reports published in the press of the landing of Italian troops in Spain since February 20.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				125,
				129,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1937v01d44"
	},
	{
		"content": "German reports on the occupation of Athens assert that except for desultory fighting in the vicinity the Greek capital was occupied without a struggle and that it had not been either bombed or machine gunned from the air.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				36,
				42,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1941v02d723"
	},
	{
		"content": "Repeated to Abu Dhabi, Algiers, Baghdad, Bonn, Caracas, Cairo, Damascus, Dhahran, Jakarta, Jidda, Kuwait, Lagos, Libreville, London, Manama, Ottawa, Paris, Quito, Tehran, Tokyo, Tripoli, Vienna, and Geneva.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Caracas",
				47,
				54,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1533",
		"id": "frus1969-76v37d189"
	},
	{
		"content": "['<div collection=\"frus\"> <a href=\"#frus1936v01d412u_n1\"><sup>1</sup></a> [Extracts] No. 538 <p> Sir: Referring to the Department's circular telegram of June 17, 1936, I have the honor to report that Dr. Schacht, Minister for National Economy of the German Reich and President of the Reichsbank, concluded a two-day visit to Belgrade when he departed for Athens on the morning of June 13.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				355,
				361,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1936v01d412"
	},
	{
		"content": "/li> <li id=\"frus1946v07d193u_n3\" value=\"3\">For text of memorandum, dated at Athens on November 25, 1946, see SC, 1st yr., 2nd series, Suppl.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				77,
				83,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1946v07d193"
	},
	{
		"content": "value=\"2\">This telegram was repeated to Bern as 649, to Frankfurt as 537, to Rome as 943, and to London as 1715.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				77,
				81,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1949v05d51"
	},
	{
		"content": "Repeated to Ankara, Athens, London, Ottawa, USUN, and USNATO.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				20,
				26,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1969-76v29d343"
	},
	{
		"content": "He had told Ambassador Goldberg Paks would not move to GA unless U.S. felt it useful.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				55,
				57,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1964-68v25d238"
	},
	{
		"content": "<li id=\"frus1935v01d169u_n3\" value=\"3\">Franco-Italian agreement signed at Rome, January 7, 1935, British and Foreign State Papers, vol.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				74,
				78,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1935v01d169"
	},
	{
		"content": "/li> <li id=\"frus1935v01d169u_n4\" value=\"4\">Nonaggression pact between the members of the Balkan Entente, signed at Athens, February 9, 1934, League of Nations Treaty Series, vol.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				116,
				122,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1935v01d169"
	},
	{
		"content": "Furthermore, if De Gasperi ever wished discuss problems related to SHAPE's mission with him, Gen Eisenhower or Gen Gruenther wld arrange to come to Rome to see him.</p> <p> De Gasperi expressed appreciation and seemed genuinely touched by Gen Eisenhower's offer and his understanding of De Gasperi's problems.</p> <p>At Gen Eisenhower's invitation, De Gasperi, Pacciardi, and Pella visited SHAPE this morning where De Gasperi gave good informal talk to staff.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				148,
				152,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1951v03p1d542"
	},
	{
		"content": "[MacArthur.]</p> <p> Bruce </p> <hr><ol class=\"footnote\"> <li id=\"frus1951v03p1d542u_n1\" value=\"1\">740.5/12-2951: Telegram </li> <li id=\"frus1951v03p1d542u_n2\" value=\"2\">This telegram was repeated for information to Rome and London.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				216,
				220,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1951v03p1d542"
	},
	{
		"content": "Repeated to Athens, Ankara, Nicosia, London, Ottawa, Stockholm, Dublin, and New Delhi.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				12,
				18,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1964-68v33d477"
	},
	{
		"content": "[Attachment] Text of Revised Yugoslav Draft Resolution Handed to Senator Lodge by Dr. Bebler, New York, October 23, 1950 <a href=\"#frus1950v02d244u_n3\"><sup>3</sup></a> <p>[Here follows the text of the preamble, which is the same as that of the original draft resolution; see GA (V), Annexes, Volume II, fascicule 72.]</p> <p",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				276,
				278,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1950v02d244"
	},
	{
		"content": "At the same time we would avoid too great a dependence on communications by the tortuous channel of the Italian Ambassador in Saigon to Rome to the Italian Ambassador here.</p> <p>2.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				136,
				140,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1964-68v04d173"
	},
	{
		"content": "He agreed with Holmes that it would be useful to get Greeks and Turks talking, and that even consideration of partition as a possible solution might tend to move them both from their present positions.</p> <p>Kirkpatrick said that as far as he knew HMG had not decided on its tactics in the GA and presumed that this would be decided by Lloyd on the spot.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				291,
				293,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1955-57v24d206"
	},
	{
		"content": "Repeated to Paris, Ankara, Athens, and Nicosia.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				27,
				33,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1955-57v24d206"
	},
	{
		"content": "Dept wld support such study and believes it wld be appropriate for IC to take it under consideration so that problem of this sort in future may be handled throughout UN in orderly manner and according to procedure laid down by GA pursuant to Art 10 of Charter.<a href=\"#frus1950v02d109u_n2\"><sup>2</sup></a> <",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				227,
				229,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1950v02d109"
	},
	{
		"content": "Rome for MacSweeney.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				0,
				4,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1955-57v12d113"
	},
	{
		"content": "Repeated to Baghdad, Rome, Karachi, Paris, Tehran, London, Cairo, Jidda, Amman, Beirut, Damascus, Belgrade, and Tel Aviv.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				21,
				25,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1955-57v12d113"
	},
	{
		"content": "It would also be helpful in securing the majority approval of this cut from WEU, which they plan to seek.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"WEU",
				76,
				79,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q189946",
		"id": "frus1955-57v27d254"
	},
	{
		"content": "They had sounded out some of the WEU members informally and think that there will be no trouble.</p> <p>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"WEU",
				33,
				36,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q189946",
		"id": "frus1955-57v27d254"
	},
	{
		"content": "We recall two previous instances in which junta opponents were mysteriously attacked: The case of General Carlos Prats, killed in Buenos Aires in September 1974, and the case of Bernardo Leighton, seriously wounded in Rome in October 1975.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				218,
				222,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1969-76ve11p2d247"
	},
	{
		"content": "GOG has no specific information regarding negotiations with Soviets including question of planes.</p> <p>D. Kyprianou coming to Athens tomorrow and may request see me.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				128,
				134,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1964-68v16d151"
	},
	{
		"content": "li id=\"frus1964-68v16d151u_n3\" value=\"3\">Telegram 400 to Athens, August 30, outlined the legal basis for Turkey's right to a troop rotation.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				57,
				63,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1964-68v16d151"
	},
	{
		"content": "['<div collection=\"frus\"> <a href=\"#frus1943d548u_n1\"><sup>1</sup></a> secret <p>I gathered from Minister for Foreign Affairs<a href=\"#frus1943d548u_n3\"><sup>3</sup></a> in San Sebastian yesterday that the Spanish Ambassador in Rome<a href=\"#frus1943d548u_n4\"><sup>4</sup></a> who is in San Sebastian thinks that the Badoglio Government cannot last more than two or three days.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				228,
				232,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1943d548"
	},
	{
		"content": "The Brazilian Ambassador<a href=\"#frus1943d548u_n5\"><sup>5</sup></a> tells me that the Spanish Ambassador in Rome informed him yesterday that there had been two attempts at a coup in Italy, one Fascist and the other military and that the military won.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				109,
				113,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1943d548"
	},
	{
		"content": "We have decided to move in the near future to a working relationship with the regime in Athens.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				88,
				94,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1964-68v16d356"
	},
	{
		"content": "In light above we believe it preferable you remain Athens for time being.</p> <p>7.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				51,
				57,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1964-68v16d356"
	},
	{
		"content": "Repeated to the Mission to NATO and Rome.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				36,
				40,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1964-68v16d356"
	},
	{
		"content": "li id=\"frus1964-68v16d356u_n2\" value=\"2\">In telegram 98588 to Athens, January 15, the Department of State reported that Rockwell had begun a round of meetings with representatives of the NATO allies to explain the change in the U.S. position.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				62,
				68,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1964-68v16d356"
	},
	{
		"content": "In telegram 3248 from Athens, January 19, Talbot suggested that the appropriate line of approach would be a direct response from the President.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				22,
				28,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1964-68v16d356"
	},
	{
		"content": "In telegram 101277 to Athens, the Department of State authorized Talbot to convey orally to Papadopoulos an acknowledgement of his letter and to state the President would soon reply.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				22,
				28,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1964-68v16d356"
	},
	{
		"content": "In telegram 3246 from Athens, January 19, Talbot reported that Papadopoulos had been informed by an Embassy official.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				22,
				28,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1964-68v16d356"
	},
	{
		"content": "/li> <li id=\"frus1964-68v16d356u_n4\" value=\"4\">In telegram 100451 to Athens, January 18, the Department of State reported that Rockwell had called in the Greek Ambassador on January 15 and explained the proposed changes in the U.S. position toward Greece.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				69,
				75,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1964-68v16d356"
	},
	{
		"content": "/li> <li id=\"frus1969-76v38p1d36u_n2\" value=\"2\">Kissinger's post-summit briefings took place in Brussels, Paris, Rome, Dusseldorf, Munich, and London July 3-9.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				113,
				117,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1969-76v38p1d36"
	},
	{
		"content": "\"> What is the final decision on the Santiago and Guantanamo aqueduct proposals?</li> <li value=\"3.\">",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				37,
				45,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q117040",
		"id": "frus1943v06d219"
	},
	{
		"content": "<hr><ol class=\"footnote\"> <li id=\"frus1951v03p1d544u_n1\" value=\"1\">740.5/1-352: Telegram </li> <li id=\"frus1951v03p1d544u_n2\" value=\"2\">This telegram was repeated for information to London, Bonn, Rome, The Hague, Brussels, and Luxembourg, for the eyes only of the Chiefs of Mission.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				196,
				200,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1951v03p1d544"
	},
	{
		"content": "H. Gruber Woolf, rector of St. Paul's American Church in Rome, arrested and imprisoned by the Italians.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				57,
				61,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1942v01d258"
	},
	{
		"content": "In August, 1976, the Conference of Heads of States of Governments of Non-Aligned Countries, held in Colombo, discussed the issue in its political declaration and adopted a resolution calling on the UN to convene a Special Session of the GA to review the problem of disarmament and to promote a program of priorities and measures in the disarmament field.<a href=\"#frus1977-80v26d471u_n3\"><sup>3</sup></a></p> <p>5.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				237,
				239,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1977-80v26d471"
	},
	{
		"content": "Sent also to USUN, USNATO, Canberra, Vienna, Madrid, Stockholm, Tehran, Tokyo, Kuala Lumpur, Manila, Cairo, Monrovia, Rabat, Kinshasa, Buenos Aires, Nassau, Brasilia, Bogota, Caracas, New Delhi, Colombo, and Belgrade.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Caracas",
				175,
				182,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1533",
		"id": "frus1977-80v26d471"
	},
	{
		"content": "['<div collection=\"frus\"> <p>From January 14 to 19, 1980, Edward Fried, a White House consultant on international energy issues, conducted \"exploratory talks\" in Paris, London, Bonn, Brussels, and Rome, with French, International Energy Agency, British, European Community, German, and Italian officials on energy questions \"with a view toward preparations\" for the Venice Summit in June and the IEA Ministerial meeting in March.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				197,
				201,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1969-76v37d255"
	},
	{
		"content": "Discussion topics included the outlook for the international oil market, the spot market, import targets, stock policies, less developed countries, producer-consumer dialogues, and other issues.</p> <p>A summary of the delegation's discussion with French officials on January 14 is in telegram 1565 from Paris, January 15; with OECD Secretary General Emile Van Lennep on January 14 in telegram 1107 from Brussels, January 18; with IEA Executive Director Ulf Lantzke on January 15 in telegram 1107 from Brussels, January 18; with British officials on January 16 in telegram 1189 from London, January 17; with EC officials on January 18 in telegram 1187 from Brussels, January 21; with German officials on January 18 in telegrams 1288 and 1363 from Bonn, January 22 and 23; and with Italian officials on January 19 in telegram 2119 from Rome, January 23.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				835,
				839,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1969-76v37d255"
	},
	{
		"content": "(Legtel 96, November 19)<a href=\"#frus1950v05d600u_n2\"><sup>2</sup></a> </p> <p>Further complicating note in situation is telegram received by King from Ahmad Tukan stating that resolution has no chance of obtaining 2/3 majority in GA and that Israeli delegation now opposes it.</p> <p>Only hope that Jordan will accept resolution is if new Cabinet, composition of which still highly problematical, is amenable to wishes of King.</p>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				232,
				234,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1950v05d600"
	},
	{
		"content": "Stated situation becoming very dangerous and we must decide on the course we will follow.</li> <li value=\"8.\"> Meeting recessed at 12:55 until 3 p. m. at which time discussion item 4 to be continued.</li> </ol> </p> <p>Department pass Department Defense, Brussels (pass to Luxembourg), Ottawa, Copenhagen, Paris (pass OSR), Rome, The Hague, Oslo, Lisbon, London, Heidelberg for Handy.</p> <p> Acheson </p>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				324,
				328,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1950v03d186"
	},
	{
		"content": "When obtaining confirmation from SHAEF that General Eisenhower has made this request you should make similar representations to the French Government referring to the situation described in Rome's telegram of May 6<a href=\"#frus1945v04d692u_n3\"><sup>3</sup></a> repeated to you as 77 and if necessary recalling the recent assurances given you by General de Gaulle.</p> <p> Grew </p>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				190,
				194,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1945v04d692"
	},
	{
		"content": "(Telegrams 4186 from Ankara, March 1, and 3753 from Athens, March 1; both ibid.)",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				52,
				58,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1964-68v16d362"
	},
	{
		"content": "A copy of the Canadian proposals was transmitted in telegram 3749 from Athens, March 1.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				71,
				77,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1964-68v16d362"
	},
	{
		"content": "Since there is no agreement on substance beyond the criteria agreed in Rome last year, it is difficult to understand how these explorations will proceed.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				71,
				75,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1969-76v39d55"
	},
	{
		"content": "<p>Allies can immediately intensify bilateral explorations on the basis of the Rome declaration;<a href=\"#frus1969-76v39d55u_n6\"><sup>6</sup></a> but, if desired by the Allies, the US will participate in revision of the Rome criteria.</p> <p>(b)",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				79,
				83,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1969-76v39d55"
	},
	{
		"content": "Specifically, following are kind of steps US desires see Egypt now take: <ol> <li value=\"a)\"> Offer full cooperation in urgent clearance of Canal;</li> <li value=\"b)\"> Offer full cooperation in renewal of negotiations on future Canal regime;</li> <li value=\"c)\"> Place no obstacle in way of fulfillment by UN force of its responsibilities under GA resolution in Egypt;</li> <li value=\"d)\"> Take effective measures to prevent fedayeen operations;</li> <li value=\"e)\"> Cease operations by Egyptian agents in violation sovereignty and authority of neighboring states;</li> <li value=\"f)\"> Move toward settlement of outstanding problems between Arab states and Israel.</li> </ol></p> <p>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				345,
				347,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1955-57v16d649"
	},
	{
		"content": "Dept has indicated that if such group military personnel could be made available it should reach Athens by Sunday or Monday Aug 25 or Aug 26 and that its duties in Greece would last only about 8 days.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				97,
				103,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1946v07d138"
	},
	{
		"content": "Suitable arrangements will be made for those observers scheduled to take Foreign Service exams Sept 30.</p> <p>Sent Athens 1035, rptd London 6184, Paris 4264 for Secretary.</p> <p> Acheson </p>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				116,
				122,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1946v07d138"
	},
	{
		"content": "As concerns the US-USSR relations, while the Soviets would not be happy at our pushing such an effort in the GA because of the discussion of their practices and potential interference in their internal affairs which might ensue, passage of the draft resolution would probably not have any serious negative impact on our bilateral relations.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				109,
				111,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1969-76ve03d255"
	},
	{
		"content": "While the Department has been glad to use its good offices in obtaining information in regard to the status of your properties and has on several occasions instructed the Embassy at Rome to discuss the matter informally with the Italian authorities, it is not in a position to present a claim for compensation on the basis of the steps so far taken by your board.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				182,
				186,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1939v04d576"
	},
	{
		"content": "Should you desire to inform the Italian Government of any steps which you may propose to take along these lines, the Department will be glad to transmit a message through the Embassy at Rome at your expense.</p> <p>Sincerely yours,</p> <p>For the Secretary of State:Wallace MurrayChief, Division of Near Eastern",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				186,
				190,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1939v04d576"
	},
	{
		"content": "<hr><ol class=\"footnote\"> <li id=\"frus1950v04d126u_n1\" value=\"1\">700.001/2-2450: Telegram </li> <li id=\"frus1950v04d126u_n2\" value=\"2\">This telegram was repeated to Rome, London, Brussels, Bern, and Moscow.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				165,
				169,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1950v04d126"
	},
	{
		"content": "Benoid E. Glawe was the Air Force Attache at Rome.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				45,
				49,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1948v03d453"
	},
	{
		"content": "Repeated to Athens.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				12,
				18,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1961-63v25d339"
	},
	{
		"content": "Deptel 170, Aug 7, refutes Indo claims re freedom rubber markets, and you may wish fully discuss with Indos points covered therein.</p> <p>At Rome rubber conf",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				142,
				146,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1951v06p1d410"
	},
	{
		"content": "Re proposed SA move in GA described Gadel 570,<a href=\"#frus1951v02d487u_n3\"><sup>3</sup></a> USGADel has considered matter in light existing conditions here and of the various procedural possibilities, and offers fol recommendations to Dept in hope they will be helpful:</p> <p>1.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				23,
				25,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1951v02d487"
	},
	{
		"content": "In view consistent US position concerning right GA comites hear such persons as necessary for performance of tasks, and in view our belief that Comite Four res to hear Herero spokesmen was legal, US cannot support res to have GA declare Comite Four res illegal.</li> <li value=\"(b)\"> Such a res as SA contemplates wld certainly fail, and such a GA decision wld set a dangerous precedent which wld be cited in future efforts obtain Comite Four hearings for others.</li> <li value=\"(c)\"> Submittal res under which GA wld declare Comite Four res illegal wld open acrimonious debate in which SA conduct wld be attacked and vilified by numerous dels who might in turn introduce strong res condemning SA.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				48,
				50,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1951v02d487"
	},
	{
		"content": "In view consistent US position concerning right GA comites hear such persons as necessary for performance of tasks, and in view our belief that Comite Four res to hear Herero spokesmen was legal, US cannot support res to have GA declare Comite Four res illegal.</li> <li value=\"(b)\"> Such a res as SA contemplates wld certainly fail, and such a GA decision wld set a dangerous precedent which wld be cited in future efforts obtain Comite Four hearings for others.</li> <li value=\"(c)\"> Submittal res under which GA wld declare Comite Four res illegal wld open acrimonious debate in which SA conduct wld be attacked and vilified by numerous dels who might in turn introduce strong res condemning SA.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				226,
				228,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1951v02d487"
	},
	{
		"content": "In view consistent US position concerning right GA comites hear such persons as necessary for performance of tasks, and in view our belief that Comite Four res to hear Herero spokesmen was legal, US cannot support res to have GA declare Comite Four res illegal.</li> <li value=\"(b)\"> Such a res as SA contemplates wld certainly fail, and such a GA decision wld set a dangerous precedent which wld be cited in future efforts obtain Comite Four hearings for others.</li> <li value=\"(c)\"> Submittal res under which GA wld declare Comite Four res illegal wld open acrimonious debate in which SA conduct wld be attacked and vilified by numerous dels who might in turn introduce strong res condemning SA.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				345,
				347,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1951v02d487"
	},
	{
		"content": "In view consistent US position concerning right GA comites hear such persons as necessary for performance of tasks, and in view our belief that Comite Four res to hear Herero spokesmen was legal, US cannot support res to have GA declare Comite Four res illegal.</li> <li value=\"(b)\"> Such a res as SA contemplates wld certainly fail, and such a GA decision wld set a dangerous precedent which wld be cited in future efforts obtain Comite Four hearings for others.</li> <li value=\"(c)\"> Submittal res under which GA wld declare Comite Four res illegal wld open acrimonious debate in which SA conduct wld be attacked and vilified by numerous dels who might in turn introduce strong res condemning SA.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				512,
				514,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1951v02d487"
	},
	{
		"content": "Repeat to London, Rome, and Tel Aviv.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				18,
				22,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1955-57v15d66"
	},
	{
		"content": "<p>Brit Emb Rep stated Eden had considered carefully US and Fr views expressed at Rome mtgs but had concluded above solution preferable to one using EDC as framework, for fol reasons: (1) doubtful EDC countries, other than Ger, wld be willing to accept controls over armament for purpose settling essentially Occupying Powers-Ger problem; (2) even if this possible, procedure wld further delay buildup Eur armament production and if negots on safeguards unduly prolonged Gers might refuse ultimately to accept them; (3) present uncertainty re form, powers, future development of EDC; (4) difficult domestic Brit factor of justifying turn-over of vital responsibilities re Ger to org of which UK not member.</p> <p>Brit Emb Rep informed we wld study Brit proposal carefully.</p> <p> Webb </p>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				82,
				86,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1951v03p2d200"
	},
	{
		"content": "Despite the difficulty inherent in this as no other alternative seemed open, there was a tendency to seek a solution through future negotiations with Germany particularly in the form of the conference on Austria which it was suggested should take place in Rome in the latter part of May.</p> <p>(5)",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				256,
				260,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1935v01d199"
	},
	{
		"content": "<hr><ol class=\"footnote\"> <li id=\"frus1949v05d96u_n1\" value=\"1\">840.50 Recovery/12-2249: Telegram </li> <li id=\"frus1949v05d96u_n2\" value=\"2\">This telegram was repeated to the Embassies in Copenhagen, Brussels, The Hague, London, Rome, and Oslo.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				230,
				234,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1949v05d96"
	},
	{
		"content": "Repeated to Jidda, Cairo, Dhahran, Tehran, London, Damascus, Amman, Beirut, Tripoli, Ankara, Athens, Rabat, Karachi, and Paris.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				93,
				99,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1955-57v12d455"
	},
	{
		"content": "He told me he and Carandini<a href=\"#frus1946v05d581u_n4\"><sup>4</sup></a> planned to press the Italian Government strongly on their return to Rome, to proceed to the signature of the new armistice agreement.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				143,
				147,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1946v05d581"
	},
	{
		"content": "I therefore suggest that the Embassy at Rome be instructed to urge on the Italian Foreign Minister the desirability of concluding negotiations on the American draft civil affairs agreement on which we are awaiting a reply from the Italians.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				40,
				44,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1946v05d581"
	},
	{
		"content": "The War Department should of course be informed of our action.</p> <p>Sent Dept as 5322; repeated Rome as 272; Caserta as 12.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				98,
				102,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1946v05d581"
	},
	{
		"content": "/li> <li id=\"frus1946v05d581u_n5\" value=\"5\">In reply to this telegram, the Department forwarded to Mr. Dunn a copy of telegram 4058, October 23, from Rome, not printed (740.00119 Contrails Italy)/10-2346).",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				150,
				154,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1946v05d581"
	},
	{
		"content": "This telegram summarized the Italian arguments which were presented in the undated aide-memoire, received in the Embassy in Rome on October 19 (see infra) Mr. Dunn replied in telegram 5391, October 26, that he still felt there would be advantage in concluding the revised armistice, but that the Department would have to judge the validity of Italian objections in the light of the political situation in Italy (740.00119 Control (Italy)/10-2646).",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				124,
				128,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1946v05d581"
	},
	{
		"content": "[No decision yet taken re possible additional statement suggested Rome's 707 Feb 17.]<a href=\"#frus1948v03d558u_n3\"><sup>3</sup></a> </p>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				66,
				70,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1948v03d558"
	},
	{
		"content": "<p>Sent London as 600; rptd Rome as 477; Paris as 551; Moscow as 216; Cairo as 206; and Nairobi for Utter as 27 (Ficus 13).</p> <p> Marshall </p>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				28,
				32,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1948v03d558"
	},
	{
		"content": "(Telegram 6670 from Santiago, October 3; ibid., Central Foreign Policy File, D750344-0601) \"Four toes\" is an incorrect transcription of \"four TOWs,\" a reference to anti-tank weaponry.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				20,
				28,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1969-76ve11p2d203"
	},
	{
		"content": "(Telegram 238245 to Santiago, October 7; ibid., D750346-1211) <",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				20,
				28,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1969-76ve11p2d203"
	},
	{
		"content": "The Government of the Netherlands, in turn, required the Government of Venezuela to agree to periodic visits to Caracas of one or more Netherland officials, for the same purpose.</li> </ol> </p> <p",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Caracas",
				112,
				119,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1533",
		"id": "frus1942v03d81"
	},
	{
		"content": "On the very day of my interview with Mr. Welles, I had another interview, with His Excellency Mr. van, Kleffens, who assured me that he agreed with the terms of the proposed understanding, as set forth above, adding that he would immediately request of Queen Wilhelmina's Government the necessary authorization to conclude the arrangement and that, if the aforesaid basic points were also accept by the Venezuelan Government, he, Mr. van Kleffens, would give instructions to the Netherlands Minister in Caracas to treat with the Government of Venezuela.</p> <p>Under date of the 9th instant, Mr. van Kleffens advised me that he had received authorization from his Government to conclude the agreement and that, when he had been informed of the acceptance of the Government at Caracas, he would transmit the necessary instructions to the Netherlands Minister in Venezuela and, furthermore, that he had requested his Legation in Rio de Janeiro to forward to Mr. Methofer, Netherlands Minister in Venezuela, the complete text of any documents exchanged between the Government of Brazil and the Netherlands Government in order that Mr. Methofer might use them as a model.</p> <p>I now have the honor to write to Your Excellency to advise you that, my Government having been apprised of all the foregoing, it has authorized me to inform Your Excellency and His Excellency",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Caracas",
				503,
				510,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1533",
		"id": "frus1942v03d81"
	},
	{
		"content": "On the very day of my interview with Mr. Welles, I had another interview, with His Excellency Mr. van, Kleffens, who assured me that he agreed with the terms of the proposed understanding, as set forth above, adding that he would immediately request of Queen Wilhelmina's Government the necessary authorization to conclude the arrangement and that, if the aforesaid basic points were also accept by the Venezuelan Government, he, Mr. van Kleffens, would give instructions to the Netherlands Minister in Caracas to treat with the Government of Venezuela.</p> <p>Under date of the 9th instant, Mr. van Kleffens advised me that he had received authorization from his Government to conclude the agreement and that, when he had been informed of the acceptance of the Government at Caracas, he would transmit the necessary instructions to the Netherlands Minister in Venezuela and, furthermore, that he had requested his Legation in Rio de Janeiro to forward to Mr. Methofer, Netherlands Minister in Venezuela, the complete text of any documents exchanged between the Government of Brazil and the Netherlands Government in order that Mr. Methofer might use them as a model.</p> <p>I now have the honor to write to Your Excellency to advise you that, my Government having been apprised of all the foregoing, it has authorized me to inform Your Excellency and His Excellency",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Caracas",
				776,
				783,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1533",
		"id": "frus1942v03d81"
	},
	{
		"content": "I told him we were ready to be helpful in any way agreeable to France and Italy and Grandi remarked that it would advance matters if I could go to Rome.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				147,
				151,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1932v01d348"
	},
	{
		"content": "I told him of my talk with Grandi to which he reacted favorably and said he would welcome our cooperation which would be most helpful.</p> <p> Rosso has just informed me that he has received a message from Rome referring to Grandi's conversation with me and asking him to inform me that Mussolini would be very glad if I would come to Rome and they would like to know if I could possibly meet Mussolini there between the 7th and 10th of this month or on the 13th.</p> <p>I am somewhat reluctant to go now because I have been having too much publicity and my visit there would undoubtedly cause considerable speculation, and also because I would prefer to wait until our negotiations with the British are more crystallized.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				206,
				210,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1932v01d348"
	},
	{
		"content": "I told him of my talk with Grandi to which he reacted favorably and said he would welcome our cooperation which would be most helpful.</p> <p> Rosso has just informed me that he has received a message from Rome referring to Grandi's conversation with me and asking him to inform me that Mussolini would be very glad if I would come to Rome and they would like to know if I could possibly meet Mussolini there between the 7th and 10th of this month or on the 13th.</p> <p>I am somewhat reluctant to go now because I have been having too much publicity and my visit there would undoubtedly cause considerable speculation, and also because I would prefer to wait until our negotiations with the British are more crystallized.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				335,
				339,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1932v01d348"
	},
	{
		"content": "Repeated to London, Ankara, Athens, and Paris for USRO.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				28,
				34,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1958-60v10p1d318"
	},
	{
		"content": "He says the Brazilian Government is anxious for his company to extend services to Buenos Aires (but not to Santiago) as soon as possible and, in fact, the former Argentine Ambassador to Brazil, Dr. Labougle, had expressed the same desire to President Vargas.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				107,
				115,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1942v05d420"
	},
	{
		"content": "PROPOSING CREATION OF A SMALL INFORMAL NEGOTIATING GROUP, TENTATIVELY COMPOSED OF AUSTRALIA, BRAZIL, U.S., FRANCE, UK, INDIA, IRAN, MEXICO, ROMANIA, SENEGAL, SIERRA LEONE, TUNISIA, AND USSR, TO MEET IN NEW YORK TO EXAMINE FOLLOWING TOPICS PERTAINING TO UPCOMING WCIWY, IN ORDER OF PRIORITY: (1) ADVISABILITY OF APPROVING A DECLARATION OF PRINCIPLES, BASED ON DECLARATION OF CARACAS, WHICH NOTE REFERS TO AS REPRESENTING LATIN AMERICAN CONSENSUS; (2) FINAL OBSERVATIONS ON PROPOSED PLAN OF ACTION; (3) PROPOSED RESOLUTIONS WHICH DELEGATIONS MAY BE THINKING OF PRESENTING, INDEPENDENTLY OF PLAN OF ACTION OR DECLARATION.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"CARACAS",
				374,
				381,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1533",
		"id": "frus1969-76ve14p1d179"
	},
	{
		"content": "HOWEVER, U.S. COULD MAKE NO COMMITMENT THAT THIS SHOULD BE BASED ON CARACAS DECLARATION (ECLA REGIONAL SEMINAR ON THE INTEGRATION OF WOMEN IN DEVELOPMENT WITH SPECIAL REFERENCE TO POPULATION FACTORS), SINCE U.S. HAD DIFFICULTIES WITH IT AND WOULD HAVE ABSTAINED HAD THERE BEEN A VOTE.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"CARACAS",
				68,
				75,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1533",
		"id": "frus1969-76ve14p1d179"
	},
	{
		"content": "NOR WOULD IT SERVE THE MAIN INTERESTS OF THE CONFERENCE ITSELF, WHICH ARE TO DEAL WITH ELIMINATION OF DISCRIMINATION AGAINST WOMEN, IN ACCORDANCE WITH GA RESOLUTION CONVOKING CONFERENCE.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				151,
				153,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1969-76ve14p1d179"
	},
	{
		"content": "Aside from the obviously inadequate official announcement that Matsuoka's visit to Berlin and Rome is one of courtesy, no even reasonably authoritative information is available in Tokyo concerning the real purpose or hoped for results of his visits.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				94,
				98,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1941v04d744"
	},
	{
		"content": "In the light of the foregoing it would appear that the real result of Matsuoka's visit to Berlin (his visit to Rome is clearly one of courtesy designed to soothe Italian amour propre) will probably not be revealed until his stop over in Moscow on his way home, and while as indicated above there is no real ground for believing that the signature of an agreement with Russia is the pre-arranged and immediate purpose of his visit, some such agreement would appear to be the hoped for result.</p> <p>Sent to the Department; repeated to Moscow.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				111,
				115,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1941v04d744"
	},
	{
		"content": "But he is on the whole pleased about the general situation in Greece, since the extent of the recognition of himself and his Government which he feels is implicit in EAM's message, seems to bear out reports that in some sections, at least, of public opinion in Athens there has been in recent months a swing toward support of the Government in Exile.</p> <p>The text of the telegrams and further comment are being sent to the Department by airgram.<a href=\"#frus1944v05d84u_n4\"><sup>4</sup></a> </p>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				261,
				267,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1944v05d84"
	},
	{
		"content": "This afternoon the Council will discuss the economic clauses of the Austrian treaty.</p> <p>Repeated London 167, Berlin 296.</p> <p>Department pass to Vienna as 47, Rome as 40 and Paris as 153.</p> <p>[ Marshall ]</p>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				165,
				169,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1947v02d134"
	},
	{
		"content": "I made clear consequences to Israel and US if Jordan lost to West because US decided against arms deal in light Israeli opposition or because Israelis fiddled while Rome burned.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				165,
				169,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q18287233",
		"id": "frus1964-68v18d163"
	},
	{
		"content": "Sent for information to Ankara, Athens, Brussels, Copenhagen, The Hague, Lisbon, London, Luxembourg, Oslo, Ottawa, Paris, Reykjavik, Rome, Belgrade, Bucharest, Budapest, Prague, Sofia, Warsaw, the Mission in Berlin, Bremen, Dusseldorf, Frankfurt, Hamburg, Munich, Stuttgart, CINCUSAFE Ramstein, CINCEUR Vaihingen, CINCUSAREUR Heidelberg, and USNMR SHAPE.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				32,
				38,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1969-76ve15p2d279"
	},
	{
		"content": "Sent for information to Ankara, Athens, Brussels, Copenhagen, The Hague, Lisbon, London, Luxembourg, Oslo, Ottawa, Paris, Reykjavik, Rome, Belgrade, Bucharest, Budapest, Prague, Sofia, Warsaw, the Mission in Berlin, Bremen, Dusseldorf, Frankfurt, Hamburg, Munich, Stuttgart, CINCUSAFE Ramstein, CINCEUR Vaihingen, CINCUSAREUR Heidelberg, and USNMR SHAPE.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				133,
				137,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1969-76ve15p2d279"
	},
	{
		"content": "Sent to Ankara, Athens, Bern, Bonn, Brussels, Copenhagen, Dublin, London, Luxembourg, Madrid, Paris, Reykjavik, Rome, Vienna, Oslo, Stockholm, The Hague, and Lisbon.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				16,
				22,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1955-57v16d584"
	},
	{
		"content": "Sent to Ankara, Athens, Bern, Bonn, Brussels, Copenhagen, Dublin, London, Luxembourg, Madrid, Paris, Reykjavik, Rome, Vienna, Oslo, Stockholm, The Hague, and Lisbon.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				112,
				116,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1955-57v16d584"
	},
	{
		"content": "In telegram 7172 from Santiago, July 22, Popper reported that the Chilean Government appeared to be reviewing its economic relations with the United States in light of the restrictions imposed by the Security Assistance Act.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				22,
				30,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1969-76ve11p2d237"
	},
	{
		"content": "US adds that building 2/3 requirement explicitly into resolution may also prove a limiting factor.</p> <p>US actively seeks co-sponsors and agreement on text, as well as support within GA from countries who may not be prepared to cosponsor.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				185,
				187,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1969-76v05d372"
	},
	{
		"content": "Secretary Acheson was in Paris, for the Sixth Session of the U.N. General Assembly, and in Rome, for the Eighth Session of the North Atlantic Council.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				91,
				95,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1951v04p2d182"
	},
	{
		"content": "Raul Castro; Dr. Lucas Moran, Santiago lawyer; Anibal Castilla, further identification unknown; and Torre claim have engineered kidnapping Americans and Canadians.</p> <p>Torre said if Communists wanted join as soldiers would be permitted do so.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				30,
				38,
				"NORP"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q117040",
		"id": "frus1958-60v06d101"
	},
	{
		"content": "Arthur Ross and John Best, two of released Americans, describe Raul Castro's men as extremely religious, anti-Communist and ultra super-nationalist.</p> <p>Wollam gathered impression Raul Castro going through motions organizing free territory government in his area and asked him what kind of recognition his group would receive from Consulate in Santiago if 26 July movement took over that city.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				347,
				355,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q117040",
		"id": "frus1958-60v06d101"
	},
	{
		"content": "If, he continued, the GA made decisions and issued directives, the Afro-Asian group together with the Soviet bloc would be in a position to exercise command in a manner contrary to Western interests.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				22,
				24,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1955-57v21d139"
	},
	{
		"content": "Citing, as an example, the number of anti-Soviet votes on the Hungarian resolutions, he pointed out that the \"degree of command\" exercised by the potentially decisive votes of a joint Afro-Asian and Soviet bloc varied considerably and that the Soviet bloc alone could not defeat a motion in the GA.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				295,
				297,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1955-57v21d139"
	},
	{
		"content": "At any rate, it now appeared difficult, if not impossible, to remedy the potential imbalance of votes in the GA through the introduction of \"weighted voting\" procedures.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				109,
				111,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1955-57v21d139"
	},
	{
		"content": "A/1396, \"draft convention relating to the status of refugees: note by the Secretary-General,\" in GA (V), Annexes, agenda item 32, p. 11, and U.N. Doc.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				97,
				99,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1950v02d310"
	},
	{
		"content": "/li> <li id=\"frus1950v02d310u_n3\" value=\"3\">For text of article 1 of the draft convention, with its definition of the term \"refugee\", see GA (V), Annexes, agenda item 32, pp. 10 and 11, and Doc. US/A/C.3/319, infra.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				138,
				140,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1950v02d310"
	},
	{
		"content": "Although they recognize that purpose of resolution would be also to discourage such aggression by demonstrating in advance that means exist to prevent hamstringing of UN by veto, they nevertheless, from overall political viewpoint, doubt usefulness of proposed action at this time.</p> <p>From legal point of view, central question is whether resolution would conflict with article 12 of charter (which prevents GA front making recommendations re any dispute or situation while subject is on SC agenda).",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				412,
				414,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1950v02d184"
	},
	{
		"content": "Perhaps SC could, if action is blocked by veto, decide by affirmative vote of 7 members (without possibility of veto, since this would be procedural matter) simply to remove item from agenda in which case it would be proper for GA to deal with it.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				228,
				230,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1950v02d184"
	},
	{
		"content": "The element contained in it which bears on relationship to article 12, namely convocation of GA on 24 hour notice, could be dealt with by simple change in rules, without need for any GA resolution.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				93,
				95,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1950v02d184"
	},
	{
		"content": "The element contained in it which bears on relationship to article 12, namely convocation of GA on 24 hour notice, could be dealt with by simple change in rules, without need for any GA resolution.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				183,
				185,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1950v02d184"
	},
	{
		"content": "But this did not succeed for British Ambassador in Athens remained adamant.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				51,
				57,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1946v07d69"
	},
	{
		"content": "At end of his letter Bevin advised Sophoulis to turn for support to Chief of British Police in Athens.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				95,
				101,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1946v07d69"
	},
	{
		"content": "Please transmit a copy of my statement to the Foreign Secretary for his information and send copies to the Embassies in Paris and Rome and to the Consulate in Geneva.<a href=\"#frus1935v01d649u_n2\"><sup>2</sup></a> </p> <p",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				130,
				134,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1935v01d649"
	},
	{
		"content": "At same meeting, however, Pres betrayed unusual sensitivity about fact that some military and civilian elements had interpreted routine political contacts by our Consulate in Santiago as US support for PQD.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				175,
				183,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q42763",
		"id": "frus1964-68v32d205"
	},
	{
		"content": "A clause covering Austria's general economic relations was approved.</p> <p>The Council adjourned after agreeing to hold two meetings Sunday.</p> <p>Department please pass to Vienna as 50, Rome as 42, and Paris as 161.</p> <p>Sent Department as 1480, repeated London 174, Berlin 307.</p> <p>[ Marshall ]</p>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				189,
				193,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1947v02d142"
	},
	{
		"content": "Not only are Santiago and Rio sending such supplementary data on subversive activities as may hook up with those in the Argentine, but a very comprehensive memorandum prepared by the F. B. I.<a href=\"#frus1942v05d206u_n3\"><sup>3</sup></a> was sent down by courier yesterday to the Embassy in Buenos Aires.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				13,
				21,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1942v05d206"
	},
	{
		"content": "Repeated to Ankara, Karachi, Tehran, Cairo, Jidda, Amman, Beirut, Damascus, Rome, Paris, New Delhi, and London.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				76,
				80,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1955-57v12d112"
	},
	{
		"content": "We continue to believe that action by the GA is important in order to avoid this erroneous impression, but subject to that would have no objection to an initial step in the SC.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				42,
				44,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1951v07p1d538"
	},
	{
		"content": "We plan to depart Cairo at 1200 noon Wednesday and arrive Athens approximately 300 P.M.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				58,
				64,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1955-57v15d164"
	},
	{
		"content": "/li> <li id=\"frus1964-68v31d296u_n2\" value=\"2\">Reported in telegram 206 from Santiago, July 19.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				77,
				85,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1964-68v31d296"
	},
	{
		"content": "Korry was confirmed by the Senate on August 23 and presented his credentials in Santiago on October 16.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				80,
				88,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1964-68v31d296"
	},
	{
		"content": "['<div collection=\"frus\"> <a href=\"#frus1943v02d811u_n1\"><sup>1</sup></a> <p>I think it is worthwhile to get word to Monsignor Cicognani in very polite language: <ol> <li value=\"(a)\"> That we fully realize all that the Pope has said about Rome as a whole and that we have no desire to destroy any church property or historic monuments.</li> <li value=\"(b)\"> That, nevertheless, because war is war we must recognize that Rome is the center of the Italian Government and is of definite use to that government in conducting the war against us.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				239,
				243,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1943v02d811"
	},
	{
		"content": "['<div collection=\"frus\"> <a href=\"#frus1943v02d811u_n1\"><sup>1</sup></a> <p>I think it is worthwhile to get word to Monsignor Cicognani in very polite language: <ol> <li value=\"(a)\"> That we fully realize all that the Pope has said about Rome as a whole and that we have no desire to destroy any church property or historic monuments.</li> <li value=\"(b)\"> That, nevertheless, because war is war we must recognize that Rome is the center of the Italian Government and is of definite use to that government in conducting the war against us.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				420,
				424,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1943v02d811"
	},
	{
		"content": "This applies also to the fact that many Germans help to run Italy, with German staffs located in Rome itself.</li> <li value=\"(c)\"> Therefore, in order to be fair and equally just to both sides, we suggest that the Vatican try to have Rome declared an open city i.e. that all military installations, activities and personnel of Italy be removed from Rome, together with the use of all railroad facilities in and about Rome for military purposes.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				97,
				101,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1943v02d811"
	},
	{
		"content": "This applies also to the fact that many Germans help to run Italy, with German staffs located in Rome itself.</li> <li value=\"(c)\"> Therefore, in order to be fair and equally just to both sides, we suggest that the Vatican try to have Rome declared an open city i.e. that all military installations, activities and personnel of Italy be removed from Rome, together with the use of all railroad facilities in and about Rome for military purposes.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				235,
				239,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1943v02d811"
	},
	{
		"content": "This applies also to the fact that many Germans help to run Italy, with German staffs located in Rome itself.</li> <li value=\"(c)\"> Therefore, in order to be fair and equally just to both sides, we suggest that the Vatican try to have Rome declared an open city i.e. that all military installations, activities and personnel of Italy be removed from Rome, together with the use of all railroad facilities in and about Rome for military purposes.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				350,
				354,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1943v02d811"
	},
	{
		"content": "This applies also to the fact that many Germans help to run Italy, with German staffs located in Rome itself.</li> <li value=\"(c)\"> Therefore, in order to be fair and equally just to both sides, we suggest that the Vatican try to have Rome declared an open city i.e. that all military installations, activities and personnel of Italy be removed from Rome, together with the use of all railroad facilities in and about Rome for military purposes.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				418,
				422,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1943v02d811"
	},
	{
		"content": "Athens 2956.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				0,
				6,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1955-57v24d227"
	},
	{
		"content": "Athens may particularly inquire as to FonMin proposals for independence with anti-Anschluss guarantee.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				0,
				6,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1955-57v24d227"
	},
	{
		"content": "Athens may wish to reiterate our desire implement offer made by USUN to assist in constructive manner.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				0,
				6,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1955-57v24d227"
	},
	{
		"content": "The report of the Subcommittee contains the text of the recommended resolution, the membership of the Subcommittee, its terms of reference, and a summary of its work; for text of the report, see GA (I/2), First Committee, pp. 346-48.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				195,
				197,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1946v01d563"
	},
	{
		"content": "After some experience in talking and dealing with them here, it is my considered, if not original conviction that a modicum of attention to their pride is worth many dollars.</p> <p>MacVeagh</p> <hr><ol class=\"footnote\"> <li id=\"frus1952-54v06p2d863u_n1\" value=\"1\">711.56352/7-2552: Telegram </li> <li id=\"frus1952-54v06p2d863u_n2\" value=\"2\">Repeated to Paris, London, and Rome.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				373,
				377,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1952-54v06p2d863"
	},
	{
		"content": "Furthermore, El Mercurio, El Diario Ilustrado and other Santiago newspapers reported on February 23 that this vast spy ring had been discovered with the aid of the United States intelligence service.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				56,
				64,
				"NORP"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1944v07d756"
	},
	{
		"content": "Repeated to Athens and Ankara.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				12,
				18,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1955-57v24d122"
	},
	{
		"content": "/li> <li id=\"frus1951v05d641u_n3\" value=\"3\">Presumably the information contained in this paragraph came from telegram 2438 from Athens, January 31, which is not here printed.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				128,
				134,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1951v05d641"
	},
	{
		"content": "Moreover, Peurifoy reported that British officials in Athens were surprised at the idea that the 1939 guarantee was still considered to be valid by Turkey, and they believed that the British Foreign Office and the government would be ill-disposed to consider the commitment still binding.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				54,
				60,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1951v05d641"
	},
	{
		"content": "['<div collection=\"frus\"> <p>The attached draft cable to Santiago has been sent by State for NSC clearance.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				57,
				65,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1969-76v21d358"
	},
	{
		"content": "Moreover, State doubts that the supplies mentioned are essential to Chilean military success.</p> <p>Our Embassy in Santiago judges that the flares are important to the Chilean Air Force's success in nighttime operations in the days ahead.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				116,
				124,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1969-76v21d358"
	},
	{
		"content": "Unless other interests would be damaged (as above), I suggest we go back to Santiago with an offer to meet modest military request--assuming we will take the steps necessary to minimize early publicity.<a href=\"#frus1969-76v21d358u_n4\"><sup>4</sup></a> On the recognition question, the suggested approach seems about right--but I would urge that we not wait more than \"a few days.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				76,
				84,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1969-76v21d358"
	},
	{
		"content": "Sent as telegram 185004 to Santiago, September 18.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				27,
				35,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1969-76v21d358"
	},
	{
		"content": "/li> <li id=\"frus1969-76v21d358u_n3\" value=\"3\">Davis informed the Department that he had received the note in telegram 4356 from Santiago, September 17.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				129,
				137,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1969-76v21d358"
	},
	{
		"content": "(Telegrams 187007 and 29210 to Santiago, September 17 and 20; ibid., Nixon Presidential Materials, NSC Files, Box 777, Country Files, Latin America, Chile, Vol. VIII)",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				31,
				39,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1969-76v21d358"
	},
	{
		"content": "(Telegram 4474 from Santiago, September 21 and telegram 189358 to Santiago, September 22; both ibid.)",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				20,
				28,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1969-76v21d358"
	},
	{
		"content": "(Telegram 4474 from Santiago, September 21 and telegram 189358 to Santiago, September 22; both ibid.)",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				66,
				74,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1969-76v21d358"
	},
	{
		"content": "Ref: Deptel 6208, April 20 repeated Bonn 2771, Brussels 1285, Canberra 875, Paris 5349, Rome 2205, The Hague 705.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				88,
				92,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1964-68v34d46"
	},
	{
		"content": "Repeated to Bonn, Brussels, Canberra, Paris, Rome, and The Hague.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				45,
				49,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1964-68v34d46"
	},
	{
		"content": "Mr. Allen agreed, noting that significant hotel expansion is being carried out in Athens, and that the projected Balkan highway would be of great help also.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				82,
				88,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1955-57v24d314"
	},
	{
		"content": "\"> Wld be most advantageous Israel undertake prompt reconsideration its position which if allowed to stand may well serve as basis for termination conf with subsequent PCC report to GA of complete failure.</li> <li value=\"3.\">",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				182,
				184,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1951v05d512"
	},
	{
		"content": "How would \"blanket\" approach provide for such points as GA recommendation to disarm and intern guerrillas, authority to consult Interim Committee, and recommendation states other than A, B and Y give no aid to guerrillas, etc?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				56,
				58,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1948v04d189"
	},
	{
		"content": "In this connection, an injunction from GA to UNSCOB to continue its activities in the same manner as present operation would seem meet this point.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				39,
				41,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1948v04d189"
	},
	{
		"content": "<li id=\"frus1948v04d189u_n2\" value=\"2\">Identified also as telegram 1739, September 2, 7 p. m., from Athens; it reported a \"feeling among several of more realistically minded that US recommendations would be weak anti-climax to strong conclusions in that they offer no practical solution to problem pointed to by such conclusions.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				100,
				106,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1948v04d189"
	},
	{
		"content": "This thinking has prompted Netherlands delegate to come forward in corridors with outline of proposed GA resolution which would (1) adopt and approve general and supplementary reports (2) approve manner in which committee had discharged its mandate (3) direct it to carry on in same manner.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				102,
				104,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1948v04d189"
	},
	{
		"content": "<li id=\"frus1948v04d189u_n3\" value=\"3\">Identified also as telegram 1263, September 2, 12 noon, to Athens; it cited an Athens press source alleging that Yugoslavia was interning guerrillas crossing the Yugoslav border and in some cases turning them back (501.BB Balkan/9-248).",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				98,
				104,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1948v04d189"
	},
	{
		"content": "<li id=\"frus1948v04d189u_n3\" value=\"3\">Identified also as telegram 1263, September 2, 12 noon, to Athens; it cited an Athens press source alleging that Yugoslavia was interning guerrillas crossing the Yugoslav border and in some cases turning them back (501.BB Balkan/9-248).",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				118,
				124,
				"NORP"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1948v04d189"
	},
	{
		"content": "<li id=\"frus1948v04d189u_n5\" value=\"5\">Identified also as telegram 1242 to Athens, dated August 28, not printed.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				75,
				81,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1948v04d189"
	},
	{
		"content": "['<div collection=\"frus\"> <p>The Eighth Session of the North Atlantic Council met in Rome on November 24-28, 1951, and heard numerous reports concerning the status and readiness of NATO defense forces and plans for increasing military production.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				85,
				89,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1951v03p1d195"
	},
	{
		"content": "He tells me that following the broadcast from Athens reporting Weygand there June 30 en route to Syria he cautioned the British authorities against accepting without verification reports from interested foreign sources regarding this area and later was informed officially that subsequent inquiry in Athens had failed to reveal anyone who had seen Weygand there and at various times since Weygand left here for France on March 29 I have inquired of High Commissioner Puaux as to the truth of successive reports that Weygand had returned.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				46,
				52,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1940v03d825"
	},
	{
		"content": "He tells me that following the broadcast from Athens reporting Weygand there June 30 en route to Syria he cautioned the British authorities against accepting without verification reports from interested foreign sources regarding this area and later was informed officially that subsequent inquiry in Athens had failed to reveal anyone who had seen Weygand there and at various times since Weygand left here for France on March 29 I have inquired of High Commissioner Puaux as to the truth of successive reports that Weygand had returned.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				300,
				306,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1940v03d825"
	},
	{
		"content": "Received at 6:14 p.m. Repeated to Paris, Rome, Cairo, Ankara, and London.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rome",
				41,
				45,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q220",
		"id": "frus1955-57v14d425"
	},
	{
		"content": "As Ambassador Davis pointed out in his recent general review (Santiago 0953),<a href=\"#frus1969-76v21d292u_n2\"><sup>2</sup></a> the Marxists contend that the growing economic crisis need not be decisive for the Allende government if it can consolidate its control over the economy and work from that base to change the political balance in its favor.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				62,
				70,
				"NORP"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1969-76v21d292"
	},
	{
		"content": "> From the United States and/or an airport serving the Canal Zone (provided that if such airport be located not in the Canal Zone, but in the Republic of Panama, the consent of Panama be obtained) via intermediate points in the Caribbean, Central America, and South America, via Lima, Peru, and/or La Paz, Bolivia, and/or Antofagasta, Chile, and/or Santiago, Chile, to Salta, Tucuman, Cordoba and Buenos Aires, and beyond.</li> <li value=\"3.\">",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				349,
				357,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1947v08d212"
	},
	{
		"content": "Sent for information Immediate to USUN and London and for information to Santiago and Montevideo.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Santiago",
				73,
				81,
				"GPE"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q2887",
		"id": "frus1981-88v13d21"
	},
	{
		"content": "In reply my question Loizides stated that if no other action taken in meantime, Cypriots intended raise question next GA meeting and would be constrained request assistance some other govts perhaps even eastern European one if Greek Govt would not serve as sponsor.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				118,
				120,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1951v05d256"
	},
	{
		"content": "I asked him if he realized what an unpleasant and difficult question this would be in GA and if he were aware that US Govt might well not support Cypriot claim before UN especially if international situation remained tense.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"GA",
				86,
				88,
				"ORG"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q47423",
		"id": "frus1951v05d256"
	},
	{
		"content": "/li> <li id=\"frus1951v05d256u_n3\" value=\"3\">Peurifoy had reported Makarios' arrival in Athens on March 13 \"to see leaders all political parties on Cyprus question.\"",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				87,
				93,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1951v05d256"
	},
	{
		"content": "(747C.00/3-1451) Peurifoy's report on his meeting with Prime Minister Venizelos on March 19, during the course of which Venizelos \"confided his anxiety with growing pressure for Cyprus union with Greece\" is in telegram 3074 from Athens, March 19 (747C.00/3-1951).",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Athens",
				229,
				235,
				"LOC"
			]
		],
		"wiki": "Q1524",
		"id": "frus1951v05d256"
	},
	{
