[
	{
		"content": "Allison tom next uuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuumiuuuiiuuuuuuuuuiiiiuuuuuuuumiiiiiuuuuuuuuuumiiiuu uuuuuuuuuuuiiuuuumiiuuuuuuumuuuuuumiiuuiiiiiuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuiiiuuuuuiiiuuuuum Apr 1, 2020 5: 59 PM Our new Board takes office on April 21.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Allison tom",
				0,
				11,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Apr 1, 2020",
				191,
				202,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"April 21",
				242,
				250,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "At that meeting we elect a new County Board Chair.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "We do this through a confidential ballot/ voting process.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "We are hoping to do this remotely this year.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Have you used an online voting system allowing for confidential ballots?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Thanks.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Mark Abeles- Allison County Administrator County of Bayfield Washburn WI markaa@bayfieldcounty.org V: I?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Mark Abeles- Allison",
				0,
				20,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"County Administrator",
				21,
				41,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"County of Bayfield",
				42,
				60,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Washburn WI",
				61,
				72,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"markaa@bayfieldcounty.org",
				73,
				98,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "previous next Apr 1,2020 5: 22 PM C' a U' ii irl e .' irc r:rlb Good evening, Checking to see how other communities are handling FFCRA as it relates to public safety.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Apr 1,2020",
				14,
				24,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"FFCRA",
				129,
				134,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "HR and our public safety directors disagree on approach.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Catherine Crosby MPA Chief of Staff 748 City of Toledo Toledo OH catherine.crosby@toledo.oh.gov IV:.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Catherine Crosby",
				0,
				16,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"MPA Chief of Staff",
				17,
				35,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"City of Toledo",
				40,
				54,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Toledo OH",
				55,
				64,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"catherine.crosby@toledo.oh.gov",
				65,
				95,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The City of Delaware is exploring with our local University and with local hotels the possibility of creating an agreement or MOU to secure facilities for additional quarantine space ( if needed) for our safety forces.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"City of Delaware",
				4,
				20,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"University",
				49,
				59,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "We are having internal conversations regarding liability, but would be interested if any communities have created an agreement/ MOU and would be willing to share their agreement language or connect further on this topic.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "I have attached a DRAFT of what we are working on, but has not yet been finalized.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Thank you and stay safe!",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Kyle Kyle Kridler Assistant City Manager City of Delaware Delaware OH kkridler@delawareohio.net",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Kyle",
				0,
				4,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Kyle Kridler",
				5,
				17,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Assistant City Manager",
				18,
				40,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"City of Delaware",
				41,
				57,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Delaware OH",
				58,
				69,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"kkridler@delawareohio.net",
				70,
				95,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Obviously if there is someone who is willing to assume care of the pet in the home that is the best choice.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "However, if the person is taken to the hospital and has no back- up pet caretaker, animal control might have to take the pet into the shelter.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Here is the National Animal Control Association' s statement on removal of pets in homes of residents with COVID with precautions to keep your animal control workers safe.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"National Animal Control Association",
				12,
				47,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"COVID",
				107,
				112,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "www.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "nacanet.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "org/ wp- content/ uploads/ 2020/ 03/...",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Ledy VanKavage, Esq.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Ledy VanKavage",
				0,
				14,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Esq",
				16,
				19,
				"TITLE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Sr.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Legislative Attorney Best Friends Animal Society",
		"entities": [
					[
				"Legislative Attorney",
				0,
				20,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"Best Friends Animal Society",
				21,
				48,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "618- 550- 9469 CELL bestfriends.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"618- 550- 9469",
				0,
				14,
				"PHONE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "org facebook.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "com/ bestfriendsanimalsociety I twitter.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Like many local governments, we are freezing non -essential expenditures and hiring until we have a clearer picture of the financial impacts of this pandemic.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "I' m curious what guidance folks are providing to their department heads regarding spending or if you have any communications you would be willing to share.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Ethan Manning Director of Finance City of Newburyport Newburyport MA emanning@cityofnewburyport.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Ethan Manning",
				0,
				13,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Director of Finance",
				14,
				33,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"City of Newburyport",
				34,
				53,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Newburyport MA",
				54,
				68,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"emanning@cityofnewburyport",
				69,
				95,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Apr 1, 2020 10: 01 AM I.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Apr 1, 2020",
				0,
				11,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I asked them all to limit spending to essential services in support of the City' s efforts to prevent, prepare for, or respond to the coronavirus pandemic.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"City",
				75,
				79,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"coronavirus",
				134,
				145,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I am developing more refined guidance as we get a better handle on our revenue projection adjustments.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Tanisha Briley City Manager City of Cleveland Heights Cleveland Heights OH citymanager@clvhts.com F Original Message:",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Tanisha Briley",
				0,
				14,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"City Manager",
				15,
				27,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"City of Cleveland Heights",
				28,
				53,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Cleveland Heights OH",
				54,
				74,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"citymanager@clvhts.com",
				75,
				97,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Sent: 04- 01- 2020 08: 28 AM From: Ethan Manning Subject:",
		"entities": [
			[
				"04- 01- 2020",
				6,
				18,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"Ethan Manning",
				35,
				48,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Spending and Hiring Freeze Like many local governments, we are freezing non -essential expenditures and hiring until we have a clearer picture of the financial impacts of this pandemic.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "I' m curious what guidance folks are providing to their department heads regarding spending or if you have any communications you would be willing to share.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Ethan Manning Director of Finance City of Newburyport Newburyport MA nl ad.leal.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Ethan Manning",
				0,
				13,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Director of Finance",
				14,
				33,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"City of Newburyport",
				34,
				53,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Newburyport MA",
				54,
				68,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "We' ve not released official guidance, but did tell departments we are freezing hiring and reviewing on a case by case basis.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "We will do the same for expenditures.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "I' ll keep you posted if we come up with official guidance.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "751 Catherine Crosby MPA Chief of Staff City of Toledo Toledo OH catherine.crosby@toledo.oh.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Catherine Crosby",
				4,
				20,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"MPA",
				21,
				24,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"Chief of Staff",
				25,
				39,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"City of Toledo",
				40,
				54,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Toledo OH",
				55,
				64,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"catherine.crosby@toledo.oh",
				65,
				91,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Ilrllillliiillrlli Original Message: Sent: 04- 01- 2020 08: 28 AM From: Ethan Manning Subject: Spending and Hiring Freeze",
		"entities": [
			[
				"04- 01- 2020",
				43,
				55,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"Ethan Manning",
				72,
				85,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Like many local governments, we are freezing non -essential expenditures and hiring until we have a clearer picture of the financial impacts of this pandemic.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "I' m curious what guidance folks are providing to their department heads regarding spending or if you have any communications you would be willing to share.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Ethan Manning Director of Finance City of Newburyport Newburyport MA en,ia iri,r°ucoiltu too previous next i uuuu u lu. . .",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Ethan Manning",
				0,
				13,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Director of Finance",
				14,
				33,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"City of Newburyport",
				34,
				53,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Newburyport MA",
				54,
				68,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Apr 1, 2020 6: 20 PM r..:!",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Apr 1, 2020",
				0,
				11,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "in::, io[ J-Ily....",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Ikl Tipp City has put a hiring freeze on also, unless it is a critical posit on such as a lineman.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Tipp City",
				4,
				13,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "We had a part- time administrative assistant leave due to her husbands relocation",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "and we are not filling the position.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Timothy Eggleston ICMA-CM,MPA City Manager City of Tipp City Tipp City OH egglestl 0@gmail.com F Original Mes age: 752 ']",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Timothy Eggleston",
				0,
				17,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"ICMA-CM,MPA",
				18,
				29,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"City Manager",
				30,
				42,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"City of Tipp City",
				43,
				60,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Tipp City OH",
				61,
				73,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"egglestl 0@gmail.com",
				74,
				94,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "['Sent from my iPhone On Mar 21, 2020, at 12:10 AM, PITTMAN, RYAN D <rpittman(@email.sc.edu>wrote: Good Evening Dr. Fauci, My name is Ryan Pittman.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Mar 21, 2020",
				25,
				37,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"PITTMAN, RYAN D",
				52,
				67,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"rpittman(@email.sc.edu",
				69,
				91,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Dr. Fauci",
				112,
				121,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Ryan Pittman",
				134,
				146,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "| live in outh Carolina, right outside of |",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Carolina",
				15,
				23,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The virus is here.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Seeing as this is likely to get worse before it gets better, | want to be prepared to help people in my neighborhood when they start developing symptoms and the hospitals are not ready for them.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "How do you recommend | go about doing this.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "| am prepared to acquire a modest stockpile of supplies to give to those suffering through this, but | am not entirely sure what would be best.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "The hope is to take your information and pass it on to those in other neighborhoods in the area, so we can come together and help as many people as we can get through this pandemic.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Thank you for your time.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "[' FINN Partners FINN PARTNERS TRAVEL, MARKETING, AND RESEARCH INSIGHTS PRACTICAL CONTENT FROM OUR GLOBAL TEAM OF EXPERTS FINN Travel Finn Partners Travel and Lifestyle practice features experts from around the globe representing destinations, airlines, hotels, cruise lines, travel service providers and attractions worldwide.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"FINN Partners",
				3,
				16,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"FINN PARTNERS",
				17,
				30,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"FINN Travel",
				122,
				133,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Finn Partners Travel and Lifestyle",
				134,
				168,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "From all sectors, we are seeing the travel industry heavily impacted by the COVID-19 Pandemic.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"COVID-19",
				76,
				84,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Our teams have combined some of our best thinking on trends and new directions to assist those in the industry in finding a positive way forward.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "We hope you find these insights useful in your planning and remember, #DontCancelPostpone #TravelTomorrow TRAVEL BRANDS STRIVE TO FIND BALANCE BETWEEN INSPIRATIONAL AND PROMOTIONAL As travel restrictions from the Coronavirus have spread across the world, it’s evident that tourism is currently one of the most affected sectors during this pandemic...",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Coronavirus",
				213,
				224,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Read more HOW TO ADAPT SOCIAL MEDIA STRATEGY FOR THE COVID-19 CRISIS As people across the globe are forced into self-isolation in a bid to prevent the spread of Coronavirus, a new virtual world is evolving and people’s attitudes are switching to a new focus at home...",
		"entities": [
			[
				"COVID-19",
				53,
				61,
				"MED"
			],
			[
				"Coronavirus",
				161,
				172,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Read more ARMCHAIR TOURISM THE RISE OF ARMCHAIR TOURISM It was Russian revolutionary leader Vladimir Lenin who once said: “There are decades where nothing happens, and then there are weeks where decades happen.”",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Russian",
				63,
				70,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Vladimir Lenin",
				92,
				106,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "And there can be little doubt that these past few weeks...",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Read more THE STATE OF SPORTS With the Olympics postponed until July 2021, Wimbledon cancelled, the National Basketball Association (NBA) and National Hockey League (NHL) seasons suspended....",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Olympics",
				39,
				47,
				"EVENT"
			],
			[
				"July 2021",
				64,
				73,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"Wimbledon",
				75,
				84,
				"EVENT"
			],
			[
				"National Basketball Association",
				100,
				131,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"NBA",
				133,
				136,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"National Hockey League",
				142,
				164,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"NHL",
				166,
				169,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Read more TRAVEL BEYOND COVID-19: FIVE KEY TAKEAWAYS FROM THE EXPERTS",
		"entities": [
			[
				"COVID-19",
				24,
				32,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The travel industry is actively working to understand the long-term impacts of COVID-19.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"COVID-19",
				79,
				87,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "CatchOn, a FINN Partners company in Asia, took on this topic within a webinar series where thought leaders assess how e...",
		"entities": [
			[
				"CatchOn",
				0,
				7,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"FINN Partners",
				11,
				24,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Asia",
				36,
				40,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Read more For more information on Finn Partners Travel Practice please contact: Debbie Flynn – Global Travel Amy Skelding – UK/Europe Virginia Sheridan – U.S. Cathy Chon – Asia Terry Ferraro – Promotions and Partnerships For more information on Finn Partners Research please contact: Barry Reicherter - Research, Planning, and Measurement FINNPARTNERS.COM Finn Partners, 301 East 57th Street, New York, NY Unsubscribe Manage preferences ']",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Finn Partners Travel Practice",
				34,
				63,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Debbie Flynn",
				80,
				92,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Amy Skelding",
				109,
				121,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"UK/Europe",
				124,
				133,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Virginia Sheridan",
				134,
				151,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"U.S.",
				154,
				158,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Cathy Chon",
				159,
				169,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"Asia",
				172,
				176,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Terry Ferraro",
				177,
				190,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Finn Partners Research",
				245,
				267,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Barry Reicherter",
				284,
				300,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"FINNPARTNERS.COM",
				339,
				355,
				"URL"
			],
			[
				"Finn Partners",
				356,
				369,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"301 East 57th Street",
				371,
				391,
				"ADDRESS"
			],
			[
				"New York, NY",
				393,
				405,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "['Meanwhile, please keep in mind that the best ways to prevent the spread of COVID-19 are: Maintain your Social Distancing – At least 6 Feet apart!",
		"entities": [
			[
				"COVID-19",
				77,
				85,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Stay at home if at all possible.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "* Wash your hands often with soap and water for at least 20 seconds.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "If soap and water are not available, use an alcohol-based hand sanitizer.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "* Avoid touching your eyes, nose, and mouth with unwashed hands.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "* Avoid close contact with people who are sick.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "* Stay home when you are sick, or if you are a not an essential employee.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "* Cover your cough or sneeze with a tissue, then immediately throw the tissue in the trash.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "* Clean and disinfect frequently touched objects and surfaces.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "COVID-19 spreads through the air when an infected person coughs or sneezes.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"COVID-19",
				0,
				8,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Symptoms are thought to appear within two to 14 days after exposure and consist of fever, cough, runny nose, and difficulty breathing.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "For people with mild illness, individuals are asked to stay home, drink plenty of fluids, and get rest.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "For people with more severe symptoms, such as shortness of breath, individuals are advised to seek healthcare, using telemedicine where available.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Mail Attachment image001.jpg ']",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "[\"Hi Katrina, Ok to send out?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Katrina",
				5,
				12,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I am fine with it.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Thanks, Alisa >>>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Alisa",
				8,
				13,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Michael Keuler 7/15/2020 5:15 PM >>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Michael Keuler",
				0,
				14,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"7/15/2020",
				15,
				24,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": ">",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Hi Katrina and Alisa, I sent this to you before, but I wanted to get final approval to send.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Katrina",
				3,
				10,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Alisa",
				15,
				20,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Please see below the correspondence I have drafted to send to H2A farmworker employers.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "I tried to keep it short, sweet, and persuasive to increase testing among farmworkers.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "It will officially be sent from Dora Herrera, Foreign Labor Coordinator with the Oregon Employement Department to H2A employers in Marion County.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Dora Herrera",
				32,
				44,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Foreign Labor Coordinator",
				46,
				71,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"Oregon Employement Department",
				81,
				110,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Marion County",
				131,
				144,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "-----------------------------------------------------",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Marion County encourages agriculture employers with H2A farmworkers to sign up for an onsite testing event.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Marion County",
				0,
				13,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Resources are available for COVID-19 testing to come to your facility.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"COVID-19",
				28,
				36,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "This aligns with Marion County's goal of increased testing for vulnerable populations, such as Migrant Seasonal Farmworkers.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Marion County",
				17,
				30,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "To request COVID-19 testing for your farmworkers, please complete the attached COVID-19 Testing Event Request Form.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"COVID-19",
				11,
				19,
				"MED"
			],
			[
				"COVID-19",
				79,
				87,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In addition, please see Marion County's COVID-19 Farm Worksite Health Guidelines for more information to prevent the spread of COVID-19: •",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Marion County",
				24,
				37,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"COVID-19",
				40,
				48,
				"MED"
			],
			[
				"COVID-19",
				127,
				135,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "English: https://www.co.marion.or.us/HLT/COVID-19/Documents/2020MCCOVID- 19_FarmWorksiteHousingGuidelines_1.pdf • Spanish: https://www.co.marion.or.us/HLT/COVID-19/Documents/2020MCCOVID- 19_SpanishFarmWorksiteHousingGuidelines.pdf For more information, contact us at health_liaison@co.marion.or.us.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"English",
				0,
				7,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"https://www.co.marion.or.us/HLT/COVID-19/Documents/2020MCCOVID- 19_FarmWorksiteHousingGuidelines_1.pdf •",
				9,
				113,
				"URL"
			],
			[
				"Spanish",
				114,
				121,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"https://www.co.marion.or.us/HLT/COVID-19/Documents/2020MCCOVID- 19_SpanishFarmWorksiteHousingGuidelines.pdf",
				123,
				230,
				"URL"
			],
			[
				"health_liaison@co.marion.or.us",
				267,
				297,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Kind Regards, Michael Keuler Farm Needs Coordinator COVID-19 Liaison Team Marion County Health & Human Services 503-991-3595 >>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Michael Keuler",
				14,
				28,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Farm Needs Coordinator",
				29,
				51,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"COVID-19 Liaison Team",
				52,
				73,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Marion County Health & Human Services",
				74,
				111,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"503-991-3595",
				112,
				124,
				"PHONE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "> Katrina Rothenberger 7/7/2020 4:46 PM >>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Katrina Rothenberger",
				2,
				22,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"7/7/2020",
				23,
				31,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": ">",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Yeah, is the graphic available in Spanish too?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Spanish",
				34,
				41,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Katrina Rothenberger, MPH Marion County Health & Human Services Public Health Division Director Desk: 503-373-3787 Cell: 971-707-2437 P Please consider the environment before printing this email >>>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Katrina Rothenberger",
				0,
				20,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"MPH",
				22,
				25,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"Marion County Health & Human Services",
				26,
				63,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Public Health Division Director",
				64,
				95,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"503-373-3787",
				102,
				114,
				"PHONE"
			],
			[
				"971-707-2437",
				121,
				133,
				"PHONE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Michael Keuler 7/7/2020 12:13 PM >>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Michael Keuler",
				0,
				14,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"7/7/2020",
				15,
				23,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": ">",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Hi all, Just checking on this to see if this messaging is ready to send out Oregon Employment Department for H2A employers.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Oregon Employment Department",
				76,
				104,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Let me know if you have edits.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "I believe the testing request form is being reviewed by Kelly for any additional edits.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Kelly",
				56,
				61,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Kind Regards, Michael Keuler Farm Needs Coordinator COVID-19 Liaison Team Marion County Health & Human Services 503-991-3595 >>>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Michael Keuler",
				14,
				28,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Farm Needs Coordinator",
				29,
				51,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"COVID-19 Liaison Team",
				52,
				73,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Marion County Health & Human Services",
				74,
				111,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"503-991-3595",
				112,
				124,
				"PHONE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Michael Keuler 7/1/2020 4:03 PM >>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Michael Keuler",
				0,
				14,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"7/1/2020",
				15,
				23,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": ">",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Hi Katrina and Alisa, Please see below the correspondence I have drafted to send to H2A farmworker employers.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Katrina",
				3,
				10,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Alisa",
				15,
				20,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I tried to keep it short, sweet, and persuasive to increase testing among farmworkers.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "It will officially be sent from Dora Herrera, Foreign Labor Coordinator with the Oregon Employement Department to H2A employers in Marion County.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Dora Herrera",
				32,
				44,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Foreign Labor Coordinator",
				46,
				71,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"Oregon Employement Department",
				81,
				110,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Marion County",
				131,
				144,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "-----------------------------------------------------",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Marion County encourages agriculture employers with H2A farmworkers to sign up for an onsite testing event.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Marion County",
				0,
				13,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Resources are available for COVID-19 testing to come to your facility.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"COVID-19",
				28,
				36,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "This aligns with Marion County's goal of increased testing for vulnerable populations, such as H2A farmworkers.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Marion County",
				17,
				30,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "To request COVID-19 testing for your farmworkers, please complete the COVID-19 Testing Event Request Form [insert hyperlink].",
		"entities": [
			[
				"COVID-19",
				11,
				19,
				"MED"
			],
			[
				"COVID-19",
				70,
				78,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In addition, please see Marion County's COVID-19 Farm Worksite Health Guidelines for more information to prevent the spread of COVID-19: •",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Marion County",
				24,
				37,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"COVID-19",
				40,
				48,
				"MED"
			],
			[
				"COVID-19",
				127,
				135,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "English: https://www.co.marion.or.us/HLT/COVID-19/Documents/2020MCCOVID- •",
		"entities": [
			[
				"English",
				0,
				7,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"https://www.co.marion.or.us/HLT/COVID-19/Documents/2020MCCOVID- •",
				9,
				74,
				"URL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "English: https://www.co.marion.or.us/HLT/COVID-19/Documents/2020MCCOVID-",
		"entities": [
			[
				"English",
				0,
				7,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"https://www.co.marion.or.us/HLT/COVID-19/Documents/2020MCCOVID-",
				9,
				72,
				"URL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "19_FarmWorksiteHousingGuidelines_1.pdf • Spanish: https://www.co.marion.or.us/HLT/COVID-19/Documents/2020MCCOVID- 19_SpanishFarmWorksiteHousingGuidelines.pdf For more information, contact us at health_liaison@co.marion.or.us.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Spanish",
				41,
				48,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"https://www.co.marion.or.us/HLT/COVID-19/Documents/2020MCCOVID- 19_SpanishFarmWorksiteHousingGuidelines.pdf",
				50,
				157,
				"URL"
			],
			[
				"health_liaison@co.marion.or.us",
				194,
				224,
				"URL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Kind Regards, Michael Keuler Farm Needs Coordinator COVID-19 Liaison Team Marion County Health & Human Services 503-991-3595 >>>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Michael Keuler",
				14,
				28,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Farm Needs Coordinator",
				29,
				51,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"COVID-19 Liaison Team",
				52,
				73,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Marion County Health & Human Services",
				74,
				111,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"503-991-3595",
				112,
				124,
				"PHONE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Jenna Wyatt 7/1/2020 3:57 PM >>>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Jenna Wyatt",
				0,
				11,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"7/1/2020",
				12,
				20,
				"DATE"
			]
			
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Looks great!",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Just added a colon in the version below: Marion County encourages agriculture employers with H2A farmworkers to sign up for an onsite testing event.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Marion County",
				41,
				54,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Resources are available for COVID-19 testing to come to your facility.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"COVID-19",
				28,
				36,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "This aligns with Marion County's goal of increased testing for vulnerable populations, such as H2A farmworkers.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Marion County",
				17,
				30,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "To request COVID-19 testing for your farmworkers, please complete the COVID-19 Testing Event Request Form [insert hyperlink].",
		"entities": [
			[
				"COVID-19",
				11,
				19,
				"MED"
			],
			[
				"COVID-19",
				70,
				78,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In addition, please see Marion County's COVID-19 Farm Worksite Health Guidelines for more information to prevent the spread of COVID-19: •",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Marion County",
				24,
				37,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"COVID-19",
				40,
				48,
				"MED"
			],
			[
				"COVID-19",
				127,
				135,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "English: https://www.co.marion.or.us/HLT/COVID-19/Documents/2020MCCOVID- 19_FarmWorksiteHousingGuidelines_1.pdf • Spanish: https://www.co.marion.or.us/HLT/COVID-19/Documents/2020MCCOVID- 19_SpanishFarmWorksiteHousingGuidelines.pdf For more information, contact us at health_liaison@co.marion.or.us.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"English",
				0,
				7,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"https://www.co.marion.or.us/HLT/COVID-19/Documents/2020MCCOVID- 19_FarmWorksiteHousingGuidelines_1.pdf •",
				9,
				113,
				"URL"
			],
			[
				"Spanish",
				114,
				121,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"https://www.co.marion.or.us/HLT/COVID-19/Documents/2020MCCOVID- 19_SpanishFarmWorksiteHousingGuidelines.pdf",
				123,
				230,
				"URL"
			],
			[
				"health_liaison@co.marion.or.us",
				267,
				297,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": ">>>",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Michael Keuler 7/1/2020 3:54 PM >>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Michael Keuler",
				0,
				14,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"7/1/2020",
				15,
				23,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": ">",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Hi Jenna, Please see below the correspondence I have drafted to send to H2A farmworker employers and give me your feedback.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Jenna",
				3,
				8,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I tried to keep it short, sweet, and persuasive to increase testing among farmworkers.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Once I get your feedback, I will send to the Incident Commanders.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "It will officially be sent from Dora Herrera, Foreign Labor Coordinator with the Oregon Employement Department.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Dora Herrera",
				32,
				44,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Foreign Labor Coordinator",
				46,
				71,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"Oregon Employement Department",
				81,
				110,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "-----------------------------------------------------",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Marion County encourages agriculture employers with H2A farmworkers to sign up for an onsite testing event.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Marion County",
				0,
				13,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Resources are available for COVID-19 testing to come to your facility.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"COVID-19",
				28,
				36,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "This aligns with Marion County's goal of increased testing for vulnerable populations, such as H2A farmworkers.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Marion County",
				17,
				30,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "To request COVID-19 testing for your farmworkers, please complete the COVID-19 Testing Event Request Form [insert hyperlink].",
		"entities": [
			[
				"COVID-19",
				11,
				19,
				"MED"
			],
			[
				"COVID-19",
				70,
				78,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In addition, please see Marion County's COVID-19 Farm Worksite Health Guidelines for more information to prevent the spread of COVID-19.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Marion County",
				24,
				37,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"COVID-19",
				40,
				48,
				"MED"
			],
			[
				"COVID-19",
				127,
				135,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "•",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "English: https://www.co.marion.or.us/HLT/COVID-19/Documents/2020MCCOVID- 19_FarmWorksiteHousingGuidelines_1.pdf • Spanish: https://www.co.marion.or.us/HLT/COVID-19/Documents/2020MCCOVID- 19_SpanishFarmWorksiteHousingGuidelines.pdf For more information, contact us at health_liaison@co.marion.or.us.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"English",
				0,
				7,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"https://www.co.marion.or.us/HLT/COVID-19/Documents/2020MCCOVID- 19_FarmWorksiteHousingGuidelines_1.pdf •",
				9,
				113,
				"URL"
			],
			[
				"Spanish",
				114,
				121,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"https://www.co.marion.or.us/HLT/COVID-19/Documents/2020MCCOVID- 19_SpanishFarmWorksiteHousingGuidelines.pdf",
				123,
				230,
				"URL"
			],
			[
				"health_liaison@co.marion.or.us",
				267,
				297,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Kind Regards, Michael Keuler Farm Needs Coordinator COVID-19 Liaison Team Marion County Health & Human Services 503-991-3595 \"]",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Michael Keuler",
				14,
				28,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Farm Needs Coordinator",
				29,
				51,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"COVID-19 Liaison Team",
				52,
				73,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Marion County Health & Human Services",
				74,
				111,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"503-991-3595",
				112,
				124,
				"PHONE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "['Hi all The Epidemiology Sit Rep for today is attached.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Cherie Sent from my Verizon, Samsung Galaxy smartphone",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Cherie",
				0,
				6,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Hi all Attached please find today's Epidemiology Sit Rep.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "This report is for situational awareness and is not intended for public nor media.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Cherie Sent from my Verizon, Samsung Galaxy smartphone",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Cherie",
				0,
				6,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "--------",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Original message --------",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "From: \"Drenzek, Cherie\" <Cherie.Drenzek@dph.ga.gov>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Drenzek, Cherie",
				7,
				22,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Cherie.Drenzek@dph.ga.gov",
				25,
				50,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Date: 6/30/20 11:48 PM (GMT-05:00)",
		"entities": [
			[
				"6/30/20",
				6,
				13,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "To: \"Rustin, Chris\" <Chris.Rustin@dph.ga.gov>, \"Soetebier, Karl\" <Karl.Soetebier@dph.ga.gov>, \"Minarcine, Scott\" <Scott.Minarcine@dph.ga.gov>, \"Mindlin, Michele\" <Michele.Mindlin@dph.ga.gov>, \"Bacon, Rosalyn\" <Rosalyn.Bacon@dph.ga.gov>, \"Toomey, Kathleen\" <kathleen.toomey@dph.ga.gov>, \"Miller, Kristin\" <kristin.miller@dph.ga.gov>, \"Nydam, Nancy\" <Nancy.Nydam@dph.ga.gov>, \"Hough, Dawona\" <Dawona.Hough@dph.ga.gov>, \"Keheley, Ricky\" <Ricky.Keheley@dph.ga.gov>, \"Franko, Elizabeth\" <Elizabeth.Franko@dph.ga.gov>, \"Kroening, Sara\" <sara.kroening@dph.ga.gov>, \"Nadeau, Kelly\" <Kelly.Nadeau@dph.ga.gov>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rustin, Chris",
				5,
				18,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Chris.Rustin@dph.ga.gov",
				21,
				44,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Soetebier, Karl",
				48,
				63,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Karl.Soetebier@dph.ga.gov",
				66,
				91,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Minarcine, Scott",
				95,
				111,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Scott.Minarcine@dph.ga.gov",
				114,
				140,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Mindlin, Michele",
				144,
				160,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Michele.Mindlin@dph.ga.gov",
				163,
				189,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Bacon, Rosalyn",
				193,
				207,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Rosalyn.Bacon@dph.ga.gov",
				210,
				234,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Toomey, Kathleen",
				238,
				254,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"kathleen.toomey@dph.ga.gov",
				257,
				283,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Miller, Kristin",
				287,
				302,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"kristin.miller@dph.ga.gov",
				305,
				330,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Nydam, Nancy",
				334,
				346,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Nancy.Nydam@dph.ga.gov",
				349,
				371,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Hough, Dawona",
				375,
				388,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Dawona.Hough@dph.ga.gov",
				391,
				414,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Keheley, Ricky",
				418,
				432,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Ricky.Keheley@dph.ga.gov",
				435,
				459,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Franko, Elizabeth",
				463,
				480,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Elizabeth.Franko@dph.ga.gov",
				483,
				510,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Kroening, Sara",
				514,
				528,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"sara.kroening@dph.ga.gov",
				531,
				555,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Nadeau, Kelly",
				559,
				572,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Kelly.Nadeau@dph.ga.gov",
				576,
				599,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Cc: EOC Epidemiology <eocepidemiology@gets.onmicrosoft.com>, DPH-EPI <DPH-EPI@dph.ga.gov>, \"Loke, Ryan\" <ryan.loke@georgia.gov>, \"Noggle, Caylee\" <caylee.noggle@georgia.gov>, audrey.arona@gnrhealth.com, \"Memark, Janet\" <janet.memark@dph.ga.gov>, \"Voccio, Gary\" <Gary.Voccio@dph.ga.gov>, \"Taylor, Zachary\" <zachary.taylor@dph.ga.gov>, \"Logan, Pamela\" <pamela.logan@dph.ga.gov>, \"Goggans, Stephen\" <Stephen.Goggans@dph.ga.gov>, \"Townsend, Beverley\" <Beverley.Townsend@dph.ga.gov>, \"Ruis, Charles\" <charles.ruis@dph.ga.gov>, \"Grow, William\" <William.Grow@dph.ga.gov>, \"Obasanjo, Olugbenga\" <Olugbenga.Obasanjo@dph.ga.gov>, \"Ford, Sandra\" <Sandra.Ford@dph.ga.gov>, \"Paxton, Lynn\"",
		"entities": [
			[
				"EOC Epidemiology",
				4,
				20,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"eocepidemiology@gets.onmicrosoft.com",
				22,
				58,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"DPH-EPI@dph.ga.gov",
				70,
				88,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Loke, Ryan",
				92,
				102,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"ryan.loke@georgia.gov",
				105,
				126,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Noggle, Caylee",
				130,
				144,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"caylee.noggle@georgia.gov",
				147,
				172,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"audrey.arona@gnrhealth.com",
				175,
				201,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Memark, Janet",
				204,
				217,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"janet.memark@dph.ga.gov>",
				220,
				244,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Voccio, Gary",
				247,
				259,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Gary.Voccio@dph.ga.gov",
				262,
				284,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Taylor, Zachary",
				288,
				303,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"zachary.taylor@dph.ga.gov",
				306,
				331,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Logan, Pamela",
				335,
				348,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"pamela.logan@dph.ga.gov",
				351,
				374,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Goggans, Stephen",
				378,
				394,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Stephen.Goggans@dph.ga.gov",
				397,
				423,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Townsend, Beverley",
				427,
				445,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Beverley.Townsend@dph.ga.gov",
				448,
				476,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Ruis, Charles",
				480,
				493,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"charles.ruis@dph.ga.gov",
				496,
				519,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Grow, William",
				523,
				536,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"William.Grow@dph.ga.gov",
				539,
				562,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Obasanjo, Olugbenga",
				566,
				585,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Olugbenga.Obasanjo@dph.ga.gov",
				588,
				617,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Ford, Sandra",
				621,
				633,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Sandra.Ford@dph.ga.gov",
				636,
				658,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Paxton, Lynn",
				662,
				674,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "<Lynn.Paxton@fultoncountyga.gov>, \"Haynes, Reneé\" <renee.haynes@dph.ga.gov>, \"Davis, Lawton\" <Lawton.Davis@dph.ga.gov>, \"Craft, Thomas\" <thomas.craft@dph.ga.gov> Subject: Epidemiology Daily Sit Rep, 6/30/20 20",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Lynn.Paxton@fultoncountyga.gov",
				1,
				31,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Haynes, Reneé",
				35,
				48,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"renee.haynes@dph.ga.gov",
				51,
				74,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Davis, Lawton",
				78,
				91,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Lawton.Davis@dph.ga.gov",
				94,
				117,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"Craft, Thomas",
				121,
				134,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"thomas.craft@dph.ga.gov",
				137,
				160,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"6/30/20",
				199,
				206,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Hi all Attached please find today's Epidemiology SitRep.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "This document is for internal situational awareness only, not public nor media.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Take care, Cherie Cherie L. Drenzek DVM, MS State Epidemiologist Chief Science Officer Georgia Department of Public Health 2 Peachtree Street NW, Suite 14-420 Atlanta, GA 30303 404-657-2609 cherie.drenzek@dph.ga.gov 21 ']",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Cherie",
				11,
				17,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Cherie L. Drenzek",
				18,
				35,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"DVM, MS State Epidemiologist",
				36,
				64,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"Chief Science Officer",
				65,
				86,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"Georgia Department of Public Health",
				87,
				122,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"2 Peachtree Street NW, Suite 14-420",
				123,
				158,
				"ADDRESS"
			],
			[
				"Atlanta, GA",
				159,
				170,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"404-657-2609",
				177,
				189,
				"PHONE"
			],
			[
				"cherie.drenzek@dph.ga.gov",
				190,
				215,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "['Date: 4/9/20 12:55 PM (GMT-05:00)",
		"entities": [
			[
				"4/9/20",
				8,
				14,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "To: DBPD PIO < pio@dbpd.us >",
		"entities": [
			[
				"DBPD PIO",
				4,
				12,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"pio@dbpd.us",
				15,
				26,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": ">",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Subject: FOX & Friends First-",
		"entities": [
			[
				"FOX & Friends First",
				9,
				28,
				"EVENT"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "FOX News Channel Interview Request",
		"entities": [
			[
				"FOX News Channel",
				0,
				16,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Hello, This is Kyra with FOX News Channel’s national morning program FOX & Friends First.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Kyra",
				15,
				19,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"FOX News Channel",
				25,
				41,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"FOX & Friends First",
				69,
				88,
				"EVENT"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I am reaching out to see if a member from the Daytona Beach Police Department would be available tomorrow morning at 05:30 AM EST to join us for a LIVE interview via Skype.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Daytona Beach Police Department",
				46,
				77,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "We would like to discuss the talking drones that the department is using to enforce social distancing guidelines.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Please let me know if someone from the department would be available tomorrow morning at 5:30 AM EST to join us LIVE via Skype.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Thank you, Kyra Dersarkissian FOX & Friends First FOX News Channel 718-974-4976 Sent from Mail for Windows 10 This message and its attachments may contain legally privileged or confidential information.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Kyra Dersarkissian",
				11,
				29,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"FOX & Friends First",
				30,
				49,
				"EVENT"
			],
			[
				"FOX News Channel",
				50,
				66,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"718-974-4976",
				67,
				79,
				"PHONE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "It is intended solely for the named addressee.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Rather, you should permanently delete this message and its attachments and kindly notify the sender by reply e-mail.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Any content of this message and its attachments that does not relate to the official business of Fox News or Fox Business must not be taken to have been sent or endorsed by either of them.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Fox News",
				97,
				105,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Fox Business",
				109,
				121,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "No representation is made that this email or its attachments are without defect.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "_________________________________________________________________",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Under Florida law, e-mail addresses are public records.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Florida",
				6,
				13,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "If you do not want your e-mail address released in response to a public-records request, do not send electronic mail to this entity.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Instead, contact this office by phone or in writing.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "_________________________________________________________________",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Under Florida law, e-mail addresses are public records.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Florida",
				6,
				13,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "If you do not want your e-mail address released in response to a public-records request, do not send electronic mail to this entity.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Instead, contact this office by phone or in writing.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "_________________________________________________________________",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Under Florida law, e-mail addresses are public records.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Florida",
				6,
				13,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "If you do not want your e-mail address released in response to a public-records request, do not send electronic mail to this entity.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Instead, contact this office by phone or in writing.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "_________________________________________________________________",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Under Florida law, e-mail addresses are public records.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Florida",
				6,
				13,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "If you do not want your e-mail address released in response to a public-records request, do not send electronic mail to this entity.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Instead, contact this office by phone or in writing. ']",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "['CAUTION:",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "This email originated from outside your organization.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Exercise caution when opening attachments or clicking links, especially from unknown senders.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Yes they are both recent.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "We are sending out quarantine letters and if we have any pushback from provider I will let you know.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "I jumped ahead asking you so I can say \"I have already consulted with our health officer'' Will recommend testing again.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "From: Alex L. Brzezny <brzeznya@columbiabasinhospital.org>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Alex L. Brzezny",
				6,
				21,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"brzeznya@columbiabasinhospital.org",
				23,
				57,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Sent: Tuesday, April 28, 2020 3:43 PM",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Tuesday, April 28, 2020",
				6,
				29,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "To: Maria Vargas <mvargas@granthealth.org>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Maria Vargas",
				4,
				16,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"mvargas@granthealth.org",
				18,
				41,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Subject: RE: guidance Quarantine, no bones about it.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "The onle other method would be to test (and confirm positive) or to test twice with a negative result at least 24 hours apart.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Any symptoms: PROBABLE and ISOLATE.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Testing would have been an OK thing to do; quarantine very acceptable.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "No work!!",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "The exposure is recent, \"weeks ago\" has no way to be proven (and serology tests do not work for that purpose).",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "I am presuming that the \"confirmed\" was tested recently.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "AB From: Maria Vargas [mailto:mvargas@granthealth.org]",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Maria Vargas",
				9,
				21,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"mvargas@granthealth.org",
				30,
				53,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Sent: Tuesday, April 28, 2020 3:33 PM",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Tuesday, April 28, 2020",
				6,
				29,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "To: Alex L. Brzezny Subject: guidance",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Alex L. Brzezny",
				4,
				19,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Quick question, We have a confirmed who was exposed via her father in law who is also confirmed .. her husband went in to be tested today in Quincy and explained to the Dr he had similar symptoms weeks ago, so Dr opted to not test and gave him a release to return to work.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Quincy",
				141,
				147,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Dr",
				169,
				171,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"Dr",
				210,
				212,
				"TITLE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "We do NOT know he had COVID and he has now been exposed to 2 confirmed cases.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"COVID",
				22,
				27,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "My thought is we still quarantine.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "He has a Dr's note stating otherwise is why I am wanting your written guidance in case he refuses Maria Vargas Community Public Health Manager 1038 W Ivy St Moses Lake WA 98837",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Maria Vargas",
				98,
				110,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Community Public Health Manager",
				111,
				142,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"1038 W Ivy St",
				143,
				156,
				"ADDRESS"
			],
			[
				"Moses Lake WA",
				157,
				170,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "mvargas@,granthealth.org 509-766-7960 ext 19 509-766-6519 1 YGCHD tHtANt' COUNTY HEALTH 01~-rrucr 0 ,,,.,_bllcHt~",
		"entities": [
			[
				"mvargas@,granthealth.org",
				0,
				24,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"509-766-7960",
				25,
				37,
				"PHONE"
			],
			[
				"509-766-6519",
				45,
				57,
				"PHONE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "th Always working for a safer and healthier Grant County CONFIDENTIALITY NOTICE:",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Grant County",
				44,
				56,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "copies of the original message.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "This e-mail may be considered subject to the Public Records Act and as such may be disclosed by Grant County Health District to a third-party requester.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Public Records Act",
				45,
				63,
				"LAW"
			],
			[
				"Grant County Health District",
				96,
				124,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "2 ']",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "['Good afternoon, Attached is the case count for today!",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Stay safe and well!",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Debra Debra Bradley, MSW Director of Health City of St. Joseph Health Department Patee Market Health Center 904 S. Tenth Street St. Joseph, MO 64503 (816) 271-4636 dbradley@stjoemo.org ']",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Debra",
				0,
				5,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Debra Bradley",
				6,
				19,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"MSW Director of Health",
				21,
				43,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"City of St. Joseph Health Department",
				44,
				80,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Patee Market Health Center 904 S. Tenth Street",
				81,
				127,
				"ADDRESS"
			],
			[
				"St. Joseph, MO",
				128,
				142,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"(816) 271-4636",
				149,
				163,
				"PHONE"
			],
			[
				"dbradley@stjoemo.org",
				164,
				184,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "['Hi everyone, This week’s internal Policy Talking Points are a day early.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Please note that a few of the questions have crossed out information that has updated information relating to it.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "I tried to reference the updated information but please check the date of the specific question/answer in case the guidance has been updated since that question was originally asked.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "http://inside.cbs.state.or.us/osha/policy/covid19.html Hope you all enjoy your long weekend!",
		"entities": [
			[
				"http://inside.cbs.state.or.us/osha/policy/covid19.html",
				0,
				54,
				"URL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Kate Ryan ALH/RCD/Policy Support Staff, OR-OSHA Portland Field Office 16760 SW Upper Boones Ferry Rd, Suite 200 Tigard, Oregon 97224",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Kate Ryan",
				0,
				9,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"ALH/RCD/Policy Support Staff",
				10,
				38,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"OR-OSHA Portland Field Office",
				40,
				69,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"16760 SW Upper Boones Ferry Rd, Suite 200",
				70,
				111,
				"ADDRESS"
			],
			[
				"Tigard, Oregon",
				112,
				126,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Ph: 971-673-2918 Fax: 971-673-2901 ']",
		"entities": [
			[
				"971-673-2918",
				4,
				16,
				"PHONE"
			],
			[
				"971-673-2901",
				22,
				34,
				"PHONE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "[\"Hello All I am forwarding the dates for the upcoming COVID-19 vaccine clinics that will be held in Township Hall.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"COVID-19",
				55,
				63,
				"MED"
			],
			[
				"Township Hall",
				102,
				115,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I am sharing this information for FYI only (not for wide spread distribution).",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "These clinics are still reserved for high priority groups.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "We will be in contact those who are eligible based on their priority status.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "We are working with ERand our other partners on coordinating the invitation and registration for participants.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "I have attached our recent Vaccine Minute (to be released today) that describes the priority groups more clearly.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Richard From: Katie Hickel <khickel@co.carver.mn.us>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Richard",
				0,
				7,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Katie Hickel",
				14,
				26,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"khickel@co.carver.mn.us",
				28,
				51,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Sent: Wednesday, January 06, 202111:42 AM",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Wednesday, January 06, 202111:42",
				6,
				38,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "To: Richard Scott <rscott@co.carver.mn.us>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Richard Scott",
				4,
				17,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"rscott@co.carver.mn.us",
				19,
				41,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Cc: Samantha Downs <sdowns@co.carver.mn.us>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Samantha Downs",
				4,
				18,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"sdowns@co.carver.mn.us",
				20,
				42,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Subject:",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Upcoming clinic dates Hi Richard, Below are the dates and times we have confirmed for Homeland Health to provide clinics through February.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Richard",
				25,
				32,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Homeland Health",
				86,
				101,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"February",
				129,
				137,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "We have not reached out to the groups yet who are going to be included in these clinics and we are still working this out.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Wanted to provide for your awareness, and anyone you think should be forwarded to (knowing it's not for dissemination and we will be in contact with who will be asked to sign up).",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "We are planning to use Township Hall for all listed as well.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Township Hall",
				102,
				115,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "First Dose Second Dose Date Time Date Time 30-Dec 4-8PM 28-Jan 4-8 PM 5-Jan 4-8 PM 2-Feb 4-8PM 12-Jan 4-8 PM 9-Feb 4-8PM 14-Jan 9AM-1PM 11-Feb 9AM-1PM 19-Jan 1-5 PM 16-Feb 1-5 PM 21-Jan 9AM-1PM 18-Feb 9AM-1PM 26-Jan 1-5 PM 23-Feb 1-5 PM 28-Jan 11-3 PM 25-Feb 9AM-1PM Thanks! 1 \"]",
		"entities": [
			[
				"30-Dec",
				43,
				49,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"28-Jan",
				56,
				62,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"5-Jan",
				70,
				75,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"2-Feb",
				83,
				88,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"12-Jan",
				95,
				101,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"9-Feb",
				109,
				114,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"14-Jan",
				121,
				127,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"11-Feb",
				136,
				142,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"19-Jan",
				151,
				157,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"16-Feb",
				165,
				171,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"21-Jan",
				179,
				185,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"18-Feb",
				194,
				200,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"26-Jan",
				209,
				215,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"23-Feb",
				223,
				229,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"28-Jan",
				237,
				243,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"25-Feb",
				252,
				258,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "[' \‌ JOIN US FOR A CUP!",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "\﻿Wednesday, September 30, 2020 8:30 a.m. -",
		"entities": [
			[
				"\﻿Wednesday, September 30, 2020",
				0,
				35,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Networking 9:00 a.m. - Cup of Joe Presenters Restoration Natatorium - 117 Francis Street (Parking is available in lot across street) Cup of Joe, inspired by the 1 Million Cups model in Kansas City, is a simple way to engage entrepreneurs in communities around the world.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Cup of Joe",
				23,
				33,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"117 Francis Street",
				70,
				88,
				"ADDRESS"
			],
			[
				"Cup of Joe",
				133,
				143,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"1 Million Cups",
				161,
				175,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Kansas City",
				185,
				196,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Each week, Cup of Joe offers local businesses an opportunity to share their experience with a diverse audience of mentors, advisers, and fellow business owners.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Cup of Joe",
				11,
				21,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "___________________________________________________________",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "MELISSA CHESTNUT",
		"entities": [
			[
				"MELISSA CHESTNUT",
				0,
				16,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Naturally You Makeup Artistry Melissa Chesnut began her entrepreneurial journey while in college at the age of 19 with a beauty and skin care company.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Naturally You Makeup Artistry",
				0,
				29,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Melissa Chesnut",
				30,
				45,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "It was a facial cleanser that finally worked on her acne that set her on a path of building a successful business over the next 10 years.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "After the birth of her second child and paying attention to retail trends, Melissa leaned in to what her customers were asking for: makeup application services for their special occasions.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Melissa",
				75,
				82,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "She went back to school for her certification and in the spring of 2016 launched her new business venture, Naturally You Makeup Artistry.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"2016",
				67,
				71,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"Naturally You Makeup Artistry",
				107,
				136,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In the last four years, Melissa has helped more than 200 brides achieve timeless and natural beauty on their wedding day, built a team of seven independent contractors and opened a brick and mortar makeup studio in her tiny hometown of Dearborn, Missouri.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Melissa",
				24,
				31,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Dearborn, Missouri",
				236,
				254,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "While focusing on luxurious skin prep, natural aesthetics and impeccable customer experience, Melissa has been recognized by the wedding industry’s top affiliations, such as The Knot, three years in a row and recently was a nominee for Top Three Makeup Artists in the Kansas City area.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Melissa",
				94,
				101,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"The Knot",
				174,
				182,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Kansas City",
				268,
				279,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Melissa works full-time in marketing and communications at LifeLine Foods in St. Joseph and lives on a small farm with her husband, Todd, and two small children in Dearborn, Missouri.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Melissa",
				0,
				7,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"LifeLine Foods",
				59,
				73,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"St. Joseph",
				77,
				87,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Todd",
				132,
				136,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Dearborn, Missouri",
				164,
				182,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "facebook.com JOHN ELLIS \﻿College Coupons College Coupons has been helping businesses reach students, faculty and communities since 1974 through our print coupon books.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"facebook.com",
				0,
				12,
				"URL"
			],
			[
				"JOHN ELLIS",
				13,
				23,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"College Coupons",
				30,
				45,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"College Coupons",
				46,
				61,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"1974",
				136,
				140,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The 2 3/4\" X 4 1/4\" coupon books are the perfect size, easily fitting into pockets, purses, and backpacks.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "College Coupons print and distribute coupon books twice a year, one in August for the fall semester and one in January for the spring semester.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"College Coupons",
				0,
				15,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"August",
				71,
				77,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"January",
				111,
				118,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In 2019 College Coupons developed and added an app to complement the print product.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"2019",
				3,
				7,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"College Coupons",
				8,
				23,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "This app allows businesses to monitor and handle their own marketing needs, adjusting and creating new ads on the fly.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "John Ellis began with College Coupons in 1994 as a regional sales rep.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"John Ellis",
				0,
				10,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"College Coupons",
				22,
				37,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"1994",
				41,
				45,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In 2010 he became sales manager and in 2018 he purchased College Coupons.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"2010",
				3,
				7,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"2018",
				39,
				43,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"College Coupons",
				57,
				72,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "John also operated a mobile DJ company for 42 years.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"John",
				0,
				4,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He lives in Olathe, Kansas with his wife and three spoiled pets.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Olathe, Kansas",
				12,
				26,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "college-coupons.com September Coffee Sponsor: Pronto Cafe \﻿ Visit the Cup of Joe Website Can't make it to Cup of Joe?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"college-coupons.com",
				0,
				19,
				"URL"
			],
			[
				"Pronto Cafe",
				46,
				57,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Cup of Joe",
				75,
				85,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Cup of Joe",
				111,
				121,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Join us on Facebook Live!",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "\﻿ Presenters prepare a 10-minute educational presentation and engage in 15 minutes of feedback and questions.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Entrepreneurs gain insightful feedback while connecting with a supportive community that cares about their progress.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "The audience learns a great deal from the presentations.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Whether this is through passively listening or deeply engaging with the entrepreneurs, there is much to learn every week from these dynamic and diverse communities.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Join our local group to discover what the buzz is about.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Supporters gather around 8:30am for coffee and conversation.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "The program begins at 9:00am.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "This is a casual gathering for entrepreneurs, by entrepreneurs.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Please join us to share ideas--over a cup of joe!",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "STAY CONNECTED \‌",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "\‌",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "St. Joseph Chamber of Commerce | 3003",
		"entities": [
			[
				"St. Joseph Chamber of Commerce",
				0,
				30,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Frederick Avenue, St. Joseph, MO 64506 Unsubscribe dbradley@stjoemo.org Update Profile | About our service provider Sent by redmond@saintjoseph.com powered by Try email marketing for free today!",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Frederick Avenue",
				0,
				16,
				"ADDRESS"
			],
			[
				"St. Joseph, MO",
				18,
				32,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"dbradley@stjoemo.org",
				51,
				71,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"redmond@saintjoseph.com",
				124,
				147,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "EXTERNAL EMAIL: Do not click on any links or open any attachments unless you are expecting the email and/or know the content is safe.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "If in doubt, delete the email. ']",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "['Importance: High Media Partners: Please see attached advisory as a follow‐up from the press conference earlier this afternoon.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Note:",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "This release contains the JOINT EXECUTIVE ORDER, as well as supplemental information, including an FAQ’s that we need your help in disseminating to the public.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"JOINT EXECUTIVE ORDER",
				26,
				47,
				"LAW"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "You can also access this advisory and supplemental information at the following link: https://bit.ly/3d7nQoe",
		"entities": [
			[
				"https://bit.ly/3d7nQoe",
				86,
				108,
				"URL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Thanks for your support!",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Wendy Howell Public Information Officer Dougherty County Board of Commissioners/Administration Phone: 229.302.3006",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Wendy Howell",
				0,
				12,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Public Information Officer",
				13,
				39,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"Dougherty County Board of Commissioners/Administration",
				40,
				94,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"229.302.3006",
				102,
				114,
				"PHONE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Mobile: 229.854.0006 222 Pine Avenue, Suite 540, Albany, Georgia 31701 Web: Dougherty.ga.us Email: whowell@dougherty.ga.us PUBLIC RECORDS NOTICE:",
		"entities": [
			[
				"229.854.0006",
				8,
				20,
				"PHONE"
			],
			[
				"222 Pine Avenue, Suite 540",
				21,
				47,
				"ADDRESS"
			],
			[
				"Albany, Georgia",
				49,
				64,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Dougherty.ga.us",
				76,
				91,
				"URL"
			],
			[
				"whowell@dougherty.ga.us",
				99,
				122,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Georgia has a very broad public records law.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Georgia",
				0,
				7,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Most written communications to or from City and County officials regarding City and County business are public records available to the public and media upon request.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"City",
				39,
				43,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"County",
				48,
				54,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"City",
				75,
				79,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"County",
				84,
				90,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Your email communications may be subject to public disclosure.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "40 MEDIA ADVISORY FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE March 19, 2020 MEDIA CONTACT:",
		"entities": [
			[
				"March 19, 2020",
				40,
				54,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "WENDY HOWELL DOUGHERTY COUNTY PUBLIC INFORMATION OFFICER 229.854.0006 whowell@dougherty.ga.us DOUGHERTY COUNTY, GEORGIA –",
		"entities": [
			[
				"WENDY HOWELL",
				0,
				12,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"DOUGHERTY COUNTY PUBLIC INFORMATION OFFICER",
				13,
				56,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"229.854.0006",
				57,
				69,
				"PHONE"
			],
			[
				"whowell@dougherty.ga.us",
				70,
				93,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"DOUGHERTY COUNTY",
				94,
				110,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"GEORGIA",
				112,
				119,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Today, Mayor Bo Dorough, City of Albany, and Chairman Christopher S. Cohilas, Dougherty County Board of Commissioners, issued a Joint Executive Order, in the wake of the Coronavirus (COVID-19) Pandemic and under the Authority of the Georgia Emer- gency Management Act of 1981.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Mayor Bo Dorough",
				7,
				23,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"City of Albany",
				25,
				39,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Chairman",
				45,
				53,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"Christopher S. Cohilas",
				54,
				76,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Dougherty County Board of Commissioners",
				78,
				117,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Joint Executive Order",
				128,
				149,
				"LAW"
			],
			[
				"Coronavirus",
				170,
				181,
				"MED"
			],
			[
				"COVID-19",
				183,
				191,
				"MED"
			],
			[
				"Georgia Emer- gency Management Act of 1981",
				233,
				275,
				"LAW"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The order is in effect for seven (7) days beginning 8 a.m. on March 20, 2020.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"March 20, 2020",
				62,
				76,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Center for Disease Control (CDC) has recommended that all events with more than 50 people be cancelled to curb the spread of COVID-19 and the World Health Organization (WHO) has classi- fied the coronavirus as a pandemic.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Center for Disease Control",
				4,
				30,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"CDC",
				32,
				35,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"COVID-19",
				129,
				137,
				"MED"
			],
			[
				"World Health Organization",
				146,
				171,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"WHO",
				173,
				176,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"coronavirus",
				199,
				210,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In Dougherty County, Phoebe Putney Memorial Hospital has re- ported four deaths connected to COVID-19.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Dougherty County",
				3,
				19,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Phoebe Putney Memorial Hospital",
				21,
				52,
				"FAC"
			],
			[
				"COVID-19",
				93,
				101,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Large gatherings of individuals pose a risk of the spread of COVID-19 and the CDC recommends limiting large gatherings to contain the spread.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"COVID-19",
				61,
				69,
				"MED"
			],
			[
				"CDC",
				78,
				81,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "For the full Joint Executive Order, visit Dougherty.ga.us and the News and Events/Public Notices section.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Joint Executive Order",
				13,
				34,
				"LAW"
			],
			[
				"Dougherty.ga.us",
				42,
				57,
				"URL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "### About Dougherty County, Georgia Located in the heart of Southwest Georgia, Dougherty County is home to internationally recognized quail plantations, a university and technical institute.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Dougherty County",
				10,
				26,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Georgia",
				28,
				35,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Southwest Georgia",
				60,
				77,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Dougherty County",
				79,
				95,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Our mission is to improve the quality of life for all citizens by being accessible and good stewards of our resources, delivering cost-effective, responsive services with integ- rity, fairness, and friendliness.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "For more information, visit Dougherty.ga.us.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Dougherty.ga.us",
				28,
				43,
				"URL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Or, find us on Facebook at face- book.com/Dougherty.ga.us or on Twitter @1doughertycoga.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"face- book.com/Dougherty.ga.us",
				27,
				57,
				"URL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "City of Albany/Dougherty County Declaration of Disaster & Public Health Emergency FAQs When does the order go into effect?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"City of Albany",
				0,
				14,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Dougherty County",
				15,
				31,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The order goes into effect at 8 a.m. on March 20, 2020.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"March 20, 2020",
				40,
				54,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "How long does the order last?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "The order is in place for seven days (March 25, 2020).",
		"entities": [
			[
				"March 25, 2020",
				38,
				52,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "It may be amended at any time should circumstances dictate.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Will there be enforcement and how?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "A violation of the order is a misdemeanor.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "If you have a complaint about businesses operating outside of the order or large community gatherings during the effective period, please notify the Emergency Operations Center at (229) 302-1900.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Emergency Operations Center",
				149,
				176,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"(229) 302-1900",
				180,
				194,
				"PHONE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The City may use other enforcement tools as allowed by law.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"The City",
				0,
				8,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "To report a potential violation of the order, Should my business close during this time?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "The order does not require all private businesses to temporarily close, but those that fall under the categories listed in the declaration of Public Health Emergency are expected to follow the order.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "If you are unsure if your business falls under the classifications listed in the order, call 311.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Are daycares required to close under this order?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "No.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Childcare facilities are not included in this order, but should maintain social distancing.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Can production facilities and distribution centers stay open?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Yes, production facilities and distribution centers may remain open so long as social distancing guidelines of six feet are followed.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Will grocery stores remain open?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Yes, grocery stores may remain open so long as persons are not within six feet of one another for extended periods of time.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Will retailers and shopping centers have to close?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Malls and shopping centers and other retail establishments are not included in the definition of community gathering so long as persons are not within six feet of one another for extended periods of time.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Does my church have to cancel in-person service?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Possibly.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "A community gathering is defined as any indoor or outdoor event or convening that brings or is likely to bring together 10 or more persons at the same time in a single room or enclosed space including auditoriums, meeting halls and event centers.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Please see definitions in section 7 of the order.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Depending upon the size of your congregation, your in-person services may violate the order.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Can we still hold funeral services?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Yes, as long as indoor attendance is limited to less than 10 persons per the community gathering definition in sections 4 and 6 of the order.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Outdoor graveside services would not be subject to the community gathering prohibition as long as they are not in fenced or otherwise enclosed spaces and attendees are able to maintain 6-foot social distancing measures.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Can we still hold weddings, birthday parties, book clubs, baby showers, private gatherings in a home?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "At a business?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Possibly.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Public or private community gatherings that bring together or are likely to bring together 10 or more people at the same time are prohibited.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Please see Sections 4 and 6 of the Order for the specific definitions or requirements.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "The Mayor and Dougherty County Public Health District strongly recommend canceling, rescheduling or not attending events with more than 10 persons.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"The Mayor",
				0,
				9,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Dougherty County Public Health District",
				14,
				53,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "If my restaurant/bar/gym limits access to 10 members or less at a time, does it have to close?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Restaurants are prohibited from providing service in their dining rooms.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Restaurants may continue to provide drive through, pick up/curbside and delivery services.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Bars and other similar establishments are closed.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Gyms and other similar businesses fall under the temporary closure order.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "My hotel has a restaurant and/or continental breakfast buffet.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Should that be closed?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Yes.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Food should be delivered to rooms or picked up to-go during the effective period of the order.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Are beauty and barber shops allowed to stay open?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Yes.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Social distancing guidelines of six feet are required.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Can dance studios continue classes that are limited to 10 students or less at one time?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "No.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "A dance studio falls under the category of Indoor Recreational Facility and is subject to the requirements of the order.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Can employees of businesses not affected by the order still be allowed to come in to work, but remain closed to the public?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Yes, as long as community gathering situations are not created as defined in the order (sections 5 and 7).",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "The recommended six-foot social distance is required.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Can we still maintain our dentist, eye doctor, and medical doctor appointments?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Yes.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Hospitals and medical facilities are not included in the Community Gathering definition so long as persons are generally not within 6 feet of one another for extended periods.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Please see the social distancing recommendations included with the order or visit https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/downloads/community-mitigation-strategy.pdf Will the City work with people who cannot pay their utility bill due to being out of work as a result of COVID-19?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/downloads/community-mitigation-strategy.pdf",
				82,
				167,
				"URL"
			],
			[
				"City",
				177,
				181,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"COVID-19",
				273,
				281,
				"MED"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "If you are unable to pay your bill, please contact the the Albany Utility Board at (229) 883-8330.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Albany Utility Board",
				59,
				79,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"(229) 883-8330",
				83,
				97,
				"PHONE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "As always, utilities staff is prepared to work with you on a payment plan for your bill.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Is public transit still running a full schedule?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Yes.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Transit services are not prohibited under the order and are continuing as normal, with enhanced measures for cleaning.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Six foot distancing still required.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Is the animal shelter remaining open?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Animal shelter operations are continuing as normal.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Are parks and playgrounds still open?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Outdoor recreational facilities such as parks and playgrounds remain open so long as there are not gatherings of 10 or more people.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Parks and Recreation has implemented an extensive cleaning schedule for all playground equipment, tables, benches and other outdoor facilities. ']",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Parks and Recreation",
				0,
				20,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "[\"attn: County EMs During some of the regional briefings that I've been doing this week, I reported that Region VII is sending questions about this event up to FEMA Headquarters for clarification.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"FEMA",
				160,
				164,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "FEMA Region VII has been sending us a compilation of those questions every couple of weeks.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"FEMA",
				0,
				4,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Some of the EM's I've talked to expressed an interest in seeing those questions, so I'm sending you the latest list of questions and answers.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "I'm also attaching a list of all of the applicants who have already entered a Request for Public Assistance for your use.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "The remaining four documents are ones that I think you will be able to refer to often in the days ahead and while you may have received them before, I'm sending them again here.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "It is instructions you can give to potential applicants, a list of eligible emergency protective measures, updated information about procurement rules during this event and a blank copy of the RPA form.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Additionally, an Applicant Briefing slide deck and other forms and fact sheets have been posted on the KDEM PA website at http://www.kansastag.gov/KDEM.asp?PageID=166 Please feel free to refer folks to this page for information about applying for FEMA PA.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"KDEM",
				103,
				107,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"http://www.kansastag.gov/KDEM.asp?PageID=166",
				122,
				166,
				"URL"
			],
			[
				"FEMA",
				247,
				251,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Please do not hesitate to contact me if you have other questions or concerns.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "And, again, thank you all for your help.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Christina J. Flyntz Public Assistance Officer Kansas Division of Emergency Management 2800 SW Topeka Blvd Topeka, KS 66611 christina.j.flyntz.nfg@mail.mil 785-646-2523 3 \"]",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Christina J. Flyntz",
				0,
				19,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Public Assistance Officer",
				20,
				45,
				"TITLE`"
			],
			[
				"Kansas Division of Emergency Management",
				46,
				85,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"2800 SW Topeka Blvd",
				86,
				105,
				"ADDRESS"
			],
			[
				"Topeka, KS",
				106,
				116,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"christina.j.flyntz.nfg@mail.mil",
				123,
				154,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"785-646-2523",
				155,
				167,
				"PHONE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "['Sent: Thursday, January 23, 2020 9:18 AM",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Thursday, January 23, 2020",
				8,
				34,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "To: Figliola, Mike <Mike.Figliola@turner.com>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Figliola, Mike",
				4,
				18,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Mike.Figliola@turner.com",
				20,
				44,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Subject: RE: Request from CNN's New Day Checking now for all times between 6- 9 will let you know soonest Patricia L. Conrad Public Health Analyst and Special Assistant to the Director National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases",
		"entities": [
			[
				"CNN",
				26,
				29,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"New Day",
				32,
				39,
				"EVENT"
			],
			[
				"Patricia L. Conrad",
				106,
				124,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Public Health Analyst and Special Assistant to the Director",
				125,
				184,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases",
				185,
				238,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The National Institutes of Health 31 Center Drive, MSC 2520 - Room 7A03 Bethesda, Maryland 20892 301-496-4409 fax Disclaimer:",
		"entities": [
			[
				"National Institutes of Health",
				4,
				33,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"31 Center Drive, MSC 2520 - Room 7A03",
				34,
				71,
				"ADDRESS"
			],
			[
				"Bethesda, Maryland",
				72,
				90,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"301-496-4409",
				97,
				109,
				"PHONE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The information in this e-mail and any of its attachments is confidential and may contain sensitive information.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "It should not be used by anyone who is not the original intended recipient.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "If you have received this e-mail in error please inform the sender and delete it from your mailbox or any other storage devices.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID) shall not accept liability for any statement made that are sender's gwn and not expressly made on behalf of the NIAID by one of its representatives.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases",
				0,
				53,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"NIAID",
				55,
				60,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"NIAID",
				174,
				179,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "From: Figliola, Mike <Mlike.Figlicla@turner.com>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Figliola, Mike",
				6,
				20,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Mlike.Figlicla@turner.com",
				22,
				47,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Sent: Thursday, January 23, 2020 9:10 AM",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Thursday, January 23, 2020",
				6,
				32,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "To: Conrad, Patricia (NIH/NIAID)",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Conrad, Patricia",
				4,
				20,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"NIH/NIAID",
				22,
				31,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "[E] Subject: RE: Request from CNN's New Day Hi again Could be back half of 7Zam",
		"entities": [
			[
				"CNN",
				30,
				33,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"New Day",
				36,
				43,
				"EVENT"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "but if this gets much worse we may play it higher in the hour —is there any time that doesn’t work?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Mike Figliola Editorial Producer CNN's New Day NIH-001840 mike figliola@turner.com <image001.jpg> CONFIDENTIALITY NOTICE:",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Mike Figliola",
				0,
				13,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Editorial Producer",
				14,
				32,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"CNN",
				33,
				36,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"New Day",
				39,
				46,
				"EVENT"
			],
			[
				"mike figliola@turner.com",
				58,
				82,
				"EMAIL"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "This e-mail transmission, and any documents, files or previous e-mail messages attached to it, may contain confidential information that is legally privileged.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "If you have received this transmission in error, please immediately notify us by reply e-mail at mike figliola@turner.com or by telephone at (917) 670-9410, and destroy the original transmission and its attachments without reading them or saving them to disk.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"mike figliola@turner.com",
				97,
				121,
				"EMAIL"
			],
			[
				"(917) 670-9410",
				141,
				155,
				"PHONE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Thank you.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Sent: Thursay, January 23, 2020 8:57 AM To: Figliola, Mike <Mike Figliola@turner.com>",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Thursay, January 23, 2020",
				6,
				31,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"Figliola, Mike",
				44,
				58,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Mike Figliola@turner.com",
				60,
				84,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Subject: FW: Request from CNN's New Day",
		"entities": [
			[
				"CNN",
				26,
				29,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"New Day",
				32,
				39,
				"EVENT"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Hi Mike — we can make this happen.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Mike",
				3,
				7,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The 7 am hour is best for us but will get back to you.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "do you have an idea of the hit time?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "need to make sure our nih studio is available.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"nih",
				22,
				25,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
