[
	{
		"content": "['[Extract] secret No. 1393",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Sir: ...",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Unfortunately, however, as I have pointed out in reports to the Department during the last year, the Colombians frankly regard the conflict between Argentina and the American family of nations as a conflict between Washington and Buenos Aires.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Department",
				64,
				74,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Colombians",
				101,
				111,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Argentina",
				148,
				157,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"American",
				166,
				174,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Washington",
				215,
				225,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Buenos Aires",
				230,
				242,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Colombian super-sensitiveness with regard to intervention in any form inclines the Colombians to view the energetic policies pursued by the American Government with some suspicion and with very little sympathy.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Colombian",
				0,
				9,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Colombians",
				83,
				93,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"American Government",
				140,
				159,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The only constructive thought in respect of the Argentine problem which I have recently encountered came from President Lleras (vide my telegram No. 84, of January 24, 1946, 2 pm) in which he expressed the hope that if it was true that the United States possessed documentary evidence establishing Argentine guilt in respect of the Axis, \"we can then do something\".",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Argentine",
				48,
				57,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"President Lleras",
				110,
				126,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"January 24, 1946",
				156,
				172,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"United States",
				240,
				253,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Argentine",
				298,
				307,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Axis",
				332,
				336,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "By this, I believe, he had in mind a collective condemnation of Argentina. . . . . . . . . . . . . . .",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Argentina",
				64,
				73,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Respectfully yours, John C. Wiley']",
		"entities": [
			[
				"John C. Wiley",
				20,
				33,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "['PARTICIPANTS Prime Minister Edgar Faure Secretary of State Laforest M. Massigli M. Berard Ambassador Dillon D.M. Bane REFERENCE Embassy's telegram 4740 (Saigon 687) April 29",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Prime Minister Edgar Faure",
				15,
				41,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Secretary of State Laforest",
				42,
				69,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"M. Massigli",
				70,
				81,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"M. Berard",
				82,
				91,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Ambassador Dillon",
				92,
				109,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"D.M. Bane",
				110,
				119,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Embassy",
				130,
				137,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Saigon 687",
				155,
				165,
				"WORK_OF_ART"
			],
			[
				"April 29",
				167,
				175,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Ambassador opened the meeting by outlining in detail those points on which the United States Government would like clarification from the French Government prior to proceeding with the consideration of questions of procedure and personalities posed in the French Aide-Memoire of April 17, as well as those assurances of wholehearted support for the future Vietnamese Government which the United States Government feels must be received from the French Government and Bao Dai in order to justify the continued support of the United States Government in South Vietnam.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Ambassador",
				4,
				14,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"United States Government",
				83,
				107,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"French Government",
				142,
				159,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"French",
				260,
				266,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"April 17",
				283,
				291,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"Vietnamese Government",
				360,
				381,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United States Government",
				392,
				416,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"French Government",
				449,
				466,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Bao Dai",
				471,
				478,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"United States Government",
				528,
				552,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"South Vietnam",
				556,
				569,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "A detailed account of the Ambassador's exposition, which was read and approved by the French, was contained in the reference telegram as well as the Ambassador's comments to Prime Minister Edgar Faure regarding United States concern over the continuation of Jean Sainteny in the role of French Delegate General to North Vietnam.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Ambassador",
				26,
				36,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"French",
				86,
				92,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Ambassador",
				149,
				159,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Prime Minister Edgar Faure",
				174,
				200,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"United States",
				211,
				224,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Jean Sainteny",
				258,
				271,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"French",
				287,
				293,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Delegate General to North Vietnam",
				294,
				327,
				"TITLE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The following summary of the French reaction was read and approved by the French and is set forth here since it is in greater detail than the account given in the reference telegram.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"French",
				29,
				35,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"French",
				74,
				80,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Prime Minister Edgar Faure began by saying that he must tell us in all seriousness that the French Government felt constrained to review its policy vis-a-vis Vietnam in the light of recent developments, and to confirm that the French Government had no intention of intervening unilaterally with Bao Dai at this juncture.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Prime Minister Edgar Faure",
				0,
				26,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"French Government",
				92,
				109,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Vietnam",
				158,
				165,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"French Government",
				227,
				244,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Bao Dai",
				295,
				302,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He reminded us that for the past six months the French Government had made clear its conviction to the United States Government that the Diem Government did not possess the capability of effecting a stabilization of the political situation in South Vietnam, and that for the past month the French Government had endeavored to persuade the United States Government to enter into a joint review of the political situation at Saigon and to reach mutual agreement on a course of action to follow that might avert the outbreak of civil war.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"French Government",
				48,
				65,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United States Government",
				103,
				127,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Diem",
				137,
				141,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"South Vietnam",
				243,
				256,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"French Government",
				290,
				307,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United States Government",
				339,
				363,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Saigon",
				423,
				429,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He added the personal comment that while holding the posts successively of Minister of Finance, Foreign Affairs, and now Prime Minister, he had not met a single person who believed that Diem could succeed in stabilizing the situation at Saigon.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Minister of Finance",
				75,
				94,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"Foreign Affairs",
				96,
				111,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"Prime Minister",
				121,
				135,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"Diem",
				186,
				190,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Saigon",
				237,
				243,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Prime Minister emphasized, however, that while neither he nor anyone in the French Government shared the American point of view as regards Diem, he wished to make clear that neither he nor the French Government had any intention or desire to enter into conflict with the United States on this score.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Prime Minister",
				4,
				18,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"French Government",
				80,
				97,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"American",
				109,
				117,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Diem",
				143,
				147,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"French Government",
				197,
				214,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United States",
				275,
				288,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The fact that Diem is anti-French, he said, is and has always been a secondary consideration as far as the French were concerned.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Diem",
				14,
				18,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"anti-French",
				22,
				33,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"French",
				107,
				113,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Prime Minister reiterated once again that the French Government is not wedded to any particular formula for the solution of the crisis at Saigon and that it continued to hold the hope that it might be possible to reach, in consultation with us, a mutually satisfactory position.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Prime Minister",
				4,
				18,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"French Government",
				50,
				67,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Saigon",
				142,
				148,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In referring to the steps taken by Bao Dai yesterday to convoke Diem as well as certain Vietnamese personalities to Cannes, the Prime Minister expressed his very real fear that these steps had perhaps been taken too late to save South Vietnam from full-scale civil war.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Bao Dai",
				35,
				42,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Diem",
				64,
				68,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Vietnamese",
				88,
				98,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Cannes",
				116,
				122,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Prime Minister",
				128,
				142,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"South Vietnam",
				229,
				242,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "If Bao Dai's action had been taken several weeks ago, he said, the chances of success would have been infinitely greater than those presented to us today.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Bao Dai",
				3,
				10,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Although it may be too late to prevent the occurrence of full-scale civil war in South Vietnam, the Prime Minister said that France remains ready to do its utmost in conjunction with the United States to retrieve the situation.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"South Vietnam",
				81,
				94,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Prime Minister",
				100,
				114,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"France",
				125,
				131,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United States",
				187,
				200,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In this connection, the Prime Minister expressed the view that with the sole exception of the problem posed by our feeling that M. Sainteny not return to Hanoi, he foresaw no difficulty in the French Government's accepting the views of the United States Government as outlined by the Ambassador.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Prime Minister",
				24,
				38,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"M. Sainteny",
				128,
				139,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Hanoi",
				154,
				159,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"French Government",
				193,
				210,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United States Government",
				240,
				264,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Ambassador",
				284,
				294,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He said, however, that he would like Minister Laforest and other officials concerned to go over the points as outlined by the Ambassador and that he would confirm the French position shortly.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Minister Laforest",
				37,
				54,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Ambassador",
				126,
				136,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"French",
				167,
				173,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "As regards United States concern over French policy towards North Vietnam, the Prime Minister said that he wished to underline in strongest terms that the French Government was not following an equivocal policy or playing \"a double game\" in Vietnam and that it had no intention of \"playing the Vietminh card\" to the detriment of the legally constituted Government of South Vietnam.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"United States",
				11,
				24,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"French",
				38,
				44,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"North Vietnam",
				60,
				73,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Prime Minister",
				79,
				93,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"French Government",
				155,
				172,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Vietnam",
				241,
				248,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Vietminh",
				294,
				302,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Government of South Vietnam",
				353,
				380,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He emphasized that the French Government had no illusions regarding Ho Chi Minh.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"French Government",
				23,
				40,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Ho Chi Minh",
				68,
				79,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "However, he said, France needed a representative at Hanoi not with a view to cooperating with the Vietminh but solely for the purpose of protecting such French interests and influence as remain and to keep abreast of developments in that region.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"France",
				18,
				24,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Hanoi",
				52,
				57,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Vietminh",
				98,
				106,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"French",
				153,
				159,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Prime Minister made abundantly clear that for domestic political considerations it was out of the question for him to relieve Sainteny of his functions.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Prime Minister",
				4,
				18,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Sainteny",
				130,
				138,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "However, he wished to assure the United States Government that the French Government had, as in the past, every intention of taking fully into account United States views in this regard.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"United States Government",
				33,
				57,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"French Government",
				67,
				84,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United States",
				151,
				164,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Minister Laforest at this juncture stated that the failure of the French Government to conclude the mixed company agreement with the Vietminh could be attributed in large measure to the unfavorable attitude taken by the United States Government toward the conclusion of such an agreement.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Minister Laforest",
				0,
				17,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"French Government",
				66,
				83,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Vietminh",
				133,
				141,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United States Government",
				220,
				244,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The sale of the Charbonnages du Tonkin constituted, he said, a clear-cut illustration of the intention of the French Government to give maximum consideration to United States views.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Charbonnages du Tonkin",
				16,
				38,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"French Government",
				110,
				127,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United States",
				161,
				174,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The person of Sainteny, however, Minister Laforest reiterated, posed a domestic political problem.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Sainteny",
				14,
				22,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Minister Laforest",
				33,
				50,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The latter's role, he said, was limited to that of an observer, and Sainteny had been selected for this post solely because he was considered to be the best qualified man for the job.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Saintenyr",
				68,
				76,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Sainteny mission as constituted today, the Prime Minister emphasized, represented a far more preferable approach than that of being placed in the position of having to accredit a consul to the Vietminh Government, a situation which the French Government has tried to avoid from the beginning.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Sainteny",
				4,
				12,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Prime Minister",
				47,
				61,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Vietminh Government",
				197,
				216,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"French Government",
				240,
				257,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In conclusion, Mr. Faure stressed that with the sole exception of the recall of Sainteny, he could foresee no impediment to French acceptance of the points as outlined by the Ambassador pursuant to the Department's instructions.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Faure",
				19,
				24,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Sainteny",
				80,
				88,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"French",
				124,
				130,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Ambassador",
				175,
				185,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Department",
				202,
				212,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In response to the Ambassador's inquiry concerning Bao Dai's delegation of full military power to General Vy, Minister Laforest stated that Vy was the oldest Vietnamese General, that he was generally respected, and stressed the importance of the fact that General Vy had made clear that he did not wish to participate in a fratricidal civil war.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Ambassador",
				19,
				29,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Bao Dai",
				51,
				58,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"General Vy",
				98,
				108,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Minister Laforest",
				110,
				127,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Vy",
				140,
				142,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Vietnamese",
				158,
				168,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"General",
				169,
				176,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"General Vy",
				256,
				266,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He noted that Diem presently has perhaps approximately 10 battalions of Tonkinese troops, including elite parachute elements, presently engaged in supporting him in the present conflict at Saigon.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Diem",
				14,
				18,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Tonkinese",
				72,
				81,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Saigon",
				189,
				195,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Minister Laforest likened the situation to the Swiss support of Louis XVI.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Minister Laforest",
				0,
				17,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Swiss",
				47,
				52,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Louis XVI",
				64,
				73,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "However, he said, while Diem might succeed in gaining control of the situation in Saigon-Cholon, unquestionably civil war would flare up and continue indecisively in the provinces.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Diem",
				24,
				28,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Saigon-Cholon",
				82,
				95,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Many terrible things could occur in the next several weeks, he added, and irremediable damage inflicted.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Prime Minister Faure intervened to point out that the Vietminh are deliberately keeping clear of the present conflict, \"rubbing their hands in delight\", with full knowledge that civil war will ultimately deliver South Vietnam into their hands.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Prime Minister Faure",
				0,
				20,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Vietminh",
				54,
				62,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"South Vietnam",
				212,
				225,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Prime Minister at this juncture referred to his statement at his morning press conference to the effect that France would keep its engagements under the Geneva Accords as regards elections, and he expressed the fear that the scheduled elections had been passed over (depasse) by events which very likely would deliver South Vietnam in fact into the hands of the Vietminh before July 1956.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Prime Minister",
				4,
				18,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"France",
				113,
				119,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Geneva Accords",
				157,
				171,
				"LAW"
			],
			[
				"South Vietnam",
				322,
				335,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Vietminh",
				366,
				374,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"July 1956",
				382,
				391,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Prime Minister stressed, however, that it was perhaps not impossible to retrieve the situation and ultimately succeed in the test with the Vietminh if joint Franco-American action taken quickly.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Prime Minister",
				4,
				18,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Vietminh",
				143,
				151,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Franco-American",
				161,
				176,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He underlined that the basic objective of France and the United States was the same, namely to maintain and safeguard a non-Communist Vietnam within the free world orbit.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"France",
				42,
				48,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United States",
				57,
				70,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"non-Communist",
				120,
				133,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Vietnam",
				134,
				141,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "M. Faure made clear, however, that the next move was primarily up to the United States and, specifically, he expressed the hope that the United States would exert its influence on Diem to see that he returned to Cannes in accordance with Bao Dai's request in an effort to salvage the situation and find a salutary solution.']",
		"entities": [
			[
				"M. Faure",
				0,
				8,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"United States",
				73,
				86,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United States",
				137,
				150,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Diem",
				180,
				184,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Cannes",
				212,
				218,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Bao Dai",
				238,
				245,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "['[Telegram] 18.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Greece declared to join Allies.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Greece",
				0,
				6,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Allies",
				24,
				30,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Victory for the Prime Minister.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Prime Minister",
				16,
				30,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "No general mobilization.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "But one division of infantry to be sent to the Dardanelles.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Dardanelles",
				47,
				58,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Entire Greek Navy at the disposal of English.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Greek Navy",
				7,
				17,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"English",
				37,
				44,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Ports such as Piraeus, Saloniki, Tenedos for the use of Allies.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Piraeus",
				14,
				21,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Saloniki",
				23,
				31,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Tenedos",
				33,
				40,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Allies",
				56,
				62,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "King will accept officially to-day.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"King",
				0,
				4,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Big demonstration will follow.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Droppers']",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Droppers",
				0,
				8,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "[\"3674.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Re last paragraph Embtel 3673.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Embtel 3673",
				18,
				29,
				"WORK_OF_ART"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Following is text joint appreciation agreed to by British, French, and American Ambassadors: Begin text Internal situation in Lebanon is likely to reach critical stage within the next week.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"British, French, and American Ambassadors",
				50,
				91,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Lebanon",
				126,
				133,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "After consultation with my American-French/French-British/American-British colleagues following is our joint appreciation for urgent consideration by our respective governments (my colleagues are reporting in identical terms).",
		"entities": [
			[
				"American-French/French-British/American-British",
				27,
				74,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "(a) General Chehab is clearly unwilling to accept presidential succession from hands of Chamoun and thereby incur a political debt.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"General Chehab",
				4,
				18,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Chamoun",
				88,
				95,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Only if serious unrest threatens and no other solution seems possible might he be persuaded to stand; but it would be as an independent or opposition candidate.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "First alternative would have suited our interests but second alternative would necessarily represent a clear defeat for Chamoun's pro-western policy and is therefore undesirable.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chamoun",
				120,
				127,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"pro-western",
				130,
				141,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "(b)",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Chamoun is in our view almost certain to seek amendment of constitution and stand for re-election.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chamoun",
				0,
				7,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "We know he has solicited and been promised active sympathy and support of Iraq, Iran, Sudan and Turkey and possibly other countries such as Pakistan, Saudi Arabia, Greece, Italy, etc.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Iraq",
				74,
				78,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Iran",
				80,
				84,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Sudan",
				86,
				91,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Turkey",
				96,
				102,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Pakistan",
				140,
				148,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Saudi Arabia",
				150,
				162,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Greece",
				164,
				170,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Italy",
				172,
				177,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "His success or failure must therefore be judged in much wider context than mere internal Lebanese politics.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Lebanese",
				89,
				97,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Once he has announced his intentions western failure to support him will have repercussions among all most moderate and responsible friends and allies of west in ME area.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Chamoun has come to symbolize to them forces of resistance to Nasser.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chamoun",
				0,
				7,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Nasser",
				62,
				68,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "(c) Parliamentary situation is uncertain but Chamoun can probably command necessary 2/3s majority for amendment of constitution and re-election.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Parliamentary",
				4,
				17,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Chamoun",
				45,
				52,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "But opposition representation in Chamber of Deputies not proportional to its popular support and many Moslem and some Christian elements seem determined to mobilize their adherents outside Chamber and resort if necessary to extreme measures to frustrate Chamoun.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chamber of Deputies",
				33,
				52,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Moslem",
				102,
				108,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Christian",
				118,
				127,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Chamber",
				189,
				196,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Chamoun",
				254,
				261,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Disorders must therefore be expected.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Extent of danger this factor represents depends upon willingness of Army (i.e., General Chehab) to maintain order at all costs.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Army",
				68,
				72,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"General Chehab",
				80,
				94,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "(d) General Chehab mistrusts Chamoun and is inclined to remain aloof in any civil conflict, which would inevitably tend to assume a communal character.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"General Chehab",
				4,
				18,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Chamoun",
				29,
				36,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "But we consider he is first and foremost a loyal soldier and citizen and that declared policy of three western powers will be determinative in deciding his attitude.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "(e) President Chamoun has clearly indicated his final decision will be taken about May 7.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President Chamoun",
				4,
				21,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"May 7",
				83,
				88,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He can then be expected to appeal to us for open support.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Time will be very short as parliamentary measures for amendment of constitution and re-election could be forced through in a single session.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "In our view optimum solution would be that Chamoun should hand over presidential office to General Chehab or to some other mutually agreed candidate.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chamoun",
				43,
				50,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"General Chehab",
				91,
				105,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "This now seems excluded.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "We are therefore likely to be faced with stark alternative of supporting Chamoun or standing aloof.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chamoun",
				73,
				80,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "For reasons in paragraph 2(b) above in particular we consider we shall have to support Chamoun despite known risks.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chamoun",
				87,
				94,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Practical measures short of open support might involve: (a) Approach to General Chehab to ensure maintenance of law and order (see 2(d) above).",
		"entities": [
			[
				"General Chehab",
				72,
				86,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Financial aid to deal especially with press which is hostile but venal.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Coordination and mobilization of diplomatic support by countries mentioned in 2(b) above.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Provision of equipment to strengthen government radio station Beirut.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Beirut",
				62,
				68,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Clear warning UAR interference will not be tolerated.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"UAR",
				14,
				17,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "We are not able to assess reaction of EG [sic] Soviet Government which may be extremely sharp owing to presence of Nasser as their guest.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Soviet Government",
				47,
				64,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Nasser",
				115,
				121,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "But we consider that despite possibility of internal disorder and external complications failure to support Chamoun represents greater long term risk.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chamoun",
				108,
				115,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Grateful for very early instructions, since President has already asked to see American Ambassador on Wednesday morning, May 7.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President",
				44,
				53,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"American Ambassador",
				79,
				98,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"May 7",
				121,
				126,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "End text Suggest Department pass Copenhagen for Secretary.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Department",
				17,
				27,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Copenhagen",
				33,
				43,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Secretary",
				48,
				57,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "McClintock\"]",
		"entities": [
			[
				"McClintock",
				0,
				10,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "[\"No. 263.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "No. 28.]",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Sir: With reference to the ceremonies which have taken place at New York upon the arrival at that port and the delivery of the statue of Liberty, I have received from M. de Freycinet an official communication requesting me to express to my Government the thanks of the French Republic for the magnificent and flattering way in which the gift of France has been received.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"New York",
				64,
				72,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"statue of Liberty",
				127,
				144,
				"FAC"
			],
			[
				"M. de Freycinet",
				167,
				182,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"French Republic",
				269,
				284,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"France",
				345,
				351,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I inclose herewith a copy and translation of Mr. de Freycinet's note.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"de Freycinct",
				49,
				61,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I have, &c., ROBERT M. McLANE.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"ROBERT M. McLANE",
				13,
				29,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "[Inclosure in No. 28.--Translation.]",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Mr. de Freycinct to Mr. McLane.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"de Freycinct",
				4,
				16,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"McLane",
				24,
				30,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Ministry of Foreign Affairs,Paris, June 20, 1885.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
				0,
				27,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Paris",
				28,
				33,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"June 20, 1885",
				35,
				48,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Sir: Our consul at New York telegraphs me an account of the imposing ceremony which has just taken place in the United States on the occasion of the delivery of the statue of Liberty.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"New York",
				19,
				27,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"United States",
				112,
				125,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"statue of Liberty",
				165,
				182,
				"FAC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He calls especial attention to the magnificent reception and flattering welcome which Admiral Lacombe and his staff have received from Mr. Whitney, Secretary of the Navy, and Mr. Grace, mayor of New York.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Admiral Lacombe",
				86,
				101,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Whitney",
				139,
				146,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Secretary of the Navy",
				148,
				169,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"Grace",
				179,
				184,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"mayor of New York",
				186,
				203,
				"TITLE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I beg you to be kind enough to transmit to the Federal Government the expression of our gratitude for these marks of sympathy which correspond so well with the sentiments of good feeling and cordiality which unite the two nations.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Federal Government",
				47,
				65,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Accept, &c., C. de FREYCINET.\"]",
		"entities": [
			[
				"C. de FREYCINET",
				13,
				28,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "['NATIONAL SECURITY COUNCIL MEETING IN CABINET ROOM, MONDAY, NOVEMBER 25, 1968 WITH THE PRESIDENT, SECRETARY RUSK, J. R. WIGGINS, AMBASSADOR TO THE U.N. JOSEPH SISCO, ASSISTANT SECRETARY OF STATE, SECRETARY CLIFFORD, PAUL NITZE, SECRETARY FOWLER, DIRECTOR HELMS, GENERAL WHEELER, GEORGE CHRISTIAN, WALT ROSTOW, BROMLEY SMITH AND ED FRIED --12:06 P.M.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"NATIONAL SECURITY COUNCIL",
				2,
				27,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"CABINET ROOM",
				39,
				51,
				"FAC"
			],
			[
				"NOVEMBER 25, 1968",
				61,
				78,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"PRESIDENT",
				88,
				97,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"SECRETARY RUSK",
				99,
				113,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"J. R. WIGGINS",
				115,
				128,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"AMBASSADOR TO THE U.N.",
				130,
				152,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"JOSEPH SISCO",
				153,
				165,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"ASSISTANT SECRETARY OF STATE",
				167,
				195,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"SECRETARY CLIFFORD",
				197,
				215,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"PAUL NITZE",
				217,
				227,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"SECRETARY FOWLER",
				229,
				245,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"DIRECTOR HELMS",
				247,
				261,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"GENERAL WHEELER",
				263,
				278,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"GEORGE CHRISTIAN",
				280,
				296,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"WALT ROSTOW",
				298,
				309,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"BROMLEY SMITH",
				311,
				324,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"ED FRIED",
				329,
				337,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "[Here follows a brief introductory discussion of two U.S. reconnaissance planes that were shot down over Vietnam.]",
		"entities": [
			[
				"U.S.",
				53,
				57,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Vietnam",
				105,
				112,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Fowler:",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Fowler",
				0,
				6,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The first place we always look to for answers on these things are the Departments.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Departments",
				70,
				81,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "And I think, therefore, I will give you a quick report on what the market situation was as of 11 o'clock this morning which covers most of the trading day in Europe.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Europe",
				158,
				164,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The exchange rate, movements and the flow of funds are very faithful because the money is going out of Germany and into France.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Germany",
				103,
				110,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"France",
				120,
				126,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "And the French franc rate is up and the British pound rate is up and apparently this is the result of the real money flow rather than in marketing prevention.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"French",
				8,
				14,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"British",
				40,
				47,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The other significant thing from our point of view is that the dollar is strong and the gold market has remained very calm.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Low rise, and high minor rise, in the morning from 30# the first fixing and a decline back to $40.10 in the afternoon.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "So the first market reactions are good.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "As to the impact of the French measures, the details will not be announced until tomorrow, so we get impressions on these from our fellows in Paris the way they feel about these things.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"French",
				24,
				30,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Paris",
				142,
				147,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The French exchange patrol measures that were issued last June, and then rescinded later, were fairly mild in form and not particularly effective, but the new regulations have all the markings of being very tough and very effective, as far as releasing money from France by Frenchmen--in other words, out of France.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"French",
				4,
				10,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"June",
				58,
				62,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"France",
				264,
				270,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Frenchmen",
				274,
				283,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"France",
				308,
				314,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Just one example.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "On tourism.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Frenchmen can carry abroad $40.00 worth of French francs, and--in French bank notes--and $100.00 of foreign currency.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Frenchmen",
				0,
				9,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"French",
				43,
				49,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"French",
				66,
				72,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "They must carry evidence that they bought the currency from an authorized bank and it is a once in a year allowance.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "People moving into France will have to--when you go in you will have to, if you are an ordinary tourist, register the amount of currency you are taking in, so that the effective currency rate is under control.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"France",
				19,
				25,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Characteristically, French exchange control regulations have been very effective in the past when they have been really tough enough, though I don't think we should underestimate the possibility that for a period of time they may be able to considerably arrest the flow.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"French",
				20,
				26,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The export tax percentage has not been made at all clear.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "DeGaulle simply said he would relieve corporations of \"certain taxes that excessively weigh on their costs.\"",
		"entities": [
			[
				"DeGaulle",
				0,
				8,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "We have no details, but it seems to involve an increased tax rebate of some sort, like our investment credit on import-export taxes.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "On imports, nothing special expected.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "This could be a very effective way of quickly arresting the balance of payments problem, but there's no sign yet of a rigid issuance of import licenses.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "France has traditionally resisted import surcharges, that is, adding taxes to imports as being inflationary.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"France",
				0,
				6,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "And reducing the pressure of foreign competition.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "We don't know what they are going to do in the wage-price field, although the General's message to the Nation clearly indicated a Hold the Line policy on wages and prices.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"General",
				78,
				85,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Whether that would be by any further measures or not, or whether he's going to wait and see what's happening, we don't know.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "I think insofar as the United States is concerned--impact on trade--it would be fair to say that what's happened in Germany, which is advantageous to us, will be adequate to prove to be a counterweight for anything that happens in Great Britain or anything that we see currently likely to happen in France.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"United States",
				23,
				36,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Germany",
				116,
				123,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Great Britain",
				231,
				244,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"France",
				299,
				305,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I would say it's a standoff and the benefits we receive from Germany would probably just about be offset by the French and the United Kingdom moves.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Germany",
				61,
				68,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"French",
				112,
				118,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United Kingdom",
				127,
				141,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The overall impact of this that we should note is, of course, that now four of the major economies in the world--United States, United Kingdom, France, and to some extent Germany--are cutting back their growth and this will tend over a time to have some heavy impact on world trade.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"United States",
				113,
				126,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United Kingdom",
				128,
				142,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"France",
				144,
				150,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Germany",
				171,
				178,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Mr. President, I think the further implications for the Security Council would be largely in the political field.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President",
				4,
				13,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Security Council",
				56,
				72,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "There has undoubtedly been a great impact as a result of this situation on Franco-German relationships and on German-United Kingdom relationships.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Franco-German",
				75,
				88,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"German-United Kingdom",
				110,
				131,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I think as far as the offset situation, instead of the reduction of their trade surplus being a minus, in view of the statements that Strauss and Schiller made during the course of the meeting, some of which have gotten into the press, it gives us a very firm position--that don't come around pleading now that because you did this you can diminish your offset and prolong it.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Strauss",
				134,
				141,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Schiller",
				146,
				154,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "One of the prime reasons that they put forward during the course of the meeting for not revaluing at 7-1/2 percent or greatly increasing these grave tax measures was that they needed to have adequate trade surplus in order to make good on a 900 billion dollar offset--the fact that this is something our successors should be made aware of.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "President: What is the feeling between the Germans and the French?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President",
				0,
				9,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Germans",
				43,
				50,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"French",
				59,
				65,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Fowler: Considerable.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Fowler",
				0,
				6,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "[8 lines of source text not declassified] There were--undoubtedly this pressure that was felt in the meeting of the Central Bank Governors at Bonn--and the Germans feel that the French put them in a very tough position.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Central Bank Governors",
				116,
				138,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Bonn",
				142,
				146,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Germans",
				156,
				163,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"French",
				178,
				184,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In turn, the French, I think quite properly, feel that the Germans have not done as much as they could or should as partners in this operation.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"French",
				13,
				19,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Germans",
				59,
				66,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "What they would have liked to have done is work out a straight Franco-German deal--a package deal, and neither party--they were not able to work that out.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Franco-German",
				63,
				76,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "President: What conceivably could we be called upon to do extra?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President",
				0,
				9,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Put up more as far as France?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"France",
				22,
				28,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Fowler:",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Fowler",
				0,
				6,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "No.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "The installment on the credit package.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "A French request for withdrawal (interrupted).",
		"entities": [
			[
				"French",
				2,
				8,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "President: Four or five hundred million more?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President",
				0,
				9,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Fowler: I don't think so.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Fowler",
				0,
				6,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "President: Is there anything else that you can foresee that we ought to be planning?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President",
				0,
				9,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Fowler:",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Fowler",
				0,
				6,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "We, last night--yesterday, Mr. President, made an appraisal of the French measures, and what we could do in addition to help on this thing.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President",
				31,
				40,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"French",
				67,
				73,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Bill Martin yesterday afternoon called the head of the German Central Bank, Blessing and ---- the Head of the Mellon Central Bank, who's also Chairman of the Ball Group, and Stopper, the Head of the Swiss Bank, and asked them to do what they could do through their organizations to give objective press guidance on the French action of the sort that we are trying to give here.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Bill Martin",
				0,
				11,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"German Central Bank",
				55,
				74,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Blessing",
				76,
				84,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Mellon Central Bank",
				110,
				129,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Chairman",
				142,
				150,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"Ball Group",
				158,
				168,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Stopper",
				174,
				181,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Swiss Bank",
				199,
				209,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"French",
				319,
				325,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "And also to speed up a settling program--that the Central Bank Governments were mandated to do with the BIS on a recycling of check flow--this wouldn't have any figures or any limit but the idea you see would be to make the gain completely useless.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Central Bank Governments",
				50,
				74,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"BIS",
				104,
				107,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "If one--let's say the Bank of France intervening in the market to protect the franc spent one hundred million and it went into Germany and that could be identified as speculative though the Germans would automatically put that back in the form of some credit arrangement to the Bank of France, so that there would be a kind of a circular flow of funds rather than a drain, an ever increasing drain, which would make the situation impossible.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Bank of France",
				22,
				36,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Germany",
				127,
				134,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Germans",
				190,
				197,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Bank of France",
				278,
				292,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In addition to those measures, Martin asked Blessing if there were any other measures that he thought the Germans could take to moderate capital outflow.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Martin",
				31,
				37,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Blessing",
				44,
				52,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Germans",
				106,
				113,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Blessing and Martin have a very good relationship, and I am sure Blessing levelled with him when he said he couldn't think of another thing they could do.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Blessing",
				0,
				8,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Martin",
				13,
				19,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Blessing",
				65,
				73,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He called the British Treasury and expressed the desirability of their making helpful noises.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"British Treasury",
				14,
				30,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He talked to Douglas Allott.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Douglas Allott",
				13,
				27,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The number two man agreed and said they were trying to and would follow our lead on that.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "They seemed to have mixed emotions.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "They are very glad there was no franc devaluation, which was what they were deathly afraid of, certainly a major one.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "They are concerned over market reactions--probably feel better today after what has happened.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "He talked also to Paul Schweitzer, the Director of the International Monetary Fund, who had developed that there was some case for devaluation, but felt that this move was a good move, a gracious move.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Paul Schweitzer",
				18,
				33,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"International Monetary Fund",
				55,
				82,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He did not think the French would apply for a standby credit on the Fund at this time, but was less certain on this than he had been on Saturday afternoon.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"French",
				21,
				27,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Fund",
				68,
				72,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I think the IMF will make constructive comments, so the most, Mr. President, that we can do at this time, I think, is to try to keep this in an optimistic, favorable framework, this whole suggestion.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"IMF",
				12,
				15,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"President",
				66,
				75,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "President: Is it fair to say that after reading DeGaulle's speech and after seeing the performance of the market and after talking to the bankers that Martin talked to and the contacts that you all have had, that you think that this is likely to be successful?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President",
				0,
				9,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"DeGaulle",
				48,
				56,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Martin",
				151,
				157,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Fowler:",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Fowler",
				0,
				6,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I think I would say that.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "President:",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President",
				0,
				9,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "And is it fair to assume that you do not anticipate any more serious calls for performance on our part?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Fowler:",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Fowler",
				0,
				6,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I hesitate to make a long-term projection on that.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "I think this thing could conceivably hold and stabilize the situation for months in advance.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "On the other hand-- President:",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President",
				20,
				29,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Well, but I got the impression prior to reading the report that before he even took this action, that he didn't feel that it was going to adversely affect us one way or the other.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Fowler:",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Fowler",
				0,
				6,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "No, I don't think that-- President: And that there wasn't anything much that we needed to do.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President",
				25,
				34,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Fowler:",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Fowler",
				0,
				6,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I don't think we're in it-- President: What I'm asking now is, should we pull in our belts, pull up our socks, take any additional steps, make any additional preparation?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President",
				28,
				37,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Look at any measures that we might have to take if we got into an emergency?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Fowler:",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Fowler",
				0,
				6,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "No.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "I think that a--as I see it, the situation now, we have done all that we can do or that the minds of all the Ministers of Finance and the Central Bank Governors can conjure up.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Ministers of Finance",
				109,
				129,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Central Bank Governors",
				138,
				160,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I think about all I would say on that is I think that over the next 60 or 90 days we ought to keep our situation extremely sound here at home, because the one sustaining element in the whole picture, psychologically, has been the strength of the dollar.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Had we been rocking and rolling God knows what would have happened.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "[Here follows discussion of Vietnam, several issues before the United Nations, the Middle East, and disarmament questions.]']",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Vietnam",
				28,
				35,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United Nations",
				63,
				77,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Middle East",
				83,
				94,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "[\"[Omitted here are a table of contents, and Sections I through X.] XI.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "LATIN AMERICA",
		"entities": [
			[
				"LATIN AMERICA",
				0,
				13,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Throughout Latin America, governments continued in 1972 to come under severe pressures to achieve economic development and social reform.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Latin America",
				11,
				24,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"1972",
				51,
				55,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The rate of progress has varied greatly in the hemisphere, but no country has reached a sufficient level of development to warrant confidence that both goals will be reached soon.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Even in countries that enjoy relatively enlightened leadership, tradition-bound political groups and social institutions offer strong resistance to change.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Other problems, such as high population growth and the rapid influx of impoverished, illiterate, and unskilled people into urban areas also hindered progress.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Developments in Latin America during 1972 reflected the intensification of nationalistic sentiment that has characterized recent years.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Latin America",
				16,
				29,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"1972",
				37,
				41,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Nationalism contributed to further shifts in international relationships and to pressures against US and other foreign investment.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"US",
				98,
				100,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "There was generally increased interest among Latin American governments in expanding ties with Europe, the Soviet Union, Japan, and to a lesser extent, Communist China.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Latin American",
				45,
				59,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Europe",
				95,
				101,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Soviet Union",
				107,
				119,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Japan",
				121,
				126,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Communist China",
				152,
				167,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Thirteen Latin American nations now have formal relations with Moscow; Paraguay is the only South American country that has not recognized the USSR.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Latin American",
				9,
				23,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Moscow",
				63,
				69,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Paraguay",
				71,
				79,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"South American",
				92,
				106,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"USSR",
				143,
				147,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Argentina, Mexico, and Guyana opened diplomatic relations with Peking during the year, and several countries exchanged commercial missions with Communist China.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Argentina",
				0,
				9,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Mexico",
				11,
				17,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Guyana",
				23,
				29,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Peking",
				63,
				69,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Communist China",
				144,
				159,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Nationalism was a major ingredient in the tendency among Latin American leaders to pursue what they described as revolutionary policies.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Latin American",
				57,
				71,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "This was true in Brazil, Panama, and Peru, as well as in Chile, which has a Marxist president.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Brazil",
				17,
				23,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Panama",
				25,
				31,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Peru",
				37,
				41,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Chile",
				57,
				62,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Marxist",
				76,
				83,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Latin America's economic growth slowed for the second consecutive year in 1972 but remained above the 5.3 percent average rate of the 1961-70 period.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Latin America",
				0,
				13,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"1972",
				74,
				78,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"1961-70",
				134,
				141,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The gross domestic product for Latin America grew by an estimated 5.7 percent in real terms, down from the 6.1 percent obtained the previous year and considerably below the post-1960 record of 6.8 percent reached in 1970.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Latin America",
				31,
				44,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"post-1960",
				173,
				182,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"1970",
				216,
				220,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Despite this slowdown and the continuing high rate of population growth (2.8 percent annually), per capita income gains in 1972 averaged 2.8 percent for the region, surpassing the 2.5 percent goal established under the Alliance for Progress and considerably better than the 1961-70 average of 2.3 percent.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"1972",
				123,
				127,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"Alliance for Progress",
				219,
				240,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"1961-70",
				274,
				281,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The region's progress during 1972, as in the previous year, owed much to the extremely rapid growth of the Brazilian economy (about 9.5 percent).",
		"entities": [
			[
				"1972",
				29,
				33,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"Brazilian",
				107,
				116,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Excluding Brazil, economic growth in the region averaged only 4.3 percent, and per capita growth only 1.5 percent.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Brazil",
				10,
				16,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Although the Mexican economy recovered substantially in 1972, growth fell sharply in Peru and Chile and remained low in Argentina and Uruguay.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Mexican",
				13,
				20,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"1972",
				56,
				60,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"Peru",
				85,
				89,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Chile",
				94,
				99,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Argentina",
				120,
				129,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Uruguay",
				134,
				141,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Most countries saw the gap widen between themselves and rich nations outside the hemisphere.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "The armed forces, to varying degrees, exercised political power in Argentina, Brazil, Bolivia, Panama, Peru, and Ecuador.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Argentina",
				67,
				76,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Brazil",
				78,
				84,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Bolivia",
				86,
				93,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Panama",
				95,
				101,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Peru",
				103,
				107,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Ecuador",
				113,
				120,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In Ecuador a military coup ousted President Velasco and installed General Rodriguez as the national leader.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Ecuador",
				3,
				10,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"President Velasco",
				34,
				51,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"General Rodriguez",
				66,
				83,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "To a great extent the armed forces in these countries apparently are convinced that they alone are capable of ensuring progress at present stages of development.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "During 1972 national elections were held in Jamaica, where the opposition party regained power after a ten-year lapse, and in El Salvador, which saw a closely contested presidential race decided by the legislature.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"1972",
				7,
				11,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"Jamaica",
				44,
				51,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"El Salvador",
				126,
				137,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In Panama, elections restored the presidential system with National Guard Commander, General Torrijos, retaining supreme executive power under a new constitution.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Panama",
				3,
				9,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"National Guard Commander",
				59,
				83,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"General Torrijos",
				85,
				101,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Prime Minister Pindling of the Bahamas won a strong victory in September elections, thus giving him the mandate he sought to press on to independence in 1973.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Prime Minister Pindling",
				0,
				23,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Bahamas",
				31,
				38,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"September",
				63,
				72,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"1973",
				153,
				157,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In Nicaragua a constituent assembly and a three-man executive were elected to serve until 1974.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Nicaragua",
				3,
				12,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"1974",
				90,
				94,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Uruguay's President Bordaberry began his term on 1 March and proceeded in the months thereafter to develop effective security measures that enabled the military to inflict serious damage on the Tupamaro terrorist movement.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Uruguay",
				0,
				7,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"President Bordaberry",
				10,
				30,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"1 March",
				49,
				56,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"Tupamaro",
				194,
				202,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In Argentina, the military-controlled government initiated a process to return power to an elected government in 1973, a task complicated by the difficulty in reaching an understanding with the followers of ex-dictator Juan Peron, who form the country's strongest political movement.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Argentina",
				3,
				12,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"1973",
				113,
				117,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"Juan Peron",
				219,
				229,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In Chile, serious economic problems, including consumer shortages and an inflation rate well over 100 percent, were compounded by Marxist President Allende's campaign to expand state control over the economy.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chile",
				3,
				8,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Marxist",
				130,
				137,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"President Allende",
				138,
				155,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Frequent major strikes and large-scale public protests contributed to unrest and occasional rumors of a military coup.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Although Allende was usually able to keep the tactical advantage over the opposition, pressures on the government increased significantly.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Allende",
				9,
				16,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Efforts at regional economic cooperation showed some gains during 1972, although major obstacles to full integration remained.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"1972",
				66,
				70,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Andean Pact group prepared to admit Venezuela as a sixth member.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Andean Pact",
				4,
				15,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Venezuela",
				40,
				49,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In the Caribbean, several English-speaking states agreed on preliminary plans to initiate a common market during 1973.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Caribbean",
				7,
				16,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"English",
				26,
				33,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"1973",
				113,
				117,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Central American Common Market showed signs of reviving after a period that threatened to destroy its chances to bring greater regional economic cooperation.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Central American Common Market",
				4,
				34,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Some persistent problems affecting US interests remained unsolved; at least some of them reflected the heightened sense of nationalism on the part of a number of countries.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"US",
				35,
				37,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The dispute continued between Peru and the International Petroleum Company over payment of compensation for the company's expropriated assets.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Peru",
				30,
				34,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"International Petroleum Company",
				43,
				74,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Chile's unwillingness to provide compensation for the expropriated holdings of the two largest US-owned copper firms in Chile was a continuing source of friction.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chile",
				0,
				5,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"US",
				95,
				97,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Chile",
				120,
				125,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Salinity problems remained a nettlesome factor in Mexican-US relations, with both countries seeking equitable means of alleviating damage to Mexican soil.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Mexican-US",
				50,
				60,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Mexican",
				141,
				148,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Several nations were firmly pursuing a policy designed to establish their sovereignty over an expanded territorial sea, in several cases up to a 200-mile limit.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "There was growing support in Latin America for steps to end Cuba's isolation in the hemisphere.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Latin America",
				29,
				42,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Cuba",
				60,
				64,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Peru's renewal of diplomatic relations with Havana in July undermined the OAS sanctions against Cuba.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Peru",
				0,
				4,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Havana",
				44,
				50,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"July",
				54,
				58,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"OAS",
				74,
				77,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Cuba",
				96,
				100,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Guyana, Jamaica, Trinidad-Tobago, and Barbados have agreed to seek early diplomatic ties with Cuba.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Guyana",
				0,
				6,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Jamaica",
				8,
				15,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Trinidad-Tobago",
				17,
				32,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Barbados",
				38,
				46,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Cuba",
				94,
				98,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Meanwhile, the Castro Government's close relationship with the Soviet Union appeared to have been further strengthened by Fidel Castro's extended visit.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Castro",
				15,
				21,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Soviet Union",
				63,
				75,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Fidel Castro",
				122,
				134,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Shortly after his return to Havana it was announced that CEMA, the Soviet-dominated economic partnership, had accepted Cuba as a member.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Havana",
				28,
				34,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"CEMA",
				57,
				61,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Soviet",
				67,
				73,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Cuba",
				119,
				123,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Nevertheless, the Cuban economy showed no improvement over the poor performance of the previous year.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Cuban",
				18,
				23,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Only about 4 million tons of sugar were produced -- the second lowest figure in Castro's 13-year rule.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Castro",
				80,
				86,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Despite the lackluster record of insurgency movements in the hemisphere, Cuba has continued to call for armed revolution in countries of the hemisphere where it believes conditions are exploitable.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Cuba",
				73,
				77,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Direct Cuban support for guerrilla activities has for tactical reasons become more selective and is now limited to Guatemala and one or two other countries.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Cuban",
				7,
				12,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Guatemala",
				115,
				124,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Politically motivated violence, at times directed against US installations, occurred occasionally in several countries as dissident groups attempted to exploit underlying dissatisfactions.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"US",
				58,
				60,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Bombings and other isolated violence occurred, notably in Mexico, Argentina, and Chile.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Mexico",
				58,
				64,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Argentina",
				66,
				75,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Chile",
				81,
				86,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In Brazil, on the other hand, the terrorists continued to suffer setbacks at the hands of the security forces and became less and less effective.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Brazil",
				3,
				9,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Small guerrilla bands continued to operate in Guatemala, Venezuela, and Colombia, but without much success.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Guatemala",
				46,
				55,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Venezuela",
				57,
				66,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Colombia",
				72,
				80,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Advocates of black power were active in the Caribbean; a principal objective is to end foreign domination of the local economies.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Caribbean",
				44,
				53,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Aside from contributing to occasional minor disruptions, however, black power groups have had relatively little impact.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "[Omitted here are Sections XII through XXIII.]\"]",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "[\"[Telegram--Paraphrase.]",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Referring to legation's telegram of 28th, Mr. Knox advises Mr. Squiers that the department accepts the indemnities offered and dismissal of police officers involved in the case of the Buffalo.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"28th",
				36,
				40,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"Knox",
				46,
				50,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Squiers",
				63,
				70,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Buffalo",
				184,
				191,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Mr. Knox says that persons other than police officers involved should be punished by the courts, and that indemnity payments should be accompanied by a formal expression of regret pursuant to instructions.\"]",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Knox",
				4,
				8,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "['No. 173.]",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Sir: I have the honor to report that Mr. August Dziuk, concerning whom there has been considerable correspondence between the Department and this Legation in relation to the Balboa and Pacific Estates Company, Limited, and railway development in Panama, called upon me this morning and stated that he is leaving Saturday for Washington (en route to Germany) to interview the American Government with regard to his affairs and is considering opening an office in New York for the purpose of interesting American capital.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"August Dziuk",
				41,
				53,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Department",
				126,
				136,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Legation",
				146,
				154,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Balboa and Pacific Estates Company, Limited",
				174,
				217,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Panama",
				246,
				252,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Washington",
				325,
				345,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Germany",
				349,
				356,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"American Government",
				375,
				394,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"New York",
				462,
				470,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"American",
				502,
				510,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Mr. Dziuk asked for a letter of introduction for use at the Department.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Dziuk",
				4,
				9,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Department",
				60,
				70,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I suggested that he would naturally come to our Government with an introduction from his Embassy in Washington, but that I would give him a personal note of introduction, as he requested.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Embassy",
				89,
				96,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Washington",
				100,
				110,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The exact composition of the body of capitalists which he represents is a little in doubt as it is given out that it is made up of English capitalists rather more than of German.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"English",
				131,
				138,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"German",
				171,
				177,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Such introduction to our Government as he may receive through the German Embassy will probably make more clear his standing.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"German Embassy",
				66,
				80,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Mr. Dziuk asked for a map and showed me the exact original concession, explaining that the territory, which he himself had been the first white man to explore, was very rich in gold.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Dziuk",
				4,
				9,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He stated that he had met with no opposition in obtaining the concession covering this first area of country and to the railroads covered by that concession.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "When he pointed out the route of his proposed extension to or near Panama, I asked him why he sought this.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Panama",
				67,
				73,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He showed some embarrassment saying that his original concession was no good without this concession, and that the territory through which the proposed line would run was very fertile and rich.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Mr. Dziuk evidently was cognizant, from Panaman sources, of the real reasons why his projects are obnoxious to our Government; and I thought it well to state that the opposition he had met with was not because of his nationality but that it would be quite the same if he were of any other foreign nation, saying that the American Government, realizing that the canal is not only a commercial but a military measure, naturally considers everything from that viewpoint, even looking far ahead into the future.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Dziuk",
				4,
				9,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Panaman",
				40,
				47,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"American Government",
				321,
				340,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I remarked that the American Government had no objections to himself as an individual.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"American Government",
				20,
				39,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In conclusion, I said to Mr. Dziuk that while I could not with propriety have suggested his going to Washington to see my Government, however, since he had himself determined on this course, I would say that I had no doubt it would prove more satisfactory to him to discuss his affairs at headquarters.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Dziuk",
				29,
				34,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Washington",
				101,
				111,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I have [etc.] Wm. Whiting Andrews.']",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Wm. Whiting Andrews",
				14,
				33,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "['Participants: Dr. Hanna Saba, United Nations Mr. T. F. Power, Jr., United States Mission Dr. Saba informed me this morning that the United Nations today received a telegram signed by Acting Foreign Minister Clementis accrediting Mr. Houdek as Permanent Czechoslovakian Delegate to the United Nations, empowered to sit on all United Nations bodies on which Czechoslovakia is entitled to be represented.']",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Hanna Saba",
				20,
				30,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"United Nations",
				32,
				46,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"T. F. Power",
				51,
				62,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"United States Mission",
				69,
				90,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Saba",
				95,
				99,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"United Nations",
				134,
				148,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Acting Foreign Minister Clementis",
				185,
				218,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Houdek",
				235,
				241,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Permanent Czechoslovakian Delegate to the United Nations",
				245,
				301,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"United Nations",
				327,
				341,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Czechoslovakia",
				358,
				372,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "[\"5706.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "1.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "I am sure you have in mind fact that Park reacts sensitively to special attentions shown him on such occasions as the Honolulu meeting.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Park",
				37,
				41,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Honolulu",
				118,
				126,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "If it is intended to move him forward on question of additional troops, it is vital that consideration be given to gestures indicating personal esteem of President Johnson for him.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President Johnson",
				154,
				171,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "2.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "I do not believe that the problem of additional troops is as difficult for him as he and his associates pretend, but their attitude does lend emphasis to para one above, and there will of course be substantial, perhaps outlandish, price tag attached.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Park's thinking on subject will also be conditioned by his estimate of probable outcome of our presidential election.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Park",
				0,
				4,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Porter\"]",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Porter",
				0,
				6,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "[\"Suggestions We need Asians to take the lead in Asian affairs.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Asians",
				22,
				28,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Asian",
				49,
				54,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Best asset to US is strong Asian leader, who is our friend, who understands us, and is prepared to weld Asians together toward objectives that coincide with our aims.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"US",
				14,
				16,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Asian",
				27,
				32,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Asians",
				104,
				110,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Suggest we bet on Ferdinand Marcos of the Philippines as having good potential for this kind of tough, charismatic leadership.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Ferdinand Marcos",
				18,
				34,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Philippines",
				42,
				53,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Let Asians take up the burden we have been carrying--on the battlefield--and in the farm fields.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Asians",
				4,
				10,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "a. Equip two or more Korean divisions, and send them to Vietnam.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Korean",
				21,
				27,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Vietnam",
				56,
				63,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "They could easily take the place of 30-40,000 Americans.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Americans",
				46,
				55,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The price we pay for this is cheap--for the equipping Koreans is at the ratio of 5-1 to 10-1 for the same equipment of the same number of Americans.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Koreans",
				54,
				61,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Americans",
				138,
				147,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Moreover, the Koreans are competent jungle fighters--and are ready to fight.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Koreans",
				14,
				21,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Through program grants to the Chinese on Formosa, let them carry to Africa and parts of Asia, the program we have been burdened with: --technical assistance in agriculture primarily.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chinese",
				30,
				37,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Formosa",
				41,
				48,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Africa",
				68,
				74,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Asia",
				88,
				92,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The cost of doing this through Chinese instead of Americans is, again, a ratio of 3 to 1 to 5 to 1.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chinese",
				31,
				38,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Americans",
				50,
				59,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Moreover, the Chinese are competent agronomists--in the area of giving self-help to less developed countries, they can do the job at less cost and equal efficiency.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chinese",
				14,
				21,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Explanations 1.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Asians take the lead in Asian affairs.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Asians",
				0,
				6,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Asian",
				24,
				29,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "--It makes sense to put our money on Asian leaders who have already built their base as a democratic leader, and not have to prop up either a dictator, or a chief of government who is on shaky domestic ground.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Asian",
				37,
				42,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Marcos is no puppet.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Marcos",
				0,
				6,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In fact, he needs to be a little independent of us in order to make rational and credible his leadership.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "--Some of the people in the Manila Embassy are skeptical--as well they should be.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Manila Embassy",
				28,
				42,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Macapagal came into office with the same glittering hopes only to dash them with the usual ineptness later.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Macapagal",
				0,
				9,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "--Marcos could be different.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Marcos",
				2,
				8,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He's exceptionally bright (he set an all-time record for the bar exams); one of the most inspiring orators in Asia; and toughly realistic.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Asia",
				110,
				114,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I suspect he wants to be a great president, and is willing to do unpalatable things in order to achieve that greatness (i.e. stop smuggling and corruptness, as well as put his fiscal house in order).",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "--If",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "we can work with him, and give him what help we can within reason, Marcos could become a rallying point in Asia.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Marcos",
				67,
				73,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Asia",
				107,
				111,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "--In",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "any case, the problems of Asia must be solved by Asians, and Marcos has the gifts of brain and courage to do those things that need to be done, but which need an Asian cover to be done.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Asia",
				26,
				30,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Asians",
				49,
				55,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Marcos",
				61,
				67,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Asian",
				162,
				167,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Note: Marcos invited me and Lloyd Hand through his brother-in-law, Ben Romualdez (who possibly will be the closest man to him, and the one to whom he will listen with more credibility than any other) to play golf with him on his first day in office.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Marcos",
				6,
				12,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Lloyd Hand",
				28,
				38,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Ben Romualdez",
				67,
				80,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "We teed off at 6:30 am!",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "He obviously wanted to let me know his regard for President Johnson; and to emphasize his aims of putting the Philippines in apple-pie order.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President Johnson",
				50,
				67,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Philippines",
				110,
				121,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He is a professional politician, with all the sure-footed instincts of a pro.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "He mentioned he was going to re-organize the Army, establish the Constabulary (police force) as an independent arm (it is now part of the Defense Department); and try to bring fiscal order out of the wildly porous financial structure now existent.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Army",
				45,
				49,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Constabulary",
				65,
				77,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Defense Department",
				138,
				156,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Without being sychophantic he made it clear he wanted to cooperate with U.S. I recommend that we invite him to come to the States for an official visit sometime this year.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"U.S.",
				72,
				76,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"States",
				123,
				129,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Obviously he can't come right now, but sometime after June, he could be ready.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"June",
				54,
				58,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He never brought this up--but I find it persuasive that the President ought to size him up personally; take his measure so we can determine how and what we need to do to get leadership among non-communistic Asian nations.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"President",
				60,
				69,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Asian",
				207,
				212,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "[Here follows discussion of Korea, Taiwan, and Japan.]\"]",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Korea",
				28,
				33,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Taiwan",
				35,
				41,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Japan",
				47,
				52,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "['PRESENT Mr. Kissinger, Mr. Nutter, Mr. Johnson, Lt. Gen. Richard T. Knowles and Mr. Helms Colonel Richard T. Kennedy, Mr. Thomas Karamessines and Mr. William Broe were present for all items.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Kissinger",
				14,
				23,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Nutter",
				29,
				35,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Johnson",
				41,
				48,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Lt. Gen. Richard T. Knowles",
				50,
				77,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Helms",
				86,
				91,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Colonel Richard T. Kennedy",
				92,
				118,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Thomas Karamessines",
				124,
				143,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"William Broe",
				152,
				164,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Mr. Charles Meyer and Mr. Arnold Nachmanoff were present for Item 1.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Charles Meyer",
				4,
				17,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Arnold Nachmanoff",
				26,
				43,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Mr. John Holdridge was present for Item 2. 1.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"John Holdridge",
				4,
				18,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Chile a. Mr. Meyer briefed the Committee members on his visit to Chile for President Allende's inauguration and his conversations with Allende, Frei, Osso and numerous other Chileans and Latin Americans.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chile",
				0,
				5,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Meyer",
				13,
				18,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Committee",
				31,
				40,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Chile",
				65,
				70,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"President Allende",
				75,
				92,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Allende",
				135,
				142,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Frei",
				144,
				148,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Osso",
				150,
				154,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Chileans",
				174,
				182,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Latin Americans",
				187,
				202,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "b.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Mr. Meyer expressed his conviction that very few Chileans accurately evaluate the Allende threat to Chile--they believe that the \"Chilean character\" will somehow miraculously preclude a Marxist take-over of the country.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Meyer",
				4,
				9,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Chileans",
				49,
				57,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Allende",
				82,
				89,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Chile",
				100,
				105,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Chilean",
				130,
				137,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Marxist",
				186,
				193,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Because of Chilean abhorrence of Chileans fighting Chileans there is little likelihood of an attempt to remove Allende by force.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chilean",
				11,
				18,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Chileans",
				33,
				41,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Chileans",
				51,
				59,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Allende",
				111,
				118,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Any concept of a unified political opposition to Allende at the moment is virtually hopeless.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Allende",
				49,
				56,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The CDU is so badly split its factions cannot get together and there is no rock on which to build a solid political opposition.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"CDU",
				4,
				7,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "c.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Mr. Meyer stated that a unanimous view expressed to him by every Chilean and other Latin American with whom he spoke was that the U.S. should refrain from taking any hostile action against Allende for at least the traditional 100-day honeymoon period or Allende would immediately receive at least double the support he now has among Chileans.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Meyer",
				4,
				9,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Chilean",
				65,
				72,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Latin American",
				83,
				97,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"U.S.",
				130,
				134,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Allende",
				189,
				196,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Allende",
				254,
				261,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Chileans",
				333,
				341,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "To this, the Chairman observed that it would then appear advantageous to Allende to take steps designed to provoke a U.S. reaction against him and thus far he has carefully avoided doing so.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chairman",
				13,
				21,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Allende",
				73,
				80,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"U.S.",
				117,
				121,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "d.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Mr. Meyer noted that after a period of about 70 days any substantial exchanges of foreign funds for escudos will not be possible as controls will by then be too stringent.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Meyer",
				4,
				9,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Chairman suggested that prompt steps be taken to procure escudos for possible future expenditures in Chile and Mr. Broe responded that such acquisition has commenced.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chairman",
				4,
				12,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Chile",
				105,
				110,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Broe",
				119,
				123,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
