[
	{
		"content": "[\"[Telegram] 558.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Department's 511, October 25, 6 p.m. Foreign Office replies that the State Government states that in view of the fact that the treaties of surrender of Yaqui Indians in rebellion against the Constitutionalist Government are being terminated the tranquillity of the State has been uninterrupted.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Department",
				0,
				10,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"October 25",
				18,
				28,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"Foreign Office",
				37,
				51,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"State Government",
				69,
				85,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Yaqui Indians",
				152,
				165,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Constitutionalist Government",
				191,
				219,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"State",
				265,
				270,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "No mention is made of action contemplated to protect American property, notwithstanding the fact Foreign Office was requested most earnestly to reply in this sense in my representation.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"American",
				53,
				61,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Foreign Office",
				97,
				111,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Parker\"]",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Parker",
				0,
				6,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "['[Telegram] At Foreign Office this morning I was informed officially that Italy will remain neutral.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Foreign Office",
				16,
				30,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Italy",
				75,
				80,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The reason given is that her obligations only require her to support her allies for defense and not for aggression, also that she was not previously consulted by Austria.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Austria",
				162,
				169,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "A Cabinet council was held last night and fully approved policy of Minister for Foreign Affairs.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Cabinet",
				2,
				9,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Minister for Foreign Affairs",
				67,
				95,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "It is reported that exports of flour, meats, and other foods are to be prohibited.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "The Government by decree of yesterday ordered all stock exchanges in Italy closed until further notice.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Italy",
				69,
				74,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "No popular excitement here as yet.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "[File copy not signed]']",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "['ANALYTICAL SUMMARY Contingency Plan for Saudi Arabia [1 line not declassified], the contingency plan assumes that a \"radical\" takeover is unlikely.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Saudi Arabia",
				42,
				54,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In addition to internal forces working against rapid change, there is little evidence of outside interference or subversion.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "In addition, the geography of Saudi Arabia makes it difficult for conspirators to seize control of the country or its key power centers.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Saudi Arabia",
				30,
				42,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "A coup from within the armed forces cannot be ruled out, but would be difficult to mount unless the air force and airfields were controlled, since movement of troops over land would be difficult.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Possibly destabilizing factors might be the King's death and a struggle within the royal family for succession.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"King",
				44,
				48,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "A second source of pressure on the regime stems from the unresolved status of the Arab-Israeli dispute.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Arab-Israeli",
				82,
				94,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The most likely contingency for the US, according to the plan, is not a takeover by radical elements in Saudi Arabia, but rather the danger that the King himself, or his successors, will move against the US as a matter of survival in a deteriorating Arab-Israeli situation.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"US",
				36,
				38,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Saudi Arabia",
				104,
				116,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"King",
				149,
				153,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"US",
				204,
				206,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Arab-Israeli",
				250,
				262,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Interests and Roles of Outsiders Iran has an interest that nothing threaten shipping of oil in the Persian Gulf and that hostile forces not dominate the Arab side of the Gulf.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Iran",
				33,
				37,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Persian Gulf",
				99,
				111,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Arab",
				153,
				157,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Gulf",
				170,
				174,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "If either of these developments occurred, the Shah would consider the use of military force.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Shah",
				46,
				50,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Saudis would be reluctant to turn to Iran for direct military help except in extremis.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Saudis",
				4,
				10,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Iran",
				41,
				45,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Jordan is more likely to take direct steps to help an embattled Saudi regime, both because of Saudi preference for help from an Arab state and King Hussein's own motivation.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Jordan",
				0,
				6,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Saudi regime",
				64,
				76,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Saudi",
				94,
				99,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Arab",
				128,
				132,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"King Hussein",
				143,
				155,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "If Hussein were to act, he could come under military pressures from Iraq and Syria, which could best be offset by Iranian and Israeli forces.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Hussein",
				3,
				10,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Iraq",
				68,
				72,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Syria",
				77,
				82,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Iranian",
				114,
				121,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Israeli",
				126,
				133,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Soviet Union is unlikely to intervene directly in Saudi Arabia, both because of lack of capability and the political risks involved.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Soviet Union",
				4,
				16,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Saudi Arabia",
				54,
				66,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Egypt would probably stand aside in any future Saudi crisis, and Iraq, despite probable support for a radical regime, could be constrained from active intervention by Iranian force.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Egypt",
				0,
				5,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Saudi",
				47,
				52,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Iraq",
				65,
				69,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Iranian",
				167,
				174,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Neither Israel nor the Europeans could be expected to act decisively.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Israel",
				8,
				14,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Europeans",
				23,
				32,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Contingencies If current US efforts to bolster the regime and enhance its capabilities fail, we might face the following situations: Contingency 1.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"US",
				25,
				27,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Security within Saudi Arabia deteriorates, perhaps as a result of anti-regime feeling stimulated by a renewal of Arab-Israeli hostilities.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Saudi Arabia",
				16,
				28,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Arab-Israeli",
				113,
				125,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The US would consider the following courses of action: --Activate evacuation plan for 8000 US citizens.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"US",
				4,
				6,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"US",
				91,
				93,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Airborne brigade in Europe is prepared for movement to the Gulf.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Europe",
				20,
				26,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Gulf",
				59,
				63,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Carrier task force from Southeast Asia is ordered to proceed to Gulf.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Southeast Asia",
				24,
				38,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Gulf",
				64,
				68,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "--If",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Arab-Israeli conflict is related to disorders in Saudi Arabia, press for rapid ceasefire.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Arab-Israeli",
				0,
				12,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Saudi Arabia",
				49,
				61,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "--Consult with King Faisal on internal security situation and respond with pre-arranged package of military equipment if requested.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"King Faisal",
				15,
				26,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "--Talk to Jordanians and Iranians about joint actions in event situation continues to deteriorate.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Jordanians",
				10,
				20,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Iranians",
				25,
				33,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Contingency 2.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "A succession crisis following the King's death might lead to prolonged conflict, raising the likelihood of an army takeover.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"King",
				34,
				38,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Obvious successors such as Princes Fahd and Sultan might prove to be ineffective.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Princes Fahd",
				27,
				39,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Sultan",
				44,
				50,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In these circumstances we would consider the following: --A joint Jordanian-Iranian-US effort to restore order under a new regime headed by a group of the younger princes and with a broader role for the army.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Jordanian-Iranian-US",
				66,
				86,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "--Some non-provocative but visible military measures could be taken by Jordan, Iran and the US to pressure Saudis to restore order on terms we favor.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Jordan",
				71,
				77,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Iran",
				79,
				83,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"US",
				92,
				94,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Saudis",
				107,
				113,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Contingency 3.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "A partially successful coup might lead to civil war and outside intervention.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Rebels might be successful only in holding one sector of the country and could appeal to Iraq for help in the form of aircraft.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Iraq",
				89,
				93,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The United States might take the following actions: --Dispatch US forces to staging areas in preparation for a possible landing of forces in the eastern province to seize control of oil facilities and to evacuate US nationals.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"United States",
				4,
				17,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"US",
				63,
				65,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"US",
				213,
				215,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "--Consult with Shah on measures to deter Iraq.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Shah",
				15,
				19,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Iraq",
				41,
				45,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "--Warn the Soviets of the dangers of Iraqi intervention.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Soviets",
				11,
				18,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Iraqi",
				37,
				42,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "--Activate pre-arranged plan for Jordanian military intervention.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Jordanian",
				33,
				42,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The US would provide logistical backup for Jordan's effort.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"US",
				4,
				6,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Jordan",
				43,
				49,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Contingency 4.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "In a successful coup, radical elements from the army seize control of the country.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "The US would face the following actions: --Even in the absence of information about the new regime, pressures would build on us to move rapidly, before the regime could establish its credentials, to overthrow it.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"US",
				4,
				6,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "We would try to reach a judgment with Jordan and Iran on whether such a move was justified.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Jordan",
				38,
				44,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Iran",
				49,
				53,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "--If",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "so, Jordan would play the main role by trying to seize airfields within Saudi Arabia and then carrying out air strikes against key areas.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Jordan",
				4,
				10,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Saudi Arabia",
				72,
				84,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "--Iran could deter Iraq from intervening and Israel could play a role in restraining Syria from moving against Jordan.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"--Iran",
				0,
				6,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Iraq",
				19,
				23,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Israel",
				45,
				51,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Syria",
				85,
				90,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Jordan",
				111,
				117,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "General Observations and Issues for Discussion --A change of regime in Saudi Arabia will raise the question of whether to intervene, and in what form, to reverse the situation.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Saudi Arabia",
				71,
				83,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Pressures will be intense to act rapidly, without much knowledge of the existing situation.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Are the risks of delay greater than the risks of intervention?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Does intervention stand a chance of success or is it likely to fail?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "--Recognizing the dangers for US interests elsewhere in the Arab world if we were to intervene, the paper nonetheless suggests that the gains from a successful military intervention that resulted in a stable pro-Western regime staying in power would offset any losses elsewhere.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"US",
				30,
				32,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Arab",
				60,
				64,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"pro-Western",
				208,
				219,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "But do we or the Jordanians have the capabilities to intervene successfully unless a substantial body of Saudi opinion favors such an intervention?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Jordanians",
				17,
				27,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Saudi",
				105,
				110,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "--Are there dangers of intervening against a military coup that might bring to power moderate nationalist elements that we would be able to work with just as well as the present regime?",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Is a coup group bound to be radical and anti-American?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"anti-American",
				40,
				53,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "--While Jordanian intervention is probably the most politically viable in any future crisis, if Jordan alone is unable to reverse the situation, would it be preferable for the US or Iran to act then?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Jordanian",
				8,
				17,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Jordan",
				96,
				102,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"US",
				176,
				178,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Iran",
				182,
				186,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Granted that there would be drawbacks to either US or Iranian action in terms of branding the elements we help as traitors or puppets, would Iran's intervention cause fewer problems than our own?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"US",
				48,
				50,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Iranian",
				54,
				61,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Iran",
				141,
				145,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Could Iran both deter Iraq and intervene directly?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Iran",
				6,
				10,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Iraq",
				22,
				26,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Would the Soviets exert pressure on Iran in these circumstances?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Soviets",
				10,
				17,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Iran",
				36,
				40,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "US Military Assets The following forces could be used in Saudi Arabia:",
		"entities": [
			[
				"US Military",
				0,
				11,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Saudi Arabia",
				57,
				69,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "--One Airborne Brigade from Europe could reach Riyadh or Dhahran [timeframe not declassified] --One tactical fighter squadron could reach Saudi Arabia [timeframe not declassified] --US naval forces in the area (MIDEASTFOR) consist of two destroyers and one flagship.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Europe",
				28,
				34,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Riyadh",
				47,
				53,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Dhahran",
				57,
				64,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Saudi Arabia",
				138,
				150,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"--US naval forces",
				180,
				197,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "There is also one C-130 in the area.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"C-130",
				18,
				23,
				"PRODUCT"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "--A carrier task force could reach the Persian Gulf from Southeast Asia [timeframe not declassified] Further Refinements of the Plan --If Jordan and Iran will be required to play the key roles in any successful intervention against a radical regime in Saudi Arabia, we must clearly do some planning with them for such a contingency if joint action is to be possible.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Persian Gulf",
				39,
				51,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Southeast Asia",
				57,
				71,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Jordan",
				138,
				144,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Iran",
				149,
				153,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Saudi Arabia",
				252,
				264,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Can we engage in such talks without paying a price, both with Saudi Arabia if the news leaks, and with Jordan in terms of more aid to sustain Jordanian operations in a future Saudi contingency?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Saudi Arabia",
				62,
				74,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Jordan",
				103,
				109,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Jordanian",
				142,
				151,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Saudi",
				175,
				180,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "--What kind of pre-arranged equipment package could be put together from Jordanian and Iranian sources to deliver to Saudi Arabia for maximum impact?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Jordanian",
				73,
				82,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Iranian",
				87,
				94,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Saudi Arabia",
				117,
				129,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "--Can a US evacuation plan be devised that would also allow for a show of force and a securing of oil loading facilities at Ras Tanura to prevent sabotage?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"US",
				8,
				10,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Ras Tanura",
				124,
				134,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "--Could we count on British help in any of these contingencies?",
		"entities": [
			[
				"British",
				20,
				27,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "--One contingency not dealt with is the possibility that King Faisal becomes increasingly hostile to US interests, that Princes Fahd and Sultan try to restrain him, failing which they might seek to oust him, much as Faisal deposed Saud.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"King Faisal",
				57,
				68,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"US",
				101,
				103,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Princes Fahd",
				120,
				132,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Sultan",
				137,
				143,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Faisal",
				216,
				222,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Saud",
				231,
				235,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Would we be likely to become involved in such a struggle and, if so, how?']",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "['No. 1656",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Sir: Supplementing my despatch No. 1629 of the 30th ultimo, I have the honor to report as of today the following developments in relation to the flotation of the projected new federal loan.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"30th",
				47,
				51,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I have been privileged to see some of the confidential files of the Foreign Office in preparing this report.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Foreign Office",
				68,
				82,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "It became apparent upon the occasion of the meeting of the Relief Credit Committee in London on the 2nd instant, that Austrian official circles had been unduly optimistic and had underestimated some of the obstacles standing in their path.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Relief Credit Committee",
				59,
				82,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"London",
				86,
				92,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"2nd",
				100,
				103,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"Austrian",
				118,
				126,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "It there developed that the Dutch representative stated flatly that his government desired that some plan for the amortization of and payment of interest on the old relief credits be made as a condition precedent to any action on its part.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Dutch",
				28,
				33,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "This was just what Schuller wanted to avoid, as stated on page 3 of my despatch under reference.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Schuller",
				19,
				27,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "As an offset to this request, the bankers (Montagu Norman and Morgan were specifically mentioned) raised the contention that the Austrian Government could not be required to arrange for any relief credit settlement prior to 1943 when the long term reconstruction loan matures.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Montagu Norman",
				43,
				57,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Morgan",
				62,
				68,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Austrian Government",
				129,
				148,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"1943",
				224,
				228,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "It was asserted that an earlier settlement would contravene the announcement made in the bankers' prospectus at the time the loan just mentioned was floated in 1923, and that the prospectus was based upon the bond contract.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"1923",
				160,
				164,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I have examined the American prospectus, a copy of which I have in my files, and it does not seem to me to substantiate this contention.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"American",
				20,
				28,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Foreign Office tells me that this was also the opinion of the Austrian Government and Schuller so stated to the bankers, whereupon they replied that if an earlier settlement was not strictly against the letter of the reconstruction bond, it was against its spirit.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Foreign Office",
				4,
				18,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Austrian Government",
				66,
				85,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Schuller",
				90,
				98,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Inasmuch as the bankers' views quite naturally carry very great weight as intimated in the concluding paragraph of my before-mentioned despatch No. 1629, the predicament which arose was embarrassing.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Furthermore, one of the less influential opposition papers, \"Der Montag\", printed a sensational story on the 5th instant, which attracted some attention, to the effect that the loan had gone on the rocks, mainly because of the opposition of Czechoslovakia.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Der Montag",
				61,
				71,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"5th",
				109,
				112,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"Czechoslovakia",
				241,
				255,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In point of fact, Czechoslovakia is not interested in the relief credits, because it extended none.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Czechoslovakia",
				18,
				32,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Czech Minister here denies that his government is unfriendly.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Czech Minister",
				4,
				18,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "It is nevertheless true that the Austrians believe that the Czechs have been throwing cold water on the loan proposal.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Austrians",
				33,
				42,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Czechs",
				60,
				66,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Two reasons are given: first, it is said that the electrification of the railways is against Czech interests as it would make Austria less dependent upon Czech coal and, secondly, some proceeds of the new loan were to be devoted, it was announced, to the improvement of Austrian dairies, the Austrian market for milk from Southern Moravia thereby being lessened.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Czech",
				93,
				98,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Austria",
				126,
				133,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Czech",
				154,
				159,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Austrian",
				270,
				278,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Austrian",
				292,
				300,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Southern Moravia",
				322,
				338,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Italy's attitude also created some uneasiness.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Italy",
				0,
				5,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "(See in this connection my despatch No. 1655 of the 12th instant).",
		"entities": [
			[
				"12th",
				52,
				56,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Italian relief credit delegate suddenly left London for Rome for further instructions after the meeting on the 2nd.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Italian",
				4,
				11,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"London",
				49,
				55,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Rome",
				60,
				64,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"2nd",
				115,
				118,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Dr. Schuller advised his government from London of the situation and the Relief Credit Committee took an adjournment until Monday, the 12th.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Dr. Schuller",
				0,
				12,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"London",
				41,
				47,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Relief Credit Committee",
				73,
				96,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"12th",
				135,
				139,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The result of all this was that after a Cabinet council Schuller was instructed by telegram on Thursday, the 8th, to make a relief credit settlement proposal.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Cabinet council",
				40,
				55,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Schuller",
				56,
				64,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"8th",
				109,
				112,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The entire relief credits expressed in Austrian currency amount to 848,000,000 schillings.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Austrian",
				39,
				47,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "(This is approximately the equivalent of the PS25,000,000 mentioned on page 2 of my despatch No. 1629.)",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "The accrued interest on this amount from now in 1927 up to 1943, the before-mentioned date of maturity of the reconstruction loan, is figured at 152,000,000 schillings, making the total amount due in 1943 approximately 1,000 million schillings.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"1927",
				48,
				52,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"1943",
				59,
				63,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"1943",
				200,
				204,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Schuller was authorized to propose that beginning in 1943 the Austrian Government would undertake to pay the amount just mentioned in twenty-five annual instalments of 40,000,000 schillings each.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Schuller",
				0,
				8,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"1943",
				53,
				57,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"Austrian Government",
				62,
				81,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Austrian Government desires to reserve the right to pay, beginning in 1929 and up to 1943, something on account.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Austrian Government",
				4,
				23,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"1929",
				74,
				78,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"1943",
				89,
				93,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "It is provisionally proposed, if this right be utilized, to pay at first 10,000,000 schillings annually and subsequently 15,000,000 if the federal finances justify it.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "In the event payments are thus anticipated, interest at the rate of 8 per cent is to be deducted from the before-mentioned 1,000 million schillings due as of 1943.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"1943",
				158,
				162,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "It is figured out that the estimated interest of 152,000,000 schillings would be greatly reduced and of course the annual instalment beginning from 1943 would be substantially cut down.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"1943",
				148,
				152,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "As I have heretofore reported, the Austrian Government hopes ultimately to avoid paying interest on its relief credits, taking into account their intrinsic character.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Austrian Government",
				35,
				54,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I think there is some question however whether any advance payments will ever be made.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "It is hoped nevertheless, by a proposal of this kind, to meet the bankers' views.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "The Chancellor said to me significantly on Monday that the position of the bankers was helpful to his government.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"The Chancellor",
				0,
				14,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The fact that the Schuller telegram had been sent was communicated to me on the evening of the 8th by the Finance Minister, Kien-bock.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Schuller",
				18,
				26,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"8th",
				95,
				98,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"Finance Minister",
				106,
				122,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Kien-bock",
				124,
				133,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I promised however that I would not cable any statement of the situation, which was given me in the strictest confidence, and indeed there was no reason for doing so as it was anticipated that something definite would transpire at the adjourned Relief Credit Committee meeting on Monday, the 12th.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Relief Credit Committee",
				245,
				268,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"12th",
				292,
				296,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "This anticipation was realized.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "The Committee took cognizance of the relief credit settlement proposal as made by Schuller, and stated that it would be transmitted to the various governments represented on the Committee for action.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Committee",
				4,
				13,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Schuller",
				82,
				90,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Committee",
				178,
				187,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I expect to be able later to transmit the exact formula of this proposal; something, as I understand, that was left to Schuller's discretion.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Schuller",
				119,
				127,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Committee further passed a resolution authorizing the subordination to the projected new federal loan for a period of thirty years of the Austrian assets or securities pledged for the repayment of the relief credits.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Committee",
				4,
				13,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Austrian",
				142,
				150,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "This last action was taken by the Committee although the Dutch and Swiss delegates were without authority to vote affirmatively for the resolution.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Committee",
				34,
				43,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Dutch",
				57,
				62,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Swiss",
				67,
				72,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Committee apparently had reason to believe that the written assent of the Dutch and Swiss governments would be presently forthcoming. ...",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Committee",
				4,
				13,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Dutch",
				78,
				83,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Swiss governments",
				88,
				105,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Apparently the fear expressed to me by Dr. Kienbock that parliamentary assent of other countries than the United States might be found to be necessary, proved to be groundless.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Dr. Kienbock",
				39,
				51,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"United States",
				106,
				119,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The next step will be the proceedings before the Reparation Commission.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Reparation Commission",
				49,
				70,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "There has been some reason to apprehend that Rumania would seek to make action here contingent upon the settlement of some controversy which it has with Austria, but I am told that pressure has been brought to bear to keep the former country quiet.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Rumania",
				45,
				52,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Austria",
				153,
				160,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I have [etc.]",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Albert H. Washburn']",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Albert H. Washburn",
				0,
				18,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "[\"60.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "The Foreign Minister requested me to see him this morning.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Foreign Minister",
				4,
				20,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He wished to talk about the matters mentioned in the last paragraph of my telegram No. 58, January 19, 10 a.m. I had just come from an interview with Governor Mehaffey during which the Governor mentioned his preoccupation about the continued residence in the Tivoli of the group of opposition deputies and other Panamanians.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"January 19",
				91,
				101,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"Governor Mehaffey",
				150,
				167,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Governor",
				185,
				193,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Tivoli",
				259,
				265,
				"FAC"
			],
			[
				"Panamanians",
				312,
				323,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Foreign Minister stated that he was speaking informally and not making an official request.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Foreign Minister",
				4,
				20,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He said that he understood the opposition intended to send a spokesman to the Embassy to denounce the De La Guardia Government.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Embassy",
				78,
				85,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"De La Guardia",
				102,
				115,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He stated that it must be difficult and embarrassing to American officials to have the opposition group resident in the Canal Zone and he wondered how much longer rooms would be available at the Tivoli.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"American",
				56,
				64,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Canal Zone",
				120,
				130,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Tivoli",
				195,
				201,
				"FAC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I then explained the Embassy's attitude as set forth in the last paragraph of my telegram 58.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Embassy",
				21,
				28,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Foreign Minister said that the Panamanian Government appreciated this point of view.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Foreign Minister",
				4,
				20,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Panamanian Government",
				35,
				56,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "As concerns continued residence at the Tivoli I told the Minister that I had just discussed the question in general with Governor Mehaffey, that the latter would be in Washington next Monday and could discuss it further at the Department, but that in the meantime it seemed desirable to avoid any precipitate action that might aggravate the political situation.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Tivoli",
				39,
				45,
				"FAC"
			],
			[
				"Minister",
				57,
				65,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Governor Mehaffey",
				121,
				138,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Washington",
				168,
				178,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Department",
				227,
				237,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I promised to telegraph the Department and to let the Minister have any comment which Washington might make either before or after conferring with Governor Mehaffey when the latter reaches Washington.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Department",
				28,
				38,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Minister",
				54,
				62,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Washington",
				86,
				96,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Governor Mehaffey",
				147,
				164,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Washington",
				189,
				199,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Minister again expressed his appreciation.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Minister",
				4,
				12,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I believe that Governor Mehaffey agrees with me that it would be desirable if some means could be found in the comparatively near future to inform the group at the Tivoli that accommodations no longer are available.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Governor Mehaffey",
				15,
				32,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Tivoli",
				164,
				170,
				"FAC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Foreign Minister told me this morning that warrants for the arrest of Deputy Vega and four others who are not deputies have been issued by the District Attorney on criminal charges.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Foreign Minister",
				4,
				20,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Deputy Vega",
				74,
				85,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"District Attorney",
				147,
				164,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I reminded the Minister of the talk which Ambassador Warren had had with President De la Guardia.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Minister",
				15,
				23,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Ambassador Warren",
				42,
				59,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"President De la Guardia",
				73,
				96,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Minister stated categorically that the Government was not taking any political action against the group now at the Tivoli and emphasized that the charges against Vega and the four others are criminal charges.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Minister",
				4,
				12,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"Tivoli",
				119,
				125,
				"FAC"
			],
			[
				"Vega",
				166,
				170,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He stated that these charges still are under investigation and that no final decision has been taken although the warrants of arrest do exist.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "He stated that there is absolutely no reason why Duncan and the others could not return to Panama without danger of action against them on the part of the Government.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Duncan",
				49,
				55,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Panama",
				91,
				97,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Governor Mehaffey has been informed of the foregoing.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Governor Mehaffey",
				0,
				17,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "As I left the Foreign Minister's office I met former Foreign Minister Lewis.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Foreign Minister",
				14,
				30,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Foreign Minister Lewis",
				53,
				75,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He apparently is being consulted on foreign affairs and I believe he still is supporting the De la Guardia Government.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"De la Guardia",
				93,
				106,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He told Governor Mehaffey last night that if Ambassador Jimenez resigns he Lewis still is on the list as possible Ambassador to the United States.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Governor Mehaffey",
				8,
				25,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Ambassador Jimenez",
				45,
				63,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Lewis",
				75,
				80,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Ambassador to the United States",
				114,
				145,
				"TITLE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Butler\"]",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Butler",
				0,
				6,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "['349.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Recent difficulties between Persian Gulf Command railway service and Iranian Ministry of Communications have again brought out uncertainty of position of our military forces vis-a-vis Iranian Government, in absence of any formal agreement covering presence of American troops in Iran.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Persian Gulf Command",
				28,
				48,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Iranian Ministry of Communications",
				69,
				103,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Iranian Government",
				184,
				202,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"American",
				260,
				268,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Iran",
				279,
				283,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "It would be appreciated if the Department would inform the Legation whether any progress being made in negotiation of such an agreement.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Department",
				31,
				41,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Legation",
				59,
				67,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Ford']",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Ford",
				0,
				4,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "['47.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "House of Representatives approved Greek Debt Settlement today.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"House of Representatives",
				0,
				24,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Greek",
				34,
				39,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Senate action expected shortly.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Senate",
				0,
				6,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Kellogg']",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Kellogg",
				0,
				7,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "['PARTICIPANTS Zentaro Kosaka, Former Japanese Foreign Minister Kazuo Chiba, First Secretary, Embassy of Japan The Secretary Richard L. Sneider, Country Director for Japan At the invitation of the Secretary Mr. Kosaka reviewed the impressions gained from his trip to Communist China.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Zentaro Kosaka",
				15,
				29,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Former Japanese Foreign Minister",
				31,
				63,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"Kazuo Chiba",
				64,
				75,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"First Secretary",
				77,
				92,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"Embassy of Japan",
				94,
				110,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Secretary",
				115,
				124,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Richard L. Sneider",
				125,
				143,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Country Director for Japan",
				145,
				171,
				"TITLE"
			],
			[
				"Secretary",
				197,
				206,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Kosaka",
				211,
				217,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Communist China",
				267,
				282,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Mr. Kosaka first explained that his trip to Communist China was an effort to wrest contacts with Communist China from Japanese leftwing control.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Kosaka",
				4,
				10,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Communist China",
				44,
				59,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Communist China",
				97,
				112,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Japanese",
				118,
				126,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Kosaka said that he had told Chen Yi he was pro-American and gained more respect from Chen Yi.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Kosaka",
				0,
				6,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Chen Yi",
				29,
				36,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"pro-American",
				44,
				56,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Chen Yi",
				86,
				93,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He also told Chinese leaders that the US had no intention of bombing Communist China to which Chen Yi agreed.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chinese",
				13,
				20,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"US",
				38,
				40,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Communist China",
				69,
				84,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Chen Yi",
				94,
				101,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He felt that the Chinese Communist top leadership wanted its views transmitted to the US and therefore he has made his trip to Washington.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chinese Communist",
				17,
				34,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"US",
				86,
				88,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Washington",
				127,
				137,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Basically his objective is, as a representative of the Free World, to try to make Communist China open its door to the Free World.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Free World",
				55,
				65,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Communist China",
				82,
				97,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Free World",
				119,
				129,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Mr. Kosaka then reviewed his major observations on Communist China, as follows: The \"cultural revolution\" has excluded rational thinking, eliminated able men, and reflects the senility of Mao.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Kosaka",
				4,
				10,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Communist China",
				51,
				66,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Mao",
				188,
				191,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The young generation is being force-fed Mao's thoughts and there is no feedback of the popular views to the highest level.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Mao",
				40,
				43,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Mao's objective is to divide his friends from his enemies, i.e. those accused of being pro-American, bourgeois elements and pro-Soviet revisionists.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Mao",
				0,
				3,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"pro-American",
				87,
				99,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"pro-Soviet",
				124,
				134,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The success of Mao's effort depends on an increase of agricultural production to meet rising population.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Mao",
				15,
				18,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Mao is seeking to spread his cult to agricultural areas through the Red Guard movement which is pushing for the abolition of private plots and reinstitution of communes.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Mao",
				0,
				3,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Red Guard",
				68,
				77,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "However, the farmers are apathetic and Kosaka felt that the abolition of private plots is not possible.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Kosaka",
				39,
				45,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He found that there are only about 120 million hectares of arable land, approximately one hectare per farm family.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Farm income is low with a family of 5 to 6 earning from $208 to $416 annually.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "In comparison industrial workers earn $300 per worker annually.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "At the same time costs of bicycles, $50, and TV sets, $200, are out of the range of farm families.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Clothing is available but coarse.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "The Chinese leadership to meet agricultural discontent compares farm living stand-ards today with those of 17 years ago rather than with those of other comparable areas in the Free World at the present time.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chinese",
				4,
				11,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Free World",
				176,
				186,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Generally, Chinese people have enough to eat, more schooling and free medical care which is an improvement over the pre-Communist period.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chinese",
				11,
				18,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Chinese leadership claims that agricultural production will increase this year and has offered to export cotton and rice to Japan.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chinese",
				0,
				7,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Japan",
				124,
				129,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Kosaka mentioned that there is a discrepancy between Hong Kong estimates of Chinese Communist agricultural production of 175 million tons and Communist China's estimates of 200 million tons.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Kosaka",
				0,
				6,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Hong Kong",
				53,
				62,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Chinese Communist",
				76,
				93,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Communist China",
				142,
				157,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Kosaka expressed doubts about production increases because the extensive movement of the Red Guard on Chinese railroads has disrupted transportation.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Kosaka",
				0,
				6,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Red Guard",
				89,
				98,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Chinese",
				102,
				109,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "After the crop comes in he expects this will be the basis for criticism of the Mao leadership.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Mao",
				79,
				82,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Chinese recognize that they are now underdeveloped and talk in of terms [of] needing 20-30 years to become a developed economy.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chinese",
				4,
				11,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Chinese higher education is now undergoing significant changes.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chinese",
				0,
				7,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The universities and higher schools are closed until next February and there are plans to shorten the school year and eliminate entrance exams.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"February",
				58,
				66,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In the future only students with clear-cut revolutionary background will be admitted to the top universities, with the result of eliminating some of the best students and a general lowering of academic standards.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Kosaka concluded by saying that the key problem of Communist China is when will the current contradictions come into the open.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Kosaka",
				0,
				6,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Communist China",
				51,
				66,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Chinese leadership says that they will not but Kosaka anticipates that the farmers will be disillusioned after the harvest and maybe cause a basic showdown.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chinese",
				4,
				11,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Kosaka",
				51,
				57,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He felt that it was important to let the Chinese see the progress occurring outside Communist China and open Chinese eyes.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Chinese",
				41,
				48,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Communist China",
				84,
				99,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Chinese",
				109,
				116,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He asked whether there was anything the Secretary wished him to convey to Chinese leadership since Liao Ch'eng-chih, head of the Chinese Communist trade office, offered to convey any message in the utmost secrecy.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Secretary",
				40,
				49,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Chinese",
				74,
				81,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Liao Ch'eng-chih",
				99,
				115,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Chinese Communist",
				129,
				146,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"trade office",
				147,
				159,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Secretary then questioned Kosaka on other aspects of Chinese Communist developments.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Secretary",
				4,
				13,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Kosaka",
				30,
				36,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Chinese Communist",
				57,
				74,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Kosaka mentioned that he had contact with the Red Guards at the Peking secondary school.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Kosaka",
				0,
				6,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Red Guards",
				46,
				56,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Peking",
				64,
				70,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He found them young and very articulate but they all talked the same language.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "When he asked them why the Red Guards had been formed and the Young Communist League not utilized, they replied that the YCL was \"old people\" while the Red Guard was more militant and class conscious.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Red Guards",
				27,
				37,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Young Communist League",
				62,
				84,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"YCL",
				121,
				124,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Red Guard",
				152,
				161,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In response to the Secretary's inquiry about Kosaka's impressions on the internal leadership struggle, Kosaka said that as long as Mao is alive the opposition forces in the Communist Party will be suppressed but they are strong and the struggle will continue.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Secretary",
				19,
				28,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Kosaka",
				45,
				51,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Kosaka",
				103,
				109,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Mao",
				131,
				134,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Communist Party",
				173,
				188,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He mentioned that he had tried to see Lin Piao but was advised that Lin as a military man saw no foreigners.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Lin Piao",
				38,
				46,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Lin",
				68,
				71,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Kosaka mentioned that Chou had stressed Chinese Communist peaceful intentions to the U.S.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Kosaka",
				0,
				6,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Chou",
				22,
				26,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Chinese Communist",
				40,
				57,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"U.S.",
				85,
				89,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "but there were two differences between the countries: (1) the U.S. refused to recognize the five principles; and (2) the U.S. refused to withdraw from Taiwan and the Taiwan Straits.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"U.S.",
				62,
				66,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"U.S.",
				121,
				125,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Taiwan",
				151,
				157,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Taiwan Straits",
				166,
				180,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The Secretary said that at Warsaw the Chinese Communists had continually maintained the position that there was nothing to discuss until we surrendered Formosa which the U.S. was not prepared to do.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Secretary",
				4,
				13,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Warsaw",
				27,
				33,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Chinese Communists",
				38,
				56,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Formosa",
				152,
				159,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"U.S.",
				170,
				174,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "On Sino-Japanese relations, Kosaka said that the Chinese Communists accepted the present relationship with non-governmental trade and cultural ties and no diplomatic relations.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Sino-Japanese",
				3,
				16,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Kosaka",
				28,
				34,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Chinese Communists",
				49,
				67,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "They expressed opposition to Sato but praise for Ikeda and they are evidently trying to split the Liberal Democratic Party.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Sato",
				29,
				33,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Ikeda",
				49,
				54,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Liberal Democratic Party",
				98,
				122,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In response to a question by the Secretary, Kosaka said that there were no Japanese government officials in Peking but there is a Liao-Takasaki trade office there and one official who had resigned from the government.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Secretary",
				33,
				42,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Kosaka",
				44,
				50,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Japanese",
				75,
				83,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Peking",
				108,
				114,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Liao-Takasaki",
				130,
				143,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He mentioned in passing that the Liao-Takasaki trade negotiations on the renewal of the Liao-Takasaki trade agreement had broken down recently due to the Chinese insistence that the Japanese buy more rice.']",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Liao-Takasaki",
				33,
				46,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Liao-Takasaki trade agreement",
				88,
				101,
				"LAW"
			],
			[
				"Chinese",
				154,
				161,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Japanese",
				182,
				190,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "['secret 1122.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "UK Emb has asked our views on a US-UK approach to Fr re Fr intentions on determination of final status of Saar.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"UK Emb",
				0,
				6,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"US-UK",
				32,
				37,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Fr",
				50,
				52,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Fr",
				56,
				58,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Saar",
				106,
				110,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "UK proposed making parallel not joint approach through our Embs in Paris.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"UK",
				0,
				2,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Embs",
				59,
				63,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Paris",
				67,
				72,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "We have replied that we wld be agreeable to transmitting an aide-memoire covering fol main points: 1.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Reiteration of our support for Saar's interim status, 2.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Saar",
				31,
				35,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Our concern over harmful effects this question on common relations of 3 Occupying Powers with Ger, 3.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Ger",
				94,
				97,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Recalling our past efforts to minimize these effects by asking both Fr and Gers to avoid actions and statements re Saar which wld prejudice agreement on projects of paramount importance (e.g. Schuman Plan and European integration), 4.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Fr",
				68,
				70,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Gers",
				75,
				79,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Saar",
				115,
				119,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Schuman Plan",
				192,
				199,
				"LAW"
			],
			[
				"European",
				209,
				217,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Our conviction that sooner this stumbling block can be removed by a definitive determination of status of Saar better, and 5.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Saar",
				106,
				110,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Finally, after noting reference to determination of final status of Saar in a \"peace treaty or other treaty\" in Schuman-Adenauer exchange of letters at time of signature of Schuman Plan, an inquiry as to what Fr have in mind in this respect.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Saar",
				68,
				72,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Schuman-Adenauer",
				112,
				128,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Schuman Plan",
				173,
				185,
				"LAW"
			],
			[
				"Fr",
				209,
				211,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "We agreed that approach shld be made through our Paris Emb.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Paris Emb",
				49,
				58,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "We raised question, however, whether preferable for both or just one actually approach Fr.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Fr",
				87,
				89,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "As regards timing, we prefer to avoid injecting Saar issue into Sep Fon Mins talks and suggested, that presentation of aide-memoire shld be timed with that in mind.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Saar",
				48,
				52,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Fon Mins",
				68,
				76,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "On other hand if Schuman shld raise it in some connection, it might be most effective to have Secy and Morrison themselves comment along above lines.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Schuman",
				17,
				24,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Secy",
				94,
				98,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Morrison",
				103,
				111,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Request ur comments.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Acheson']",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Acheson",
				0,
				7,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "['top secretniact 3355.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Noforn.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Eyes only Secretary and Byroade.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Secretary",
				10,
				19,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Byroade",
				24,
				31,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "During my conversation with Mosadeq this evening he stated that (Embtel 3354, repeated London 1089, February 23) British were intriguing in numerous ways to bring about overthrow of his government and at same time were pretending to United States Government that they desired settlement oil problem.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Mosadeq",
				28,
				35,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Embtel 3354",
				65,
				76,
				"WORK_OF_ART"
			],
			[
				"London 1089",
				87,
				98,
				"WORK_OF_ART"
			],
			[
				"February 23",
				100,
				111,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"British",
				113,
				120,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United States Government",
				233,
				257,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "British did not really want to come to agreement with him re oil.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"British",
				0,
				7,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "This was clear from terms of their last proposal to him.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "If they really wanted agreement they would not have incorporated in compensation agreement draft terms reference provision for determination of compensation in accordance with principles of British coal national law after he had made it clear that he could not accept terms reference so worded.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"British",
				190,
				197,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I told him I had reason believe that British proposals were in good faith and that they regarded them with utmost seriousness.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"British",
				37,
				44,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I had already pointed out in our last conversation that he had been first to suggest basing of compensation on provisions of some British national law.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"British",
				130,
				137,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Prime Minister extracted alternate compensation agreement from his papers.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Prime Minister",
				0,
				14,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "He asked if in my opinion British would accept terms reference reading as follows: \"To determine the sum required to provide compensation to the company as result of the Iranian oil nationalization laws of March and May 1951\".",
		"entities": [
			[
				"British",
				26,
				33,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Iranian",
				170,
				177,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"March",
				206,
				211,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"May 1951",
				216,
				224,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I said my instructions were to effect that no substantive change could be accepted in text as proposed.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "He stated that nevertheless he would like to have my personal opinion as to whether British would accept compensation agreement of type proposed by them with this one change.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"British",
				84,
				91,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I repeated I unable to answer that question; my instructions were that there could be no substantive changes.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "He said that he did not know as yet what his advisers might recommend but it might be useful for him have answer to this question.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "I asked if I was to understand that two documents which I handed him would be agreeable to him if terms reference would be altered along lines of his inquiry.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "He said he could make no commitments but he would like have answer to question which he had just proposed.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "He did not want to suggest to his advisers that Iran accept these two documents subject to change this kind because British after turning down such counterproposal could say that he had practically agreed to their proposals and would use this argument to prevail on successor government to accept their wording of terms reference.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Iran",
				48,
				52,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"British",
				116,
				123,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I told him that it was difficult for me on purely hypothetical basis to obtain answer to question this kind particularly in view of my instructions.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "I leave to Department's discretion whether query which Mosadeq has put to me should be passed on to British.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Department",
				11,
				21,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Mosadeq",
				55,
				62,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"British",
				100,
				107,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "It seems to me rather doubtful that acceptance or rejection of proposal should hinge on answer; nevertheless, if it should so transpire that Mosadeq should tell me later that he would accept proposals in case I could assure him that British would be agreeable to such change it might be helpful to me to know what to say.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Mosadeq",
				141,
				148,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"British",
				233,
				240,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Mosadeq does not know I informing Department re his inquiry which he stressed was of personal nature.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Mosadeq",
				0,
				7,
				"PERSON"
			],
			[
				"Department",
				34,
				44,
				"ORG"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I obtained impression from my talk that in spite of Mosadeq's inquiry there is really little likelihood that answer to our proposals will furnish basis for continuance conversations.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Mosadeq",
				52,
				59,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Henderson']",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Henderson",
				0,
				9,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "[\" [Telegram] London , undated.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"London",
				14,
				20,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "[Received February 12, 1915, noon. ] 1627.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"February 12, 1915",
				10,
				27,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "My 1626.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Foreign Office, February 10, 1915.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Foreign Office",
				0,
				14,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"February 10, 1915",
				16,
				33,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Your Excellency:",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Your Excellency",
				0,
				15,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Your excellency has already received the preliminary answer which I handed to you on the 7th January, in reply to your note of the 28th December, on the subject of seizures and detentions of American cargoes destined for neutral European ports.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"7th January",
				89,
				100,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"28th December",
				131,
				144,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"American",
				191,
				199,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"European",
				229,
				237,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Since that date I have had further opportunity of examining into the trade statistics of the United States as embodied in the customs returns, in order to see whether the belligerent action of Great Britain has been in any way the cause of the trade depression which your excellency describes as existing in the United States, and also whether the seizures of vessels or cargoes which have been made by the British Navy have inflicted any loss on American owners for which our existing machinery provides no means of redress.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"United States",
				93,
				106,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Great Britain",
				193,
				206,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United States",
				312,
				325,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"British Navy",
				407,
				419,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"American",
				447,
				455,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In setting out the results of my investigation I think it well to take the opportunity of giving a general review of the methods employed by His Majesty's Government to intercept contraband trade with the enemy, of their consistency with the admitted right of a belligerent to intercept such trade, and also of the extent to which they have endeavoured to meet the representations and complaints from time to time addressed to them on behalf of the United States Government.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"His Majesty's Government",
				141,
				165,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United States Government",
				449,
				473,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Towards the close of your note of the 28th December your excellency describes the situation produced by the action of Great Britain as a critical one to the commercial interests of the United States, and said that many of the great industries of the country were suffering because their products were denied long-established markets in neutral European countries contiguous to the nations at war.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"28th December",
				38,
				51,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"Great Britain",
				118,
				131,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United States",
				185,
				198,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"European",
				344,
				352,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "It is unfortunately true that in these days, when trade and finance are cosmopolitan, any war--particularly a war of any magnitude--must result in a grievous dislocation of commerce, including that of the nations which take no part in the war.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Your excellency will realize that in this tremendous struggle, for the outbreak of which Great Britain is in no way responsible, it is impossible for the trade of any country to escape all injury and loss, but for such His Majesty's Government are not to blame.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Great Britain",
				89,
				102,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"His Majesty's Government",
				219,
				243,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I do not understand the paragraph which I have quoted from your excellency's note as referring to these indirect consequences of the state of war, but to the more proximate and direct effect of our belligerent action in dealing with neutral ships and cargoes on the high seas.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Such action has been limited to vessels on their way to enemy ports or ports in neutral countries adjacent to the theatre of war, because it is only through such ports that the enemy introduces the supplies which he requires for carrying on the war.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "In my earlier note I set out the number of ships which had sailed from the United States for Holland, Denmark, Norway, Sweden, and Italy, and I there stated that only 8 of the 773 had been placed in the prize court, and that only 45 had been temporarily detained to enable particular consignments of cargo to be discharged for the purpose of prize-court proceedings.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"United States",
				75,
				88,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Holland",
				93,
				100,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Denmark",
				102,
				109,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Norway",
				111,
				117,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Sweden",
				119,
				125,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Italy",
				131,
				136,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "To measure the effect of such naval action it is necessary to take into consideration the general statistics of the export trade of the United States during the months preceding the outbreak of war and those since the outbreak.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"United States",
				136,
				149,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Taking the figures in millions of dollars, the exports of merchandise from the United States for the seven months of January to July 1914, inclusive, were 1,201, as compared with 1,327 in the corresponding months of 1913, a drop of 126 millions of dollars.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"United States",
				79,
				92,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"January",
				117,
				124,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"July 1914",
				128,
				137,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"1913",
				216,
				220,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "For the months of August, September, October, and November, that is to say, for the four months of the war preceding the delivery of your excellency's note, the figures of the exports of merchandise were (again in millions of dollars) 667 as compared with 923 in the corresponding months of 1913, a drop of 256 millions of dollars.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"August",
				18,
				24,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"September",
				26,
				35,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"October",
				37,
				44,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"November",
				50,
				58,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"1913",
				291,
				295,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "If, however, the single article of cotton be eliminated from the comparison, the figures show a very different result.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Thus the exports of all articles of merchandise other than cotton from the United States during the first seven months of 1914 were 966 millions of dollars as against 1,127 millions in 1913, a drop of 161 millions of dollars, or 141/2 per cent.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"United States",
				75,
				88,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"1914",
				122,
				126,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"1913",
				185,
				189,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "On the other hand, the exports of the same articles during the months August to November amounted to 608 millions of dollars as compared with 630 millions in 1913, a drop of 22 millions, or less than 4 per cent.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"August to November",
				70,
				88,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"1913",
				158,
				162,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "It is therefore clear that, if cotton be excluded, the effect of the war has been not to increase but practically to arrest the decline of American exports which was in progress earlier in the year.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"American",
				139,
				147,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In fact, any decrease in American exports which is attributed to the war is essentially due to cotton.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"American",
				25,
				33,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Cotton is an article which can not possibly have been affected by the exercise of our belligerent rights, for, as your excellency is aware, it has not been declared by His Majesty's Government to be contraband of war, and the rules under which we are at present conducting our belligerent operations give us no power in the absence of a blockade to seize or interfere with it when on its way to a belligerent country in neutral ships.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"His Majesty's Government",
				168,
				192,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Consequently no cotton has been touched.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Into the causes of the decrease in the exports of cotton I do not feel that there is any need for me to enter, because, whatever may have been the cause, it is not to be found in the exercise of the belligerent rights of visitation, search, and capture, or in our general right when at war to intercept the contraband trade of our enemy.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Imports of cotton to the United Kingdom fell as heavily as those to other countries.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"United Kingdom",
				25,
				39,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "No place felt the outbreak of war more acutely than the cotton districts of Lancashire, where for a time an immense number of spindles were idle.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Lancashire",
				76,
				86,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Though this condition has now to a large extent passed away, the consumption of the raw material in Great Britain was temporarily much diminished.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Great Britain",
				100,
				113,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The same is no doubt true of France.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"France",
				29,
				35,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The general result is to show convincingly that the naval operations of Great Britain are not the cause of any diminution in the volume of American exports, and that if the commerce of the United States is in the unfavourable condition which your excellency describes, the cause ought in fairness to be sought elsewhere than in the activities of His Majesty's naval forces.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Great Britain",
				72,
				85,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"American",
				139,
				147,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"United States",
				189,
				202,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"His Majesty",
				346,
				357,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I may add that the circular issued by the Department of Commerce at Washington on the 23d January admits a marked improvement in the foreign trade of the United States of America, which we have noted with great satisfaction.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Department of Commerce",
				42,
				64,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Washington",
				68,
				78,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"23d January",
				86,
				97,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"United States of America",
				154,
				178,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The first paragraph of the circular is worth quoting verbatim: A marked improvement in our foreign trade is indicated by the latest reports issued by the Department of Commerce through its Bureau of foreign and Domestic Commerce, sales of foodstuffs and certain lines of manufactures having been unusually large in November, the latest period for which detailed information is at hand.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Department of Commerce",
				154,
				176,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"Bureau of foreign and Domestic Commerce",
				189,
				228,
				"ORG"
			],
			[
				"November",
				315,
				323,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In that month exports aggregated $206,000,000, or double the total for August last, when, by reason of the outbreak of war, our foreign trade fell to the lowest level reached in many years.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"August",
				71,
				77,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In December there was further improvement, the month's exports being valued at $246,000,000, compared with $233,000,000 in December 1913, and within $4,000,000 of the high record established in December 1912.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"December",
				3,
				11,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"December 1913",
				123,
				136,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"December 1912",
				194,
				207,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "A better view of the situation is obtained by looking at these figures month by month.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "The exports of merchandise for the last five months have been (in millions of dollars): August 110 September 156 October 194 November 205 December 246",
		"entities": [
			[
				"August",
				88,
				94,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"September",
				99,
				108,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"October",
				113,
				120,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"November",
				125,
				133,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"December",
				138,
				146,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The outbreak of war produced in the United States, as it did in all neutral countries, an acute but temporary disturbance of trade.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"United States",
				36,
				49,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Since that time there seems to have been a steady recovery, for to-day the exports from the United States stand at a higher figure than on the same date last year.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"United States",
				92,
				105,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Before passing away from the statistics of trade, and in order to demonstrate still more clearly, if necessary, that the naval operations of Great Britain and her allies have had no detrimental effect on the volume of trade between the United States and neutral countries, it is worth while to analyse the figures of the exports to Europe since the outbreak of hostilities.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Great Britain",
				141,
				154,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United States",
				236,
				249,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Europe",
				332,
				338,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "For this purpose the European countries ought to be grouped under three heads: Great Britain and those fighting with her, neutral countries, and enemy countries.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"European",
				21,
				29,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Great Britain",
				79,
				92,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "It is, however, impossible for me to group the countries in this way satisfactorily, as the figures relating to the export trade of the United States with each country have not yet been published.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"United States",
				136,
				149,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In the preliminary statement of the export trade of the United States with foreign countries only principal countries are shown, and various countries which are tabulated separately in the more detailed monthly summary of commerce and finance are omitted.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"United States",
				56,
				69,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Those omitted include not only the Scandinavian countries, the exports to which are of peculiar importance in dealing with this question, but also Austria.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Scandinavian",
				35,
				47,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"Austria",
				147,
				154,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "So far as it is possible to distribute the figures under the headings which I have indicated above (all the figures being given in thousands of dollars)",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "the results are as follows: Total exports to Europe from the 1st August to the 30th November, 413,995, as against 597,342 [in 1913].",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Europe",
				45,
				51,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"1st August",
				61,
				71,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"30th November",
				79,
				92,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"1913",
				126,
				130,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Of these, Great Britain and her allies took 285,312, as against 316,805 in 1913; Germany and Belgium took 1,881 as against 177,136 in 1913; whereas neutral countries (among which Austria-Hungary is unavoidably included) took 123,802, as against 103,401 in 1913.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Great Britain",
				10,
				23,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"1913",
				75,
				79,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"Germany",
				81,
				88,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Belgium",
				93,
				100,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"1913",
				134,
				138,
				"DATE"
			],
			[
				"Austria-Hungary",
				179,
				194,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"1913",
				256,
				260,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The general complaint in your excellency's note was that the action of Great Britain was affecting adversely the trade of the United States with neutral countries.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Great Britain",
				71,
				84,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United States",
				126,
				139,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The naval operations of Great Britain certainly do not interfere with commerce from the United States on its way to the United Kingdom and the allied countries, and yet the exports to Great Britain and her allies during those four months diminished to the extent of over $28,000,000, whereas those to neutral countries and Austria increased by over $20,000,000.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Great Britain",
				24,
				37,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United States",
				88,
				101,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United Kingdom",
				120,
				134,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Great Britain",
				184,
				197,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Austria",
				323,
				330,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The inference may fairly be drawn from these figures, all of which are taken from the official returns published by the United States Government, that not only has the trade of the United States with the neutral countries in Europe been maintained as compared with previous years, but also that a substantial part of this trade was, in fact, trade intended for the enemy countries going through neutral ports by routes to which it was previously unaccustomed.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"United States Government",
				120,
				144,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United States",
				181,
				194,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Europe",
				225,
				231,
				"LOC"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "One of the many inconveniences to which this great war is exposing the commerce of all neutral countries is undoubtedly the serious shortage in shipping available for ocean transport, and the consequential result of excessive freights.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "It cannot fairly be said that this shortage is caused by Great Britain's interference with neutral ships.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Great Britain",
				57,
				70,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "At the present time there are only seven neutral vessels awaiting adjudication in the prize courts in this country, and three in those in the British dominions.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"British",
				142,
				149,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "As your excellency is aware, I have already instructed our ambassador at Washington to remind the parties who are interested in all these vessels that it is open to them to apply to the court for the release of these ships on bail, and if an application of this sort is made by them it is not likely to be opposed by the Grown.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Washington",
				73,
				83,
				"LOC"
			],
			[
				"Grown",
				321,
				326,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "There is therefore no reason why such an application should not be favourably entertained by the court, and, if acceded to, all these vessels will again be available for the carriage of commerce.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Only one neutral vessel is now detained in this country in addition to those awaiting adjudication in the prize court.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Every effort has been made in cases in which it has been found necessary to institute proceedings against portions of the cargo to secure the speedy discharge of the cargo and the release of the shipment, so as to enable it to resume work.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Great Britain is suffering from the shortage of shipping and the rise in freights as acutely as, if not more than, other nations and His Majesty's Government have taken every step that they could consistently with their belligerent interests to increase the tonnage available for the transport of sea-borne commerce.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Great Britain",
				0,
				13,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"His Majesty's Government",
				133,
				157,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The enemy ships which have been condemned in the prize courts in this country are being sold as rapidly as possible in order that they may become available for use; and those which have been condemned in the prize courts oversea are being brought to this country in order that they may be disposed of here, and again placed in active employment.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "The difficulties have been accentuated by the unforeseen consequences of the convention which was signed at The Hague in 1907 relative to the status of enemy merchant vessels at the outbreak of war.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Hague",
				112,
				117,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"1907",
				121,
				125,
				"DATE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "This convention was a well-intentioned effort to diminish the losses which war must impose upon innocent persons, and provided that enemy merchant ships seized by a belligerent in whose ports they lay at the outbreak of war should not be condemned, but should merely be detained for the period of the war, unless they were liberated in the days of grace.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "We could come to no arrangement with the German Government for the reciprocal grant of days of grace, and the German merchant vessels lying in British ports when the war broke out have therefore been sentenced to detention in lieu of condemnation.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"German Government",
				41,
				58,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"German",
				110,
				116,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"British",
				143,
				150,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The normal result would have been still further to reduce the volume of shipping available for the commerce of the world.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "To ease the situation, however, His Majesty's Government are resorting to the power of requisitioning which is given by the convention, so that these ships may again be placed in active service.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"His Majesty's Government",
				32,
				56,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Your excellency will see therefore that His Majesty's Government are doing all in their power to increase the volume of shipping available.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"His Majesty's Government",
				40,
				64,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I hope it will be realized that the detention of neutral ships by His Majesty's Government with a view to the capture of contraband trade on its way to the enemy has not contributed nearly so much to the shortage of shipping as has the destruction of neutral vessels by submarine mines indiscriminately laid by the enemy on the high seas, many miles from the coast, in the track of merchant vessels.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"His Majesty's Government",
				66,
				90,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "Up till now twenty-five neutral vessels have been reported as destroyed by mines on the high seas; quite apart from all questions of the breach of treaties and the destruction of life, there is far more reason for protest on the score of belligerent interference with innocent neutral trade through the mines scattered by the enemy than through the British exercise of the right of seizing contraband.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"British",
				349,
				356,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "I trust that what I have said above will be sufficient to convince your excellency's Government that the complaint that the naval policy of Great Britain has interfered with the shipments of American products to long-established markets in neutral European countries is founded on a misconception.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Government",
				85,
				95,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"Great Britain",
				140,
				153,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"American",
				191,
				199,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"European",
				248,
				256,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "In justice to the peoples of both countries, I feel that this opportunity should be taken to explain the lines on which His Majesty's Government have been acting hitherto, so as to show that the line they have followed is in no way inconsistent with the general fundamental principle of international law, and to indicate the care with which they have endeavoured to meet the representations which have been made by the United States Government from time to time during the war on these questions.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"His Majesty's Government",
				120,
				144,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"United States Government",
				420,
				444,
				"GPE"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "No one in these days will dispute the general proposition that a belligerent is entitled to capture contraband goods on their way to the enemy; that right has now become consecrated by long usage and general acquiescence.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Though the right is ancient, the means of exercising it alter and develop with the changes in the methods and machinery of commerce.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "A century ago the difficulties of land transport rendered it impracticable for the belligerent to obtain supplies of sea-borne goods through a neighboring neutral country.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "Consequently the belligerent actions of his opponents neither required nor justified any interference with shipments on their way to a neutral port.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "This principle was recognized and acted on in the decisions in which Lord Stowell laid down the lines on which captures of such goods should be dealt with.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Lord Stowell",
				69,
				81,
				"PERSON"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The advent of steam power has rendered it as easy for a belligerent to supply himself through the ports of a neutral contiguous country as through his own, and has therefore rendered it impossible for his opponent to refrain from interfering with commerce intended for the enemy merely because it is on its way to a neutral port.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "No better instance of the necessity of countering new devices for despatching contraband goods to an enemy by new methods of applying the fundamental principle of the right to capture contraband can be given than the steps which the Government of the United States found it necessary to take during the American Civil War.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Government of the United States",
				233,
				264,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"American Civil War",
				303,
				321,
				"EVENT"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "It was at that time that the doctrine of continuous voyage was first applied to the capture of contraband, that is to say, it was then for the first time that a belligerent found himself obliged to capture contraband goods on their way to the enemy, even though at the time of capture they were en route for a neutral port from which they were intended subsequently to continue their journey.",
		"entities": []
	},
	{
		"content": "The policy then followed by the Government of the United States was not inconsistent with general principles already sanctioned by international law, and met with no protest from His Majesty's Government, though it was upon British cargoes and upon British ships that the losses and the inconvenience due to this new development of the application of the old rule of international law principally fell.",
		"entities": [
			[
				"Government of the United States",
				32,
				63,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"His Majesty's Government",
				179,
				203,
				"GPE"
			],
			[
				"British",
				224,
				231,
				"NORP"
			],
			[
				"British",
				249,
				256,
				"NORP"
			]
		]
	},
	{
		"content": "The criticisms which have been directed against the steps then taken by the United States came, and come, from those who saw in the methods employed in Napoleonic times for the prevention of contraband a limitation upon the right itself, and failed to see that in Napoleonic times goods on their way to a neutral port were immune from capture, not because the immediate destination conferred a privilege, but because capture under such circumstances was unnecessary.",
